<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor><!-- Enter your name--></editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19"><!-- Enter today's date --></date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01"><!-- Enter issue date --></date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <!-- Enter issue number, date, and correct number of pages -->
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, MONDAY November 6, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIA’S LAST FIGHT. REVOLUTIONISTS' SWAY. </head>
                    <head>M. WITTE AND HIS CABINET.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 6. News of continual anti-Semitic and anti- liberal
                        riots continues to arrive from all parts, from Archangel to Tiflis and from
                        Poland to Tomsk. They are generally the result of what are called patriotic
                        or conservative manifesta- tions, which are organized under the auspices of
                        the police, and formed of mobs headed by the Imperial banner or by a
                        portrait of the Tsar. There have been hundreds oi killed and wounded at
                        Rostoff-on-Don and at Krement- chug. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg, November 6. </head>
                    <p>The Tsar's manifesto restoring all the an- cient liberties of Finland has
                        been published at Helsingfors.The constitutionalists are sa- tisfied, but
                        the revolutionaries demand further concessions. The revolutionists have
                        proved their control over the masses by countermanding yester- day's
                        demonstration, announcing that they would choose their own day, and not
                        accept one of Trepoff's choosing, for the last fight. M. Witte has not made
                        the least progress in the formation of a Cabinet The Conservatives avoid him
                        ; the Liberals show themselves dis- trustful, while the reactionaries detest
                        him. A few weeks' full is expected, during which the revolutionary party
                        will perfect their organisation. A fresh manifesto assures the people that
                        the reforms will be inflexibly carried out despite the efforts of the
                        enemies of reform, but the Government must have the coopera- tion of the
                        pacific majority. {Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The day has been quiet here. In Odessa the troubles are decreasing. (Hovas)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AUSTRIA.</head>
                    <head>UNIVERSAL SUFFRAGE WANTED</head>
                    <head>Vienna, November 6.</head>
                    <p>Great manifestations in favor of universal suffrage have taken place in the
                        principal cities of the Empire. At Prague they were the occasion of grave
                        rioting. ( Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MONTENEGRO.</head>
                    <head>PARLIAMENTARY GOVERNMENT ESTABLISHED. </head>
                    <head>Cettigne, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The Prince bes established, parliamentary government in Montenegro. (Reuter)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RING ALFONSO IN BERLIN.</head>
                    <head>Berlin, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The King of Spain has arrived on e visit to the Emperor. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Berlin, November 6.</head>
                    <p>King Alfonso has arrived and was greatly cheered. (Hovas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SLAVO-ITALIAN CONFLICTS.</head>
                    <head>Vienna, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The conflicts between the Slavian and Italian students continue. (Hovas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH BUDGET.</head>
                    <head>Paris, November 6.</head>
                    <p>The Chamber of Deputies has commenced the debate on the Budget. (Hovas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>G. AQUILINA</head>
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>Quarantine in Malta.—Alexandria is no longer considered as an "infected
                        plaoe” by the authorities in Malta.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Suez Canal.—23 vessels passed throogh the Canal on the 1st and 2nd inst, the
                        amount of dues received being frs. 637,795.37.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Cairo Mixed Court.—The judges of the Cairo Mixed Court have held a general
                        meet- ing under the presidency of M. Prunieres, and approved the "reglement
                        do service” for the judicial year 1905-6.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>False Jewellery. - Some Alexandria jewel- lers have been arrested for selling
                        imitation gold ornaments falsely stamped as being real gold. Recently, also,
                        three Syrian brothers were imprisoned at Hadra for the same offence.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Native Benevolence. TLo “Mokattam” learns from Fayoum that the omdehs and
                        notables of that town held a meeting and decided to establish a benevolent
                        society, the object of which is to build a technical school. A subscription
                        on the spot realised £3,000.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>New Doctors. — Drs. Hassan Hosny Afifi, Kamel Fahmi, Mohamed Abdul Hamid,
                        Nassif Fahmy Mencarious, Mohamed Kamil Baradab, Tewfik Naguib, Abdel Hamid
                        Sami, Abdel Aziz Helmi, Riskalla Moussa, and Mohamed Sidky, have been
                        authorised to practise in Egypt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Union Fonciered’Egypte.—It is announced that definitive share warrants to
                        bearer in the Union Fonciere d'Egypte are now ready for delivery, in
                        exchange for fully-paid allotment letters, at the Anglo-Foreign Banking Com-
                        pany, Limited, 2, Bishopsgate-street Within, London, E.C.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>A. L M. &amp; D. S.—The annual general meet- ing of the members of the
                        Alexandria Literary, Musical and Dramatic Society has been fixed to take
                        place on Wednesday, 15th inst., at H.B.M.'s Consulate, at 6.30 p.m.
                        Business: 1.To pass ths acconuts for past session ; 2. To elect a oommittee
                        end office-bearers for ensuing session; 3. To prepare programme for next
                        season.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Revue Internationale D'Egypte —The November issue of the 'Revue Internatio-
                        nale d’Egypte” is as interesting as usual and contains the following
                        contributions:—L'Expe- dition d'Egypte: 1798-1801 (R.G.C.). Le Pay- sage
                        Egyptian (Louis Fieri), II Moderno Teatro Italiano (Giovanni Munduls), Les
                        Morta (J. M.), Le Bonheur (Henri Sarvee). Un Poete (Pierre Andibert).
                        Jose-Maria De Heredia (Georges Dumani), Fata Morgana (U. Fleres).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mysterious Murder —A servant of Abdel Latif Bey Faid was murdered in His
                        master’s house Cadabah village, Gharbieh, on the 2nd inst. by some unknown
                        persons. The mur- derers appear to bare first beaten him most savagely and
                        then strangled him, forcing the point of a stick which reached the brain
                        into his skull. Ths Kafr el Zayat authorities have opened an enquiry. Hassan
                        Effendi Faid, the omdeb, and some ghaffirs are suspected of the crime,
                        because, it is said, the omdeh was on bad terms with the murdered man. They
                        have been arrested, but as yet no proof has been advanced of their
                        guilt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Princess Nazli Hanem is expected to arrive here from Tunis next Wednesday
                        accompanied by her husband, in order to spend the winter season in Egypt.
                        They will, probably, proceed to Cairo on the same day by the evening
                        express.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>H. H. the Khedive will grant an andienoe to the Russian Agent and
                        Consul-General on Thursday next</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Marquis de Soragna has returned to Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>An extension of leave for one month has been granted to Harvey Pasha.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Norddentescher Lloyd S.S. Schleswig, which arrived at Alexandria last
                        night from Marseilles, had a large contingent of passen- gers. Among the
                        more prominent people on board we noticed General Djellal-el-Diu Pasha (who
                        was met on arrival by T. H. Prince Aziz and Prince Omar Toussoun, and drove
                        off in a motor car with them), Fouad Pasha, Hon. Mr. Iddings, the new
                        American Diplomatic Agent with Mrs. and Miss Iddings, Mustapha Pasha Kamel,
                        Count de Zogheb, Adly Pasha Yeghen Governor of Cairo, Baron E. de Menasce,
                        etc.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Among the passengers who arrived by the Messageries Maritimes steamer this
                        morning were Abani Pasha, Minister of War, the family of M. de la Bonliere,
                        French Diplomatic Agent, Mr. and Mrs. John Ross, etc.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The King of Greece has bestowed the Cross of the Saviour on Mohamed Shafik
                        Bey, chief engineer of the Sharkieh Moudirich.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MR. STEAD ON SITUATION.</head>
                    <head>INTERVIEW WITH THE DOWAGER EMPRESS.</head>
                    <head>REFORMS TOO LATE.</head>
                    <head>(Gazette's Special Service) London, Monday, Nov. 6.</head>
                    <p>Mr. W. T. Stead has arrived in Copenhagen from Helsingfors and has had a long
                        private interview with the Dowager Empress ot Russia, in which he said that
                        the gravity of the situa- tion in Russia cannot be overestimated. Mr. Stead
                        predicted gigantic massacres, and he believes that the reforms have oome too
                        late. Wireless telegraphy has been installed between Peterhof and Berlin.
                        The Kaiser has sent an autograph letter to the Tsar.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ACTIVE SERVICE IN CRETE.</head>
                    <p>The following order was issued yesterday by Brig.-General Bullock, C.B.
                        commanding the Army of Occupation :— The General Officer Commanding hereby
                        declares that, by reason of the recent exis- tence of active service in the
                        Island of Crete, it is, in his opinion, necessary for the Public Service
                        that the British Forces in the Island aforesaid shall continue temporarily
                        subject to the Army Act as if they were on active service, with effect from
                        31st October, 1905, and until 30th November, 1905, both dates inclusive.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW GRAND MUFTI.</head>
                    <p>The new Grand Mufti, Sheikh Bakri Moha- med Ashour El Sedfi, has entered
                        immediately on his new post. He is a well-known personality among the Moslem
                        religious notables and a follower of the Hanafi rite. He was educated at Al
                        Azhar, where he became ulema after showing considerable theological
                        proficiency, and was for a long period Mufti to the now suppressed
                        Beit-el-Mal Administration. He was later appointed to the Mehkemeh High
                        Court as Cadi and showed such legal and theological acumen that he gained
                        the good opinion of the bulk of Egyptian Moslems. He was acting as Grand
                        Cadi in the place of Sheikh Yehia, who has gone on an important errand to
                        Constantinople, when the death of Sheikh Abdul Kader El Raffei threw open to
                        him the Grand Muftiship of Egypt. One of our Cairo contemporaries states
                        that the Ministry of Jnstice is at present discussing the question whether
                        the new Grand Mufti can still perform his functions of Grand Cadi per
                        interim, or whether some one else must be appointed to replace Sheikh Yehia
                        during his absence in Turkey.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>
                    <p> MM. Fourneron Bey and Sanpaolo, who returned last Friday night from their
                        visit to the Ibrahimieh sugar factories, left Cairo by the night train
                        yesterday for a fresh tour of inspection. This time the experts will examine
                        and report on the factories at Nag Hamadi, Arment, and Mataana, a task which
                        will, it is expected, employ their energies for at least another week. The
                        third and, let us hope, the final report of the experts is expected to be
                        completed by Thursday, the 18th inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN LAND ALLOTMENT.</head>
                    <p>Letters of allotment for the shares of the Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment
                        Company have been posted. The allotment was carried through by Messrs.
                        Russell and Kerr, chartered accountants, of Cairo. Dr. Axil Th. Preyer has
                        joined the board of the Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment Co. Mr. Crewe, who was
                        till now agent for the National Bank of Egypt at the Mousky branch, Cairo,
                        has been appointed sub-manager to the Egyptian Land Allotment Co., under a
                        con contract of ten years, and with a salary of£720 per annum.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NORTH EGYPT LAND CO.</head>
                    <p>With reference to the statement of a local contemporary in its issue of last
                        Saturday, re the North Egypt Land Co., L-d, we may point out that the
                        oompany are not wholly dependent on “providential rainfalls” for raising
                        their crops on their Mariout property, as there are already a number of
                        wells which irrigate the land, and many more are to be sunk. But leaving
                        aside the decision of the Irrigation Department not to extend the Nu- barieh
                        Canal for the present, there is another scheme about to be proposed to the
                        Govern- ment which will afford ample means for irrigat ing not only the
                        fifteen thousand feddans at present owned by the company, but a good deal
                        more.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Ellerman S.S. Britannia sailed from Malta on Sunday night and is expected
                        here on Friday morning with passengers, mails and general cargo. The Moss
                        liner Menes sailed from Liverpool on Saturday afternoon last, and is due
                        here on the 18th inst. with passengers, mails, an general cargo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICAN GIRL SLAVE IN EGYPT.</head>
                    <head>HER HUSBAND'S TREACHERY.</head>
                    <p>We cull the following from a New York oontemponry :— The extraordinary case
                        of Mollie Katain who was married last July to Harry Liederer, No. 170
                        Delancey street taken by him to Egypt sold as a white slave into bondage,
                        and rescued by the efforts of the International Society for the Suppression
                        of the White Slave Trade, has just come to light through a letter sent by
                        the girl to her brothers in New York. Her courtship was a short one, and she
                        was married at her home, No. 132, Attorney street last July. Four weeks
                        later she disappeared and was not heard of until last weak, when the society
                        sent her to her brothers after they had rescued her. Her introduction to
                        Lederer, it was said, was brought about by Mrs. Nathan Weber, who lives at
                        No. 122, Suffolk street She had $300 in bank in her own name and this must
                        have been, withdrawn without her knowledge, for in her letter she asks that
                        her fare home may be paid out of this money. The letter to her brothers is
                        in her own handwriting and is as follows: “My Dear Brothers—I am unable to
                        express the sad position in which I find myself My husband has been
                        treacherous and has fooled me all along. He brought me to Alexandria and has
                        made me a prisoner of other men. I wish you to go to court and get
                        duplicates of the documents which show that I am his wife, as he has stolen
                        the original papers from me. Buy a ticket for me to return, for he has taken
                        all my money from me. Iam very sick and cannot write much more. Molfie.”
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW SUDAN AGENT.</head>
                    <p>Captain R. C. Owen has been appointed Director ot the Intelligence Department
                        and Sudan Agent at Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PHARMACY REGULATIONS.</head>
                    <p>We mentioned in our issue of the 16th ultimo two serious infringements of the
                        new pharmacy regulations which oome into ope- ration about a year ago. These
                        prove how necessary it is for the Sanitary Adminis- tration to use the
                        utmost vigilance for safe- guarding the public. In one case a Greek named
                        Pistis, when applying for permission to open a pharmacy, sent in a diploma
                        that was ascertained to have belonged to a man who had been dead since 1896!
                        In the other case three individuals sent in diplomas pur- porting to have
                        been issued by the Faculty of Medicine of Athens bat which, when subjected
                        to expert examination, were found to be forged. The officials of the
                        Department, since the new regulations came into operation, have taken in
                        hand the inspection of pharmacies but it seems they are greatly hampered by
                        the action of the Tribunals, who, when clear cases of irregularities are
                        brought to their notice, inflict such a ridioulously small punish- ment that
                        it cannot possibly act as a de- terrent. Recently, we are informed, at Man-
                        sourah, two individuals, one a Greek and the other an Italian, were summoned
                        for keeping a pharmacy open for three months without a certificated chemist.
                        The Tribunal Mixte de Contravention inflicted for this grave offence the
                        minimum fine of P.T. 5 in one case and P.T. 10 in the other!</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW KHEDIVIAL HOTEL.</head>
                    <p>The New Khedivial Hotel at Alexandria, whioh is at present being entirely
                        renovated, will be quite ready for occupation again by the coming Christmas.
                        It will, when completed, contain altogether 150 bedrooms and twenty suites
                        of special apartments fitted with bath- rooms, closets, and other
                        accommodation. The grill-room will be open on the 1st December, and
                        afternoon teas will be served in the new pavilion on the terrace. A fine
                        Tzigane band has been specially engaged for the hotel and will play three
                        times a day. A special feature of the hotel will be the residential
                        apartments for bachelors and fami- lies, who will be able to live at the
                        hotel at an inclusive and moderate cost for board and lodging.It is expected
                        that this innovation will be taken full advantage of, and owing to the poor
                        restaurants aud high rents at Alex- andria such accommodation will be a
                        great advantage to residents. Another special feature of the hotel will be
                        the cooking.The leading "chef” at the Metro- pole Hotel, Moote Carlo, has
                        been engaged, and arrived on Sunday last with an entire brigade of
                        gastronomic artists selected with the utmost care from among the leading
                        European hotels and restaurants. During the winter the Khedivial Hotel
                        management will give a ball once a fortnight, as is the custom in Cairo.
                        There is to be a grand “Reveillon” at the hotel at Christmas, which will be
                        the formal opening fete of the hotel. Every night when there is a
                        performance at the Zizinia Theatre there will be a special supper menu at a
                        fixed inclusive price, and a band will play from midnight until 2 p.m. A
                        large American bar is to be opened on December 1, which will be equal to the
                        finest bar in Egypt. The hotel is under the manage- ment of Mr. E. Fleury,
                        late manager of the Nonvel Hotel at Vichy and of the Alexandra Hotel at
                        Monte Carlo. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BANK OF ABYSSINIA.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ALL CAPITAL APPLIED FOR.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>(Gazette's Special Service).</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>London, Monday, Nor. 6.</head>
                    <p>The Berlin Bank fur Handel and Indus- trie has applied for 100,000 £5 shares
                        in the Bank of Abyssinia.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>London, November 6.</head>
                    <p>Tbe prospectus of tbe Bank of Abyssinia has been issued. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE RODAH LAND SALE.</head>
                    <p>At the recent land sale at Rodah, according to 'Le Progres,” Dr. Nimr bade
                        L.E. 2,470 per feddan for tbe Menekley estate and this was the highest bid.
                        But owing to a dispute as to the validity of the bid it is possible that
                        Maitre Carton de Wiart's offer on behalf of an English group rail hold good.
                        The ques- tion will be decided at the next meeting of the Superior Council
                        of the Wakfs.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE VALLEY CO.</head>
                    <p>The "Financial News" is officially authoris- ed to deny tbe report that the
                        Nile Valley Company is to be reconstructed.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WALKER AND MEIMARACHI.</head>
                    <p>The latest London papers contain the report of the proceedings at the meeting
                        of Walker and Meimarachi, Limited, held in London on Monday, Ootober 30.
                        This ia said to be the first English company founded in Egypt, and owing to
                        its good management we are sure that the shareholders will be pleased-to
                        hear that the capital is to be increased so that the company may be able to
                        develop its business throughout Egypt and the Sudan. The board of directors
                        will henceforth be in Cairo, with only two directors in London. The company
                        will remain an English company and the meetings will be held in London.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BIG FIRE AT ASSIOUT.</head>
                    <p>One of the wealthiest families at Assiout is the Khaehabah family, writes our
                        Assiout Correspondent. They had four large houses at Assiout. One was burnt
                        down four months ago, another two months ago, and the remain- ing two last
                        week. The fire broke out at 11 p.m. and in aboat two hours, the two houses
                        were a blazing mass. The loss is estimated at £8,000. It is a remarkable
                        coin- cidence that in all three cases the cause of this outbreak was
                        accidental. Our correspondent states that Assiout. is very badly supplied
                        with pumps. In the fire mentioned the house was burning for a whole hour
                        before the pumps arrived, and after they came it took another hour to put
                        them in working order. Thanks are due to Mr. Russell, the Interior
                        inspector, who worked hard all night, as on the previous occasions.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW ENGLISH PAPERS.</head>
                    <p>A new illustrated political weekly, styled "The Oriental Truth,” has just
                        made its appearanoe at Cairo. It is dedicated to Oriental civillisation and
                        the editor and proprietor is Captain Joge Neokan y Weldberg. There is also
                        an Arabic and a Freneh part in addition to the English. Another new English
                        publication is “Egyp- tian Cotton,” published at Alexandria. We wish our new
                        contemporaries every success.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BANCO DI ROMA</head>
                    <p>Ainsique nous l'avons deja publie, le conseil d'administration du "Banoo di
                        Roma” a decide de porter le capital de oet important eta blissement
                        financier de O a 30 millions. L’emission das cent mille actions au prix de
                        fr. 120,80, jouissance premier janvier -1905, aveo un dividende assure non
                        inferieur aux 7 francs ordinaires par action aura lieu du 6 au 9 novembre.
                        Les nouvelles actions sont donc souscrites a moins de 115 francs, car depuis
                        de nombreuses annees deja, le dividende du "Banco di Roma" eat consolide a
                        fr. 7; ce qui vent dire que ces actions presentent le rare avantage d’un
                        place- ment aussi sur que le consolide italien a plus da 6 pour cent. Les
                        noeveaux titres aeront offerts a option aux porteurs dos anciennes actions a
                        raison d’une nouvelle action contre deux anciennes. L’emission est garantie
                        an eotier par deux grands groupes feanciers. Cette augmentation du capital
                        da "Banco di Roma” s’explique par la croissante expansion de cet
                        etablissement financier non senlement en Italie maia encore a l’etranger. En
                        effet, les sieges de cette banque existant a Paris et a Alexandrie d’Egypte
                        ont donne des resultata si encourageante que de nouvelles succursales seront
                        instituees dans d'autrees pays d’Europe. Ce succes depend aurtout de la
                        prudence et de l'habilete financiere de la direction qui a su an quelques
                        annes faire d’une petite Banque una des plus puisantes organisations
                        financie- res d’ltalie.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PRINCES AND THE DAIRA SANIEH</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE MAIN CLAIM.</head>
                    <p>Mr. H.E Garle again writes to the "Times" with references to the above, as
                        follows: Sir,—May I, in view of tbe references to this matter in your issue
                        of the 23td inst., again trespass upon your space. Tbe proceedings in
                        question had nothing whatever to do with the trial of the action and the
                        merits of the question were not even gone into. The next-of-kin’s legal
                        adviser in Egypt was of opinion that, in all the circumstances, the Egyptian
                        Courts should be asked to restrain any payment of the surplus in the hands
                        of the Daira Sanieh Limited to the Egyptian Govern- ment; and this is all
                        that was done, and is all that has failed The next-of-kin's main claim is
                        against the Egyptian Government and tho Daira Sanieh of H.H. the Khedive ;
                        it has not been tried, and will not be tried for some time to come. The
                        proceedings that have taken-place are in truth, little more than the
                        equivalent to a stop order in this country, and even so, are being appealed
                        against. I earnestly trust that you will see your way to give the same
                        prominence to this letter that you did to my last, for it is even more impor
                        tant that your statement in your issue of the 23rd inst. be answered than
                        that in your issue- of the 18th Inst. I am. Sir. your obedient servant H.
                        Ernest Garle Solicitor the next-of-kin. 61, Lincoln's inn-fields, London,
                        W.C,Oot 29. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE SIR TREVOR PLOWDEN.</head>
                    <p>Sir Trevor Chichele Ohichele-Plowden, K.O.S.L,whose death was announced
                        yesterday, connects two famous names in his own person, while the marriage
                        of his daughter with the Earl of Lytton, end his own second marriage with a
                        Fitzherbert of Swynnerton, connect him with two other names of note.
                        Chichele began with the Archbishop, whose younger brother was Sheriff of
                        London, and father of the Admiral, and Master-General of Ordeuance. Plowden
                        has produced not only Sir Trevor and other Plowdens, familiar in the annals
                        of the Indian Civil Service but also Sir Trevor's elder brother, the Cadi of
                        Marylebone, the "scintillae juris” of whose, judgement east perennially
                        enliven the police reports.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Pasenger List</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Arrivals</head>
                    <p>Per S.S. Sohleewig, arrived at Alexandria yesterday frtm Marseilles end
                        Naples:-M, D. Arif Bey, M,-and Mme P. Agoapian, Miles Marie and Ketty
                        Agopian, Mile .E Dexarena M. and Mme Heinrich Bindernagel. M. Ludwig
                        Bindernagel, Milles llse and Freida Binder- nagel, Mme Ph. Back, Mme Cecilia
                        Buallachi, Mlle Olly Bolts, Mlle Beor, M. and Mme Leopold Blariaux, M. and
                        Mae D, Caedagli, Mme K. and Mlle M. E Cettier, M. and Mme Cherky Pachs, M.
                        Ahmed Checky Bey, Mlle Viseae, Dr. von Campe, Mrs. W. Cum- mings, General
                        Ahmed Djelaleddin Pasha, Miss Helen Denison, Mr. C. Duffield, M.L. Dombre,
                        M. Henry Dubois, Mme Ida Boy Edd, Fouad Pacha, Mr. and Ms. Percival Foster,
                        Mr. and Mrs. Edward R Hoyt, Ms. Rendal, Hoyt, Mr. and Mrs.Chas Humpers
                        Mr.Andre Humpers, Mrs. Hood, Mrs. W. Hammond Mr. F. Hinkley, Mr. A.
                        Hehanoff, Adly Yeghan, Pacha and Mme, Mmme Lamalun, Mme and Mlle Alfred
                        Ismalun, Gonaull General Mrs., and Miss Iddings, Mohamed Jaffer. Mme, J. G.
                        L Kooh, Mlle W. Kloes,. M. Aug, Kiene Muatafa Kamel Pasha, Col Hon. R. T.
                        Law- ley. Capt and Mme von Langadorf, Mr. Ri- chard Louth, Baron E de
                        Menace, Mrs, C. J. Milton, Mrs. Mahony, Mme. Idanka Mayer, Mlle Lina Mayer,,
                        Mrs. MacPherran, Noury Bey, Lieuteniant van Neumann, Mr. W. M. Noyes, Mr.
                        and Mrs. R. Neville, Emille Nagel, Mlle Johanne M. Naude, M. and Mme Emila
                        Paravioini, Mr. and Mrs. Parker, Miss Parker, Miss Peel, Mrs. and Miss. W.F
                        Peel M. Theodoore J. Rodocanachi, M. Mohsen Rifky, Mr. and Mrs. A. Robinson,
                        Sabit Bey, Mme Sabit, Mlle Leonnie, Gamille Sabit Bey, Mr. and Mme., M.M.
                        Scott, M. and Mme. Alfred Suares, M. J. Shute, M. Sursook, M. A. Stul- ken,
                        M. Georg. Schmidt,Mlle A. Dan. Sommer, Mile J. Sigert, M. Albert Tilohe,
                        Mlle Tilche, Cav. Uff. A. Tilche, Mme Tilche, Hon. J. C. Vessey, Mr. and
                        Mrs. Wyatt, M. and Mme. Wierdals, Mlle Wierdals, M. Wierdals, Mr. Watt, M.
                        Ed. Wantz, Comtesse de Zogheb, Mlle Jeanne de Zogheb, M. and Mme. Rhfoasd
                        Zander, Mlle Fanny Zander, Herr Oberburder- meister Becker, Frau Ghemalin
                        and Toohter, Mr. R Baezner,Dr. and Mme F. Borchardt,Mr. M. Billwiller, Mr.
                        Ghstdve Cattaui, Mlle J. Coczalmann, Mr. Cantalamesss, Mr. and Mme Drakidis,
                        Mr. J. Dobsult, Mr. Elie Francis, Baronesse Halkett, Mr. Chr. Hornatein,
                        Mlle Ismailoff, Herr Landrat Krietzler, Mr. Lepeoh- kine, Mr.Legoulles,Mr.
                        Uaseoo,Mtared*Ueti*, Said Mob. el Mokry, Said Mob. Benani, Mr. and Mae P.
                        Michel Mr.G. Madon.Mr. P. Mao chi, Aw. P. Maochi, Ms. Georges Malic, Mile
                        Momtt, Mre. Mdngerin, Mra E Matiuea, Mr. Neddi Meddin, Mr. E Nioholsde, Mr.
                        P. Philippo and family, Mr. G. Pbilippo. Mr. A. Percy, M. and Mme A. Rocha.
                        Mlle Rossi- Pran.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 7 190S.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RUSSIAN HORRORS JEWS BUTCHERED </head>
                    <head>REVOLTNG BARBARITES. FINLAND WINS.</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 4. The Amnesty is of the widest description,
                        Applying especially- to political offenders. There are no signs of Russia
                        becoming quieter. Great disturbances and bloodshed are reported daily from
                        fresh places. The latest reports show that the horrors at Odessa were not
                        exaggerated. Hooligans aided by the police slaughtered whole families of
                        Jews, with inconceivable brutality. It is impos- sible to estimate the
                        number of the killed, but there ate at present 5,500 wounded in. the
                        hospitals. 300 corpses have already been buried. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> London, November 4.</head>
                    <p>The “Times" learn from.St. Petersburg that Finland has won a manifesto of
                        freedom, embodying all the popular demands, which was submitted for the
                        Imperial signature yes- terday evening. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg,' November 4. </head>
                    <p>Warships have left Reval for Helsinugfors as a result of the continuance of
                        alarming reports. In reply to a representation from the British Government
                        regarding the safety of British subjects, especially in the south, the
                        Embassy has also informed that stringent orders have been sent to Odessa and
                        elsewhere to restore order. The other Embassies have made similar
                        representations. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>A Petersburg, November 5.</head>
                    <p>The railway strike in Russia is ending. M. Witte has informed the strikers
                        that their demands have been granted. The police at Odessa have tardily
                        taken measures to put an end to the slaughter of the Jews. Bloodshed
                        continues elsewhere. A hundred were killed and six hundred wounded at Minsk.
                        The resignation of the' Minister of the Interior, M. Bouliguine, has been
                        accepted. A manifesto of the Tsar convokes the Finnish diet for the 28th
                        December, in view of the revision of electoral representation. It abolishes
                        the Dictatorship. Meanwhile four warships, convoying ten thousand troops,
                        have anchored at Helsiugfurs. , A great Socialist demonstration which had
                        been, arranged for to-day has been abandoned owing to the stem threat of
                        General Trepoff to repress disturbances rigorously. An official
                        communication declares that it is indispensable that all classes should
                        refrain from mutual friction in order to avoid'disturb- ances, which the
                        Government must repress for the protection of Russian citizens without
                        distinction. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Odessa, November 5.</head>
                    <p>Eight factories have been wrecked in the vicinity. The massacres were
                        accompanied by the most revolting barbarities ; eyes were gouged out,
                        tongues were torn ont with pincers, and n valids were burned alive. (Reuter)
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg, November 4.</head>
                    <p>Quiet prevailed to-day throughout Russia. The Tsar will grant the demands of
                        Finland. (Hovas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>St. Petersburg, November 5.</head>
                    <p>The Minister Bouliguine has resigned. (H.) Odessa, November 5. A riot has
                        broken out. 300 people have been killed and 3,000 injured. (Havas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Tomsk, November 5.</head>
                    <p>The revolutionaries have set fire to a build- ing in which the reactionaries
                        had taken refuge, massacring those who attempted to escape. (Hovas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>WEI-HEI-WEI NOT TO BE ABANDONED. London, November 5.</head>
                    <p>The "Observer" states that Great Britain does not intend to abandon
                        Wei-hei-wei. (It) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE ROYAL TOUR Aden, November 4.</head>
                    <p>The Renows left this afternoon. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SIR TREVOR PLOWDEN DEAD. London, November 5.</head>
                    <p>Sir Trevor Plowden is dead. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CELEBRATING INSPRUCK. Vienna, November 4.</head>
                    <p>Brawls took place between German and Italian students on tbe occasion of the
                        anni- versary of the Inspruck incidents. (Havas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>M'DEROULEDE IN PARIS. Paris, Novrmber 5. </head>
                    <p>M. Deroulede has arrived. He was oheered (Hovas)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>POWERS AND CRETE. INSURGENTS ACCEPT TEEMS. Canea, November 4.</head>
                    <p>The Cretan insurgents have agreed to accept tbe terms offered them by the
                        Powers, provided that the surrender of their arms be arranged in a manner
                        that will spare their susceptibilities. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRINCE LOUIS OF BATTENBERG. RECEPTION AT WASHINGTON. Washington, November
                        4.</head>
                    <p>Prince Louis of Batteuberg and tbe officers of tbe British aquadrou are
                        visiting this city for three days. They have been received by President
                        Roosevelt at White House with great ceremony and cordiality. Prince Louis of
                        Battenberg presented a personal message from the King. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>Washington, November 5.</head>
                    <p>Prince Louis of Battenberg has been enter- tained at a banquet by President
                        Roosevelt. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>

                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMANY AND AMERICA. TREATY OF COMMERCE. Washington, Novomber 5.</head>
                    <p>Negotiations for a Germano-American treaty of commerce have been opened.
                        {Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> GERMANY AND ABYSSINIA. APPOINTMENT OF MINISTER Berlin, November 5.</head>
                    <p>It is stated here that Germany intends to appoint a Minister in Abyssinia.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>Um Rus Gold Mines of Egypt.— This com- pany has sold tbo September gold for
                        £1,552. (Mill ran 19 days.)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Execution. — Beyioumi Bedawi, who was sentenced to death for murder, was
                        executed this morning in Tantah prison. Military Camp. — The 2nd Company of
                        Royal Engineers will move into camp on the Polygon. Abbassieh, on the 13tn
                        inst., for field works and musketry.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Theft in a Gouvernorat.— A sum of about L.E. 20 has been stolen from a safe
                        in tbe private enquiry department at the Cairo Gouvernorat. The safe
                        contained L.E. 66.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The “Egyptian Graphic."—We hear that our contemporary the "Egyptian Graphic"
                        will soon reappear for the season of 1905-06 under the editorship of Mr.
                        William Houghton.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>New Judges.—Tbe Egyptian Government is negotiating with the French and Greek
                        Governments for the appointment of two Mixed Court judges in place of Judges
                        Ruhland aud Boaphidis.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p> Egyptian Land &amp; General Trust.—Mr. John Chini, of the firm of Messrs. P.
                        Glyme- nopoulos &amp; Co., has been appointed the agent of the Egyptian Land
                        &amp; General Trust, Limit- ed, in Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Seven at a Birth.—A native contemporary states that a poor woman of Damanhour
                        has given birth to seven children, four males and three lerooles. The mother
                        is doing well, but two of tbe boys and two of the girls died shortly after
                        birth.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Thefts at Alexandria —A local contem- porary persists in denying the
                        existence of a band of robbers at Alexandria, who have recently committed a
                        number of thefts. The statement can be proved by repairing to tbe scene of
                        their operations in Sisters-street and at the establishment of the Sisters
                        of St. Vincent de Paul.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Woman Strangled.—A native woman, 35 years of age, of the name of Aysha and
                        belong- ing to Jerza village, has been found dead in the Saida Zeynab
                        quarter of Cairo with a handkerchief bound tightly round her neck. The
                        medical examina ion shows that the poor woman was strangled, and that the
                        crime occurred only a few hours before its discovery.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Y.W.C.A., Cairo.—By kind permission of H.R.H. the Duchess of Connanght, in
                        remem- brance of her visit to the home last spring, the name “Connaught
                        House" will now be incorporated with that of Young Women’s Christian
                        Association. We are asked to state this to correct tbe impression that tbe
                        name of tbe institution has been changed. Miss Maclnnes, tbe acting
                        president, returned to Cairo last month.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MINISTRY OF FINANCE. A SECOND UNDER SECRETARY OF STATE.</head>
                    <p>Owing to tho greatly increased pressure of work at the Ministry of Finanoe,
                        it has been decided to appoint anothor Under-Secretary of State, and Lord
                        Edward Cecil Pasha has been selected to fill the new post. Great sa-
                        tisfaction is expressed both in British and native circles at his
                        appointment. During his career in the Sudan servioe Lord Edward Cecil has
                        displayed in a marked degreo the qualities of a good administrator. He is
                        thirty-eight, a brilliant soldier, and a man of business as well as of
                        affairs. The be- sieged in Mafeking owe him a large debt. They hod pretty
                        bad times there long before the siege was over, but had it not been for Lord
                        Edward Cecil they would have starved long before relief came. He took upon
                        himself the responsibility of providing the town with just four times the
                        quantity of food the military authorities found necessary, and when the
                        contractors hesitated to exeoote a seven thousand pound order on the young
                        major’s sole responsibility, Lord Edward promptly got Baden-Powell to back
                        the bilL. But Muafeking was only one incident in his career. He has served
                        in Egypt several times, accompanied the famous special mission to King
                        Menelik ot Abyssinis, gained two medals for his services with the Dougoia
                        Expedition, earned more fame at Atbara, and added to it at Omdurman the D.
                        S. O. and two clasps. The mission to Menelik, by the way, nearly put an end
                        to Lord Edward’s career. While the party was on its way uue of the camels
                        fell down a deep ravine, aud Lord Edward and Captain Swayne clambered down a
                        rope of puggarees with the idea of rescuing the animal. They could not roach
                        the camel, however, and one of the Abyssinians went down. A moment later two
                        shots rang out—one ot them came pretty near to hitting Sir Rennell Rodd—-and
                        the native caino up hand over hand in doable- quick time. He had found two
                        lions devour- ing tbe camel! Lord Edward, who is, of course, a younger
                        brother of tbe Marquess of Salis- bury, married in 1894 Miss Violet Maxse,
                        daughter of tbe late Admiral Maxse, and sister to the editor of the
                        “National Review." As a girl, Lady Edward Cecil sat for Millais' "Puss in
                        Boots,” and during the Boer war she did splendid work among the sick and
                        wounded. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>The Khedive will grant an audience to the newly-appointed Russian
                        Consul-General in Cairo next Thursday afternoon, when the Con- sul will
                        submit his credentials to his Highness.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>GERMAN CONSULATE.</head>
                    <p>Baron von Humboldt-Dachroeden, German Consulat Alexandria, has been appointed
                        Consul- General at Capetown. He is expected at Alex- andria next week, on
                        his return from leave, and will take up his new post in the beginning of
                        December.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>MUNICIPAL ELECTIONS.</head>
                    <p>A preliminary meeting was held yesterday at the Alexandria Gonvernorat to
                        consider the new electoral list for tbe forthcoming munici- pal elections,
                        which will be held in March next </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AGRICULTURAL BANK OF EGYPT.</head>
                    <p>The Committee of the London Stock Ex- change has fixed Wednesday, Nov. 15, as
                        a special settling day in Agricultural Bank of Egypt—Scrip certificates to
                        bearer, fully paid, for a further issue of 248,000 Ordinary shares of £5
                        each. (Nos. 375,001 to 623,000), and has ordered the same security to be
                        quoted in the offioial list. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMERICAN INSURANCE SCANDALS.</head>
                    <p>Our recent article on the American insurance scandals has been interpreted by
                        some persons here, whose knowledge of English is limited, as reflecting on
                        the agents in Egypt of the companies concerned. But the idea that the
                        article had any reference to anyone in Egypt is of coarse quite absurd, and
                        it will not bear that interpretation for a moment to anyone conversant with
                        the English language.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                    <p>The Messageries S.S. Dumbea, from Mar- seilles, passed the Straits of Messina
                        on Satur- day and is due at Alexandria to-morrow. The Moss liner Seti
                        arrived on Saturday morning from Liverpool, via Gibraltar and Malta, with
                        passengers, mails, and general cargo. The Ellerman S.S. Andalusian sailed
                        fran Malta ou Saturday afternoon and is due here on Tuesday night with
                        general cargo. The S.S City of Dundee (Westcott and Laurence Line) left
                        Malta on Saturday night and is due here on Wednesday, with general cargo
                        from London and coal from Newcastle.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE LATE GRAND MDFTI. SUCCESSOR APPOINTED.</head>
                    <p>The funeral of the late Grand Mufti, Sheikh Mohamed Abd El Kader El Rafei,
                        took place early on Saturday afternoon. The Prime Min- ister, Mustapha Pasha
                        Fehmy, Fakhry Pasha, Fuad Pasha, tbe chiefs of the ulema, and the principal
                        dignitaries of the University of Al Azhar, Mr. Moberly, acting Commandant of
                        the Cairo Police, and a great number of notables and sheikhs were present.
                        The fu- neral service was bald at the Mosque of the Al Azhar University,
                        after which the foneral cortege moved on to the cemetery at El Me- gaonerin,
                        where the interment took place. The late Grand Mufti appears to have suc-
                        cumbed to heart failure while driving from the house of H. E. Boutros Pasha
                        Ghali to that of H.E. Ahmed Pasha Mazloum to con- clude a series ot official
                        visits which seem to have proved too fatiguing for his years. His friends
                        state that he showed no signs of illness when leaving his house in the late
                        afternoon. A successor to the Grand Mufti has already been found in Sheikh
                        Bakri Ashour, the acting Grand Cadi, who has aocepted the appointment.
                        Sheikh Bakri is reputed to be a learned theo- logian and bears a high
                        personal character.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FLOATING DOCK TO PASS THROUGH CANAL.</head>
                    <p>The Navy Department at Washington is negotiating for the passage through the
                        Suez Canal of three colliers and also a large steel floating drydock which
                        will be towed to tbe station of Olongapo, in the Philippines. No anxiety is
                        expressed over the voyage, which will be notable in many respects. The dock
                        will be the largest structure ever to pass through the Suez CanaL It is
                        estimated that the cost of taking the dock to Olongapo will be £250,000.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>The Hon. Mr. Iddings, American Diplomatic Agent and Consul-General at Cairo,
                        arrives at Alexandria this afternoon by the North German Lloyd S.S.
                        Schleswig.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Archbishop Briante and the Marquis Soragna were among the passengers who
                        arrived yesterday by the Italian mail steamer.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The new Under Seoietary of State for War is H. E. Ismail Sirhauk Pasha.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Sir Thomas Sutherland, Vice President of the Suez Canal Co., is giving a
                        dinner to his brother members of ths British section of the board of
                        directors, at the Elysee Palace Hotel London, on the 15th inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Lews Mansfield Pasha, Commandant of the Cairo City Police, arrived to-day by
                        the Austrian Lloyd steamer.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Admiral Sir Massie Blomfield, K.C.M.G. has arrived at Cairo.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Chitty Bey has arrived at Cairo from Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Kaimakam Macaulay Bey left Cairo for Khartoum on Saturday night by the
                        sleeping car train to Loxor.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>We understand that Mrs. Sydney Farrar is rather indisposed, and is coming to
                        Egypt shortly. It is hoped that the mild climate of the Nile Valley will
                        greatly benefit her health.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. R. J. Moss and Miss Moss arrived here to-day by the Austrian
                        Lloyd S.S. Cleopatra.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr. Reeves is expected at the Carlton early next week.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Lieut. R. J. Cooke, Inspector of Army Schools, leaves Port Said for Malta on
                        the 9th inst. by the S.S. City of Corinth, on the conclusion of his
                        inspection in Egypt.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Naguib Bay Chikour, chief signalling en- gineer of the Egyptian Railway
                        Administra- tion, has retired with an indemnity of L.E 1,060.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Among the visitors now staying at the Carlton Hotel, Bulkeley, are Mr. J.C.
                        Clarke Mr. B. Nathan, Mr. Ch. Christian, Mr. F Nathan, England, Miss Mary B.
                        Moffat,U.S.A. Miss F. Clarke, U.S.A., Mr. C.H. Bernhard France, Mr. B.
                        Gorra, Syria, Dr. S. Schmeil Cairo, Mr. A. Mosseri and family, Cairo Mrs.
                        Bogdadli and family, Cairo, and Mr. E. L Edgar, England.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Among the latest arrivals at tbe Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr.
                        C. R. Muratori. Mr. A. Macaulay, Mr. A. Benzinra Capt Moberly, Mr. P.
                        Cowlas, Mrs. E Macau lay, Mr. and Mrs. M. Summers, Mrs. H Mayne, Dr. E. H.
                        Ross, Mr. Batler. Mrs. C.E Malby, Mr. A. Nathan, Mr. P. Beohara, Mr. and
                        Mrs. A. Brown, Mr. James F. Waterlow M.C B.A., Mr. G. Geoman, Capt. Byarke,
                        Mr. RH. Parker, Mr. R. W. Wright Henderson Dr. and Mrs W.A. Hayes, Mr. and
                        Mrs. MoKay.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CHRYSANTHEMUM. SHOWS. SUCCESSFUL EXHIBITS AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                    <p>The eighth of the Alexandria Horticultural Society’s Chrysanthemum Shows was
                        held in the San Stefano Casino on Saturday and Sunday last. It was the
                        largest yet held here, and was remarkable for the number of novel exhibits
                        it contained, this, evidently, being the result of according a oertain
                        number of points in tho programme for new varieties not hitherto exhibited
                        in Egypt. Every year brings one or two new exhibitors who show extra-
                        ordinarily good blossoms. Mr. Rolo surprised the public last year by his
                        beautiful cut flowers a in boxes, and this year Madame Salvago and Yehia
                        Bey, who never exhibited before, were able to carry off prizes in every
                        class for which , they (competed. The group of Mme Salvago, though small,
                        was quite charming, and the fine heads of flowers that Yehia Bey produced
                        were as good as any that have been seen at San Stefano. But to those who
                        really under- stand chrysanthemums and their culture, the great feature of
                        the show was undoubtedly the mass of pot plants in the centre of Mr.
                        Zervndachi’s gronp, which had been so culti- vated that while the plant
                        remained small, the bloom was as large as if the roots had not been touohed.
                        The ball-room of the Casino was completely filled by four large groups,
                        three of which were for competition, while the fourth was the exhibit of the
                        Municipality, which never com- petes. All showed great taste in arrangement,
                        and the harmony in colour in each was well thought out. The difficulty
                        consequently lay in judging the strength of the plant and in the value of
                        the new importations into Egypt Perhaps among all the exhibitors the
                        greatest stride has been made by the Municipality; the difference in the
                        grouping of their plants was greatly noticeable. The Municipality is now
                        taking great interest in the culture of flowers. The reading-room was also
                        quite full of plants; the blossoms were enormous and although most of the
                        prizes seemed to go to three or four (competitors, yet in every class there
                        was much competition. Cultivation of the chrysanthemum has become so general
                        in Alexandria, that it almost seems as if the committee might venture to
                        take a further step, and offer prizes for special classes suoh as Pompou,
                        Incurves, etc. We must not omit to mention the boxes of well-grown flowers
                        staged by General Bullock, nor the interesting exhibit of Mrs. Crafton,
                        consisting of the leaf, flower, and fruit of the Philodendron pertusum. It
                        is not generally known that the fruit, which tastes like pineapple, takes 18
                        months to ripen. There was a mass of vases arranged by natives, most of them
                        well thought oat, though perhaps the harmony of colour which generally
                        pleases the Earopean eye, was somewhat wanting. Asa trial the oommittee
                        offered prizes for collections of vegetables, salad, and fruit, without
                        speoifiying too varieties. These exhibits were a success, and showed the
                        pnblic several vegetables which they probably had no idea were at the
                        present time to be obtained in the market. We noticed, for instance, peas,
                        figs, and strawberry grapes. The attendance on the opening day showed a
                        marked increase on former years, while on Sunday the attraction of the
                        Armenian bend helped to swell the large number who were drawn to the show.
                        The following are the names of the judges :— Miss Borchgrevink, Mrs.
                        Crafton, Messrs. Ebell, Monfront, H Seffer, and Tramontins.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PRIZE LIST. CHRYSANTHEMUMS.</head>
                    <p>Pot Plants. 1. Gronp of at least 200 plants.—Silver gilt medal, Mr. E. C.
                        Zervudachi; silver medal, Prince Omar Toussoun ; bronze medal, Mme Charlotte
                        Debbane. 2. Group of from 75 to 100 plants.—1. Mme - Salvago ; 2. Judge
                        S-ndars. 3. 18 plants, cultivated for large flowers ; 6 varieties at
                        least—1. Yehia Bey ; 2. Mr. Jacques Rolo. 4. 6 plants, cultivated for large
                        flowers.— No entry. 5. 6 plants, each at least 15 flowers.—1. Mr. E. C.
                        Zervudachi; 2. Yehia Bey. 6. 7, and 8.—No entry. Cut Flowers. 9. 24 Blooms,
                        12 varieties at least.—Silver medal, Prince Omar Toussoan ; bronze medal,
                        Mr. E. C. Zervudachi. 10. 12 Blooms, Mixed.—1. Yehia Bay; 2. Prince Omar
                        Toussoun. 11. 12 Blooms, one colour.—1. Prinoe Tous- soun ; 2. Mme Salvago.
                        12. 6 Blooms, mixed.—1. Yehia Bey; 2. Prinoe Omar Toussoun. 13. 6 Blooms,
                        one colour.—1. Prince Omar Toussoun ; 2. Yehia Bey. 14, 15, and 16.—No
                        entry. Floral Decorations, 17, 18, and 19.—No entry. 20. 1. Abdou Hassan ;
                        equal 2. Ibrahim Amer aod Shaban Ahmed. VEGETABLES AND FRUIT. 21. 1. Ahmed
                        Mohamed ; 2. Ali Said ; 3. Haffez Soliman. 22. 1. Daddour Mohamed ; 2. Ahmed
                        Mo- hamed. 23. Salad.—1. Ali Said; 2. Daddour Moha- med Best chrysanthemum
                        in the show. —Prince Omar Toussoun.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE CAIRO EXHIBITION. HIGH STANDARD Of EXHIBITS.</head>
                    <p>Saturday and Sunday's Chrysanthemum Show at Cairo was a thorough saocess from
                        the point of view of the judges, and the weather was delight- fully cool and
                        pleasant, with the result that the attendance was satisfactory and ths
                        visitors to the K. A.S building were content. The exhibits in nearly all
                        cases reached a very high standard, some of the groups being remarkably
                        beautiful, and the cut flowers attracting great attention. Mrs. Foaden, who
                        was by far tbe most successful exhibitor, secured no less than eleven first
                        prizes, her groups consisting of splendidly healthy blooms, and her other
                        exhibits being extremely tastefully arranged. Lord Cromer visited the Show
                        early on Satnrday afternoon, as did the Prime Minister and Husseith Fakhry
                        Pasha and many other well-known Cairo personalities, and there was a very
                        fair attendance on the second afternoon of the show. We need not say that
                        the arrangements were excellent, and that the excellent tea that was
                        provided and the music, for which we have to thank the C. O. of the 2nd
                        Royal Inniskilling Fosiliers, were heartily appreciated. The following were
                        the prize-winners in the various clasaes of exhibits:-</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>AMATEURS.</head>
                    <p>Flowers Cultivated in Pots. 1. Group of at least 25 pots of Cbrysanthe-
                        mums.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 1. Ahmed Bey Kho- loussi. 2. Group of at least 12
                        pots of Chrysanthe- mums and not exceeding 22 pots—1. Mrs. Foaden; 2. Ahmed
                        Bey Kholoussi. 3. Group of at leaat 6 pots of Chrysanthe- mums and qot
                        exceeding 12 pots.—1. Mrs. Foadon ; 2. Miss F. Curtis. 4. Group of at least
                        3 pots of Chrysanthe- mums grown for decorative purposes rather than for
                        large flowers. — 1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2 Ahmed Bey Kholoussi. 5. One specimen or
                        standard Chrysanthemum plant.—No exhibit 6. The best collection of at least
                        10 pots in flower other than Chrysanthemums.—2. Ahmed Bey Kholoussi. Cut
                        Flowers. 7. Collection of 48 blooms of Chrysanthe- mums.—1. Mrs. Foaden ;
                        equal 2. Mrs. Mac- kenzie and Capt. Owen. 8. Collection of 24 blooms of
                        Chrysanthe- mum.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Mrs. Mackenzie. 9. Collection of 12
                        blooms of Chrysanthe- mum.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 9. Mrs. Mackenzie. 10 6 blooms
                        of Chrysanthemum.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Mrs. Mackenzie. 11. Zinnias (one
                        box).—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2, Mackenzie. 12. Cannas (one box).—No award. 13.
                        Dahlias (one box).-1. M. Giliberti; 2. Ahmed Bey Kholoussi. 14. Collection
                        of Flowers not previously specified ; 2 boxes at least—1. M. Giliberti. 15.
                        Collection of Flowers not previously specified ; 1 box at leaat—1. M.
                        Giliberti. BASKETS AND VASES OF FLOWERS. 16. Basket of Chrysanthemums.—1.
                        Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Mrs. Butcher and Miss Crewe. 17. Vase of Chrysanthemums ;1.
                        Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Miss F. Curtis. 18. Basket of Flowers (other than Chrysan-
                        themums).—No exhibits. 19. Vase of Flowers (other than Chrysaathe- mums).—1.
                        Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Miss F. Curtis, - NURSERYMEN. 20. Group of pot
                        Chrysanthemums.—1. Moh. Said el Kebir; 2. Said Mohamad. 21. Best collection
                        of cut blooms of Chry- santhemums. 1. - Moh. Said el Bakri; 2. Said Mohamed.
                        Extra prizes for a basket of chrysanthemums and for buttonholes awarded to
                        Ahmed Mus- tapha. 22. Exhibits from Government Garden, Royal Horticultural
                        Society's S.G.M. and an Objet d'Art. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCRBRIES COMPANY. MEETING OP DEBENTURE HOLDERS.</head>
                    <p>A meeting of tbe debenture-holders of the Egyptian Sugar Refineries was held
                        recently in Paris, at which, on tbe initiative of the French Council of
                        Foreign Bondholders, a committee was formod (the Paris correspondent of the
                        "Financial News" states) with the fullest powers to safeguard their
                        interests before the Cairo Tribunal of Commerce. The creditors of the
                        unfortunate concern have again been con- vened for November 17, after having
                        met on October 18 last, to receive the report of the experts.This
                        dcoament,the correspondent says, particularly incriminates the board of di-
                        rectors which up till last year distributed dividends, whilst the company’s
                        business never resulted in a single centime profit. On the contrary, for the
                        last five years the Egyptian Sugar Refineries constantly worked at a loss,
                        which did not appear in the obviously "doctored” balance-sheets. As to tbe
                        notorious Cronier bills which the managing directors aocepted, unknown to
                        their colleagues of the board, the experts declare they were duly entered in
                        the oompany's books; but the items reffering to that account were
                        subsequently omitted from the balance- sheets. Moreover, the bills once paid
                        by the company could not be found until they were discovered at the private
                        residence of a subor- dinate employe, who had staetd that he bad never seen
                        them. The debenture-holders will now await the meeting of November 17,when
                        the experts will read a supplementary report, whioh will also set forth the
                        exact state of the assets and liabilities of the company.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                 <div type="item">
                    <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 8,1905</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JEW EXTERMINATION.</head>
                    <head>MORE TERRIBLE SCENES IN RUSSIA</head>
                    <head>THE NEW CABINET</head>
                    <head>QUIET IN ST. PETERSBURG</head>
                    <p>St. Petersburg, November 7 The strikes in Finland are ended. The total killed
                        during the recent riots in Odessa number 964. Tho number of the excesses
                        committed in the provinces is diminishing, which indicates that the tardy
                        orders of the Government for the suppression, of disorders are being carried
                        out. The St. Petersburg. Gazette annonnces that M. Witte has been appointed
                        President of the Coancil. of Ministers, which had been reorganised. It is
                        stated that M. Shipoff, chief of the Moscow Congress of Zsmstvos, has
                        accepted the post of Controller General of the Empire and Minister of the
                        interior. It is also stated that occupants have been found for the
                        portfolios of finance and Communications. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>St.Petersburg, November 7. (Official). M. Witte has been • appointed
                        President of the Council. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>London, November 7 The Chief Rabbir has received a. telegram from a leading
                        Russian Jew stating that many Jewish communities have been entirely de-
                        stroyed, and asking for help. Tho Rothechilds and others are concerning
                        measnres. A meeting of the leading Jews was held at Rothechilds this
                        afternoon. It was decided to appeal for funds lor the relief of the victims
                        in Russia. (Reuter) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>St. Petersburg November 7. M.Witte, has prepared a new electoral franchise
                        for the National Assembly, increas- ing its members to 600, inclnding 25
                        workmen, greatly reducing tho property qoa’ifiations, and widening the
                        suffarage generally. Numbers of shops and banks are being re- opened, and
                        ordinary life is being resumed here and at Moscow, Helsingfors, and else-
                        where. There are, however, still terrible scenes being enacted in the
                        neighbouring villages and at Odessa, where all the houses of Jews have been
                        destroyed. The killed number many hundreds, and thousands are wounded and
                        starving. (Reuter),</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>ABYSSINIAN BANK.</head>
                    <head>SUBSCRIPTION LIST CLOSED. .</head>
                    <p> London, November 7. Subscriptions to the Abyssinian Bank open- ed to-day,
                        and closed at noon, over subscribed. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>UNITED KINGDOM’S TRADE RETURNS.</head>
                    <p>London, November 7. The imports for the ten months ending Ootober show an
                        increase of £11,000,000, the exports an increase of £50,000,000.
                        (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>DEATH OF LADY FLORENCE DIXIE</head>
                    <p>London. November 7. Lady Florence Dixie is dead. (Reuter) Lady Florence Dixie
                        was a daughter of the seventh Marquis of Queensberry and was born in 1857.
                        She was married in 1875 to Sir Bean mint Dixie. §he acted as war
                        correspondent for the “Morning Post" during tbe Boer War.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>KAISER AND KING ALFONSO.</head>
                    <p>Berlin, November17. Cordial toasts were exchanged between the Emporor and
                        King Alfonso. (Hovas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FRENCH PARLIAMENT.</head>
                    <p> Paris, November 7.- The new elections to the Senate have been fixed for
                        January 7. The Chamber has passed a vote of confi- dence in M.
                        Rouvier,refusing State employes the right to strike. (Hovas) </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE.NEW ZEALANDERS’ SCORE.</head>
                    <head>OXFORD BEATEN.</head>
                    <p>London,November 7.. Football. The New ZsaUnders' beat Oxford by 47 to 0. The
                        total more until now is 540 against 15. (Reuter)</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>JOSEPH COMAS. TECHNICAL ENGINEER</head>
                    <p>Surveyor and Constructor in shipping. Take charge of Engines and Boilers.
                        Undertakes repairs of same, guaranteeing success. First tvalues references.
                        Address: Rue fl Warsha Maison Gabriel, ALEXANDRIA. 26685-J2A1</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    <p>The Frindisi Mail will arrive at Alex- andria at 3 pm. to-day and will be
                        distributed at tbe G.P.O. at 5 p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Quarantine in Italy.—Quarantine restric- tions against arrivals from
                        AUxandria in Ita- lian ports have been removed.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Abdeen district of Cairo daring the
                        night of Thursday will be poisoned by the police.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Greek Immigration. — A large number of Greek immigrants from the Turkish
                        islands in tbe Arcbipelago have arrived at Alexandria within the past few
                        weeks.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Veterinary College—Nine pupils have been admitted this year to the college,
                        which now numbers 31 students. Tbe curriculum will henceforth require four
                        instead of three years’ study.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The Egyptian Institute held its opening meeting of the season yesterday.
                        Professor Maspero delivered a eulogy of tbe late M. Oppert, and M. Legrain
                        read a detailed aoconnt of the latest excavations at Lexor.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Alhamrba Theatre. — The Crepy Simons French operetta company will commence a
                        series of 60 performances at this theatre on December 1 next. The company’s
                        repertoire includes all the latest creations.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Fatality —A native workman, remedies a bouk Hassan, while digging yesterday
                        in a pit at Roud Point, Alexandria, was buried under a heavy mass of earth
                        which fell upon him. The unfortunate man succumbed.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>London Stock Exchange— Application has, been made to the comittees of ths
                        London Stock Exchange to grant a settling day for - Eridea (Egypt) Exploring
                        Company, Limited. —10/07 shares of £1 each fully paid (Noe. 1 to 8 and
                        65,008 to 75,007).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Zizinia Theatre—Mr. A. Lamtert, fils, the celebrated French actor, opens at
                        tbe Zizinia Theatre this evening in Emilo Angier 4-act comedy,
                        L'Aventuriere. M. Lambert, it will be remembered, represented the French
                        stage at tbe funeral of tbe late Sir Henry Irving.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Kask el Nil.—Owing to the increase in the river traffic it has beea decided
                        to alter the hours at Kasr el Nil Bridge for traffic. From Friday next, 10th
                        inst., the bridge will be open to admit the passage of river traffic from
                        1:15 to 3 p.m., instead of from 1:30 to 3 p.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>King’s Birthday.—To-morrow (Thursday) will be observed as a holiday in the
                        Army, in honor of the anniversary of the birthday of H.M. the King, and all
                        offices and schools wil be closed. Tbe headquarters offices will be opened
                        for business of an urgent nature from 7.15 a.m. to 8.15 a.m.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>New Khedivial Hotel - Among the im provements which are being made in tbe New
                        Khedivial Hotel, we omitted to mention in yesterday’s article on the
                        subject,that a feature of tbe hotel which will be much appreciated will be
                        tbe private dining-rooms. This will meet a much-felt want in Alexandria.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>British Chamber or Commerce. — The November issue of the Journal of tbe
                        British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt has appeared The contents include:
                        Points for Manufactu- rers, Egypt's trade in Explosives, Acceleration of,
                        weekly Brindisi Mail for Alexandria.Customs Returns, Imports during
                        September, Manches- ter Goods, etc.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Walker A Meimarchi — In reference to the paragraph on Messrs. Walker &amp;
                        Meimarachi, Limited, which we published yes terday, we are authorised to
                        state that this company has decided to remain in its present business
                        premises at Alexandria and Cairo. So there is no need for brokers and house
                        agents to apply to the firm with offers of new offices eligible sites, etc.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>New British Club.—A sufficient number of replies having been receivad to
                        warrant the formation of the new British Club at Alexan- dria, a general
                        meeting of those who have signified their intention of joining will be held
                        at tbe Eastern Telegraph Company’s head quarters on Weinesdiy, 15th inst.,
                        at 9:15 p.m. Business: Election of Permanent Com mitee; Selection of
                        suitable premises (plan will be submitted).</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>FOOTBALL.</head>
                    <p>There will be a football match tomorrow at Mostapba between the E.T.C and
                        ”D." Compy. Royal Dublin Fusiliers. Kick off at 3:30.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NO CATTLE PLAGUE.</head>
                    <head>DISAPPEARANCE OF DISEASE</head>
                    <p>The reports sent in by the inspectors of the Sanitary Department regarding
                        tbe cattle plague in tbe provinces are unanimous in declaring that the
                        malady has completely disappeared.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>OPENING OF CATTLE MARKETS.</head>
                    <p>No cases of cattle plague having been report- ed since August 14, it has been
                        decided, should no further case occur, to open the cattle mar- kets on the
                        22nd inst.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE NEW GRAND MUFTL</head>
                    <p>We hear that it has been decided that Sheikh Bakri el Sedfi, the new Grand
                        Mufti of Egypt, may continue to act as Grand Cadi till the return of Sheikh
                        Yehia from Turkey. The Grand Mufti has officially called upon the Ministers
                        since his appointment</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE GRAND CADI.</head>
                    <p>The Grand Cadi of Egypt has wired to his household in Cairo, informing them
                        that he has arrived at Constantinople in safety. It is said, declares “Al
                        Moayad,” that the Grand Cadi promised his family before his departure that,
                        if no troubles were in store for him in the Capital,he would let them have
                        each a telegram. Although the Saltan's summons to tbe Cadi is still a
                        mystery,continues “A1 Moayad,” the romoor to the effect that he had been
                        called to Stamboul in order to go into tbe question of tbe Caliphate, in
                        other words, the question of the succession to the Ottoman Throne is quite
                        baseless. The Cadi of Egypt has nothing to do with such a question so long
                        as the Sheikh-ul-Islam and the other Ulema of high standing reside in
                        Constantinople. If the Sultan wishes tbe succession to pass to tbe sons
                        instead of to tbe eldest Prince he matteresn be settled at once by a single
                        1 sign from his Majesty.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>SIR WILLIAM GARSTIN.</head>
                    <p>We understand that Sir William Garstin, aocording to the latest accounts
                        received by his friends, is making most satisfactory pro- gress and will
                        almost certainly be in Egypt before tbe new year.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>VITALITY STATISTICS.</head>
                    <p>From the latest returns of tbe Statistical Department in Cairo we find that
                        the total number of births in that city during the week ending 28th Ootober
                        was 563, including 7 of foreign parentage; this being equal to a rate of 47
                        per thousand of the estimated population. For the week ended last Saturday
                        the births were 527, of which 9 were of foreign parentage, the rate being
                        44.3 per mile. The deaths for the first week under review numbered 411,
                        inoluding 24 of foreign nationality; this is equivalent to a rate of 32.7
                        per thousand for the native and 35.4 for the European portion of the inha-
                        bitants. For the week ending the 4th instant the deaths were 402, which
                        included 16 foreig- ners, and the ratios 33.0 and 23.0 per mile for the
                        native and foreign portions respec- tively. At Alexandria the births for the
                        first week were 295, which was inclusive of 15 children of foreign
                        parentage, the rate per thousand being 46.0. Last week there was registered
                        329 births, of which 17 were of the latter category. During the week ending
                        tbe 28th ult. the mortality returns were 202 natives and 12 foreigners and
                        the ratios 33.2 and 13.5 per thousand. For the week ending on Saturday last
                        the figures were 207 natives and 18 Euro- peans, the rates being 34.4 and
                        20.3 per mile respectively. For tbe guidance of those of our readers who are
                        interested in statistics, we may men- tion that according to the official
                        table recently published tbe native population of Cairo and its suburbs was
                        estimated on the 1st July last at 615,152. No exact esti- mate can, however,
                        be made of the foreign resident inhabitants of either Cairo or Alex- andria,
                        as no returns are obtainable from the Consulates. The last census of June
                        1897 gave the foreign element at 25,219 and 46,118 for each of the above
                        cities respectively but, of course, these figures must have been
                        considerably augmented since then by im- migration and excess of births over
                        deaths. The same tables give the estimated number of the native population
                        of Alexandria on the date above mentioned as 316.639.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
                    <p>The new Moss liner Menepthah sailed hence yesterday afternoon for Liverpool,
                        via Malts with passengers, mails and general cargo. The S.S. Asiatic Princa
                        from Antwerp and Middlesbrorgh, left Malta yesterday, and doe to arrive at
                        Alexandria on Saturday next.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>Beck &amp; Co s Pilsener Beei BREMEN.</head>
                    <p>Obtainable from every Respectable firm IN CAIRO, ALEXANDRIA AND THE SUDAN.
                        Otherwise apply to E J. FLEURENT, F. MICALLEF, sole agent</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LIFE OF M. WITTE THREATENED.</head>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>TREPOFFS REMOVAL DEMANDED.</head>
                    <p>(Gazette's Special Service). London, Tuesday, Nov. 7. Quiet continues to
                        prevail in St. Petersburg. The Tsar’s manifesto abolishing exclusive laws is
                        unconfirmed. The Duma is to consist of 600 members, elected on the basis of
                        property, education, and class representation. MWitte’s appointment as
                        Premier of Russia’s first Cabinet has beea gazetted. The revolutionary
                        leaders have threatened to take the life of M. Witte if General Trepoff is
                        not removed from his post within three days. M. Witte is residing in the
                        Winter Palace. The Tsar is expected in St. Petersburg on Friday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>LORD MINTO AT PORT SAID.</head>
                    <p>(From our Correspondent.) Port Said, Tuesday. Lord Minto, the new Viceroy of
                        India arrived here to-day by tbe P.&amp; O. mail S.S. Victoria on his way to
                        India.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                    <p>H. H. the Khedive spent yesterday at Koubbeh.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PRINCES AND THE DAIRA.</head>
                    <p>The legal department of the Finance Minis- try has sent a note to the
                        Under-Secretary of State for Finanoe on the subject of the Khedi- vial
                        Princes’ claims re the Daira Sanieh. The note shows that the Princes have
                        little chance n of winning their case.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NATIVE APPEAL COURT.</head>
                    <p>The Ministry of Justice has decided to create a new judgeship in the Native
                        Court of Appeal at Cairo. Hussein Bey Rouchdy, a judge ot the Cairo Mixed
                        Bench, has been selected for this post and will enter on his new duties on
                        the 1st January.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NEW INSECT PEST.</head>
                    <p>Considerable damage has been done in one or two local idea in Upper Egypt to
                        the pome- granate by the larva of a small but pretty butterfly
                        scientifically known as Dendoriz livia and a relative of the' well known
                        “blues” and “copeprs.” It seems that the caterpillar, to which usually
                        devours tbe pods of the “fitneh” accacia enters the pomegranate immediately
                        after leaving the egg and eats long tunnels into tbe fruit Three galleries
                        get rapidly filled with mildew and the "frass” of the insect, and the fruit
                        is spoiled.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE PISANI CASE.</head>
                    <p>The hearing of the Pisani case, which took place at H.B,M.’s Consulate Cairo,
                        yesterday resulted in the defendant being ordered to appear for trial before
                        the judge of the Supreme Consular Court, who is expected to arrive in Cairo
                        in about ten days to a fortnight’s time. The accused was allowed to find
                        bail, gua- ranteed by two sureties of j£160 eaoh.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>NILE VALLEY OPERATIONS.</head>
                    <p>The following report, dated Ootober 14, has been received from the Mine:-No.
                        1 shaft, 900 ft level.—North drive—This drive is now a total length of 27
                        ft. from the centre of the shaft. South drive.—The face of this drive is 18
                        ft 6 ins from the centre of the shaft. No. 5 shaft, 2nd leveL—North
                        drive.—This drive is now a total leng’h of 212 ft 3 ins from the cross-cut.
                        Tbe face of this drive is now some 20 ft north of point at which the ore
                        pinched out in the level above and is directly under the point at which the
                        cross-head cut off the fisure. Occasional specks of gold are met with. No. 7
                        shaft, 2nd level.—South drive.- This drive has again advanced to 216 ft 6
                        ins. from the cross-cut. Battery. The consignment of oil arrived on Sunday
                        morning last, since when the battery has been running steadily night and
                        day, the ore crushed being from development. </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>BAND PERFORMANCE.</head>
                    <p>By kind permission of Col H.F.M. Wilson and the officers, tbe band of the 2nd
                        Batt. Rifle Brigade will play the following program- me at the Continental
                        Hotel to-morrow (Thursday) at 8 p.m, on the occassion of the King’s
                        Birthday. 1. March- Long live the King - Hume. 2. Overture- Festival-
                        Lenteur. 3. Selection- The Dancing Doll- Bayer. 4. Funeral March of a
                        Marionette- Gounod 5. Intermezo- Rendezvous- Aletter 6. Selection- Faust-
                        Gounod 7. Landler- Grossumtterchan- Lungey. 8. Velze- Morgenblatter- Trauss
                        Khedivial Anthem- God Save the King R. Wood, Bandmaster </p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head> BRITISH GARRISON. </head>
                    <head>NOW COMMANDED BY SIRDAR.</head>
                    <p>The British troops stationed at Khartoum have been placed under the command
                        of his Excellency the Governor-General of the Sudan, and have been struck
                        off the strength of tbe Egyptian Command with effect from 6th inst,
                        inclusive.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>RAMBLEH'S WATER SUPPLY</head>
                    <p>To the Editor or the Egyptian Gazette. Sir,—As everybody is aware, we have
                        had two fires at Ramleh within the last month, and at both of these the Fire
                        Brigade promptly turned up ,but was quite useless as there was no water.
                        This news has already appeared in the columns of the “Gazette,” but we have
                        had no reply or contradiction from the Alex- andria Water Company, which
                        turns off the Ramleh water supply about 5 p.m. Fortanately on eaoh of the
                        nights on which the fires occured there was no wind. Otherwise in the case
                        of tbe fire at Bacos, all that thickly populated part of Ramleh might have
                        devastated. I presume that nothing will be done to remedy this deplorable
                        state of things until the palatial residence of some Municipal Councillor or
                        of one of the Kbedivial Princes is completely gutted. Then, and not till
                        then, will pressure be brought to bear on the Alexandria Water Company.
                        Meanwhile, all the inhabitants of Ramleh must go to bed every night with the
                        apprehension that if their home does gat on fire, all they can do is to
                        watch it burn—Truly yurs, A Ramlehite. Balkeley, 7th November.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>CAIRO STREET PERILS.</head>
                    <p>Dear Sir,—I was recently told the following story by a friend, which I repeat
                        in the hope that those to whom we vaguely refer as “the proper authorities”
                        will read, mark, and learn. My informant was walking slowly one after- noon
                        along one of Cairo’s streets—and by no means its meanest—and found time to
                        pause for an instant and admire the demeanour of two Arabs who were walking
                        along tbe pavement hand in hand cleanly dressed, silent—for a wonder—and
                        their faces illumined with an abject and ruatio happiness which was worth
                        going miles to see. Suddenly a loud gargling noise came from overhead, and
                        from a spout that project- ed apparently aimlessly from a third story a jet
                        of soapy water descended on the pair. They first exhibited a wild surprise
                        and then in- dulged for a couple of minutes in excusable, if unrestrained,
                        profanity, after which they wiped their garments and moved on, still
                        cursing, amid demonstrations of amused sym- pathy from the passers-by. Now,
                        Sir, I like a harlequinade as much as any man—the spectacle of a policeman
                        falling through a trap door or coming in contact with a red hot poker has
                        always and will always please me. There is a strenuous humour ia the
                        oartoons of eighteenth century caricaturist that also appeals to me, and the
                        decent of a tub-full of soap suds on an immaculately dressed passer-by has
                        been immortalised by their pencils. But I frankly admit that I dslike
                        practical jokes when they are directed against me ; my motto is flat ex-
                        perimentum in corpore vili, and I now make a detour whenever I notice one of
                        these projecting spouts which, I hear, carry away the overflow of baths and
                        washhouses. If our city authori- ties can do something to prevent their
                        being need in this way they will earn the gratitude of many besides.
                        Meticulous. Cairo, November 7.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    <p>Adly Pasha Yaghen called upon the Prime Minister yesterday.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>The salary of Lord Edward Cecil Pasha as Under Secretary of State for Finance
                        has been fixed at L.E. 2,000 per aonum.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>M. de la Bouliniere arrived at Cairo from Alexandria at 8 p.m. yesterday and
                        was met at the station by MM. Bonin, Bonequet, and the remaining members of
                        the personnel of the French Agency and Consulate.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Among tbose leaving for Egypt on the India at the end of the month are the
                        Dow- ager Lady Kensington and Miss Winifred Edwardes, Lady Messsrene and Sir
                        W.E. Cooper.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Count A. Gouzaga will pay a short visit to Jerusalem in tbe near future.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr. and Mrs. E. W. P. Foster have retruned to Alexandria from Europe.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>M. Saint Saena the emirent composer, in- tends paying a visit to Egypt in
                        December or January next. In February he goes to Monte Carlo to attend the
                        rehearsals of his new opera, L’Ancetre.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>We regret to hear that Me. Molteni had a paralytic stroke late on Monday
                        night, and that his condition, in spite of unremitting medical watchfulness
                        and care, gives rise to very serious anxiety.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <p>Mr.Reeves has arrived at the Carlton Hotel Balkeley.</p>
                </div>
                <div type="item">
                    <head>THE SUCBERIES CRASH.</head>
                    <head>M. Poutrel v. Hon. A.J Davey</head>
                    <p>On Monday the action brought by M. Poutret against the Hon. A.J. Davey came
                        before tbe Cairo Mizel Tribunal the hearing wu put back to the role special.
                        M. Poutrel claims one franc damages costs and the in- sertion of the verdict
                        in three Egyptian and three French newspapers, on the ground that tbe Hon.
                        A. J. Davey dismissed him unjus- tifiably from the service of the Suceries
                        Company on the charge of having kept him in ignorance of tbe Say operations,
                        and that there is no foundation whatever for the charge. Tbe plaintiff's
                        assignation contains an elaborate summary of the reasons go to prove his own
                        innocence in the matter. We extract the* following passages from the
                        assignation:-- Attendu que par lettre du 29 septembre 1905, le sieur Davey a
                        licencie le sieur Poutrol du service de la Societe des Sucraries. Attendu
                        que les motifs mis en avant par Davey consistent en des imputations de plu-
                        sieurs faite ayant tous eu pour but an dire de Davey, de le tenir lui Davey
                        dans l'ignorance de operations Say (io)... Attendu que si ion comprend tres
                        bien I'in- teret que pent avoir. Davey dane les ciroons- tances sotuelles a
                        se faire considerdere comme etant reste dans lignorance deadites opera-
                        tions, il est impossible pourtant qu'il cherche a faire cela an detriment
                        d’un employe dont la eonduito a toojours e e absolument correcte, et a se
                        constituer ainsi les elemnts d’un “alibi moral” preventif. Or attendu que
                        Poutrel ne pouvalt avoir I’idee de tenir Davey dans l'gnorances de ces
                        operations (acceptions on antres) par la rai- son toute simple qu’il ne
                        pouvait venir a l'ide de personne que Davey put les ignore. Attendu quo pour
                        supposer que Davey les ignonorait, il aurait tallu supposer ches ledit Davey
                        une dose d’ingenuite equivalant a l'in- conscience. Attendu en effet que ces
                        operations out toutes e e passeces regulierement en comptabi- . lite et
                        figurent en toutes lettres ettons chiffres dans les livres de la societe.
                        Attendu, en consequence qu'a moins de ne pas saior lire ou de ne pas vouloir
                        voir, toute pereonne jetont les yeux sur les livres (et Davey avait ce
                        pouvoir et ce devoir) etait ne- cessairement mis au courant des dites opera-
                        tions. Attendu que dans ces conditions, suppose Davey non au courant des
                        acceptations Say, ce serait admettre ohez lui ou bien la desertion abeolue
                        de son devoir et la meconnaissanbe eotiere de son mandat, ou bien une
                        attitude speciale a la plus invetere et a la plus son- pable des ignorances.
                        Attendu qne bien loin de vouloir cacher a quiconque ces operations Say, que
                        Davey repudie maintenant, cest Pontrel lui-meme qui, entre en fonetions, a
                        donne personnel- lement des ordres pour que ces operations, tenues
                        jurqualora en dehors de la compta- bilite se ent desormais passees
                        reguliere- ment et integralement dans la comptabilite generale. Attendu
                        qu'ainsi passees integralament ces operations ni rien de ce quis’y rap-
                        portait ne ponvait etre cache qu’il fant done pour pretendre avoir ete tanu
                        dans l’ignorance et recourir a de si pauvres pre- textes faire appal aux
                        ressources fertiles d’une imagination complaisante plutot quiaux saines
                        lumieires de la raison. Attendu d’ailleurs que Davey est reste siul
                        administrateur present en Egypte en l'ete 1903, (le requerant etant aussi
                        absent a cette epoque); que dans ces conditions personne n’etant la pour lui
                        maintenir de force le bandeau sur les yeux, il eat impes- sible que Davey
                        u'ait pas ete mis par M, Boinet, son securiaire particulier, choisi per
                        lui-meme et charge depouillement de la correspindance sinon au courant da
                        moine aur la piste de ces operations qu'il ignorait et core apres 5 ans
                        passes par lui a la Di- rection de la societe. Attendu que dans le courrant
                        de la presente. annes, dans une instance engages contre la Societe, il a ete
                        depose par le sieur Talbot, l'adversaire de la societe, un memoire dont les
                        echos meme affaibliset aisent encore assez suggestifs. Que ce meme memoire a
                        sans doute ete au moins parcouro par l’avocat de la Societe, pui que ledit
                        ayocayat a demande dans ses con- clusions qu’il ful ecarle des debata comme
                        iejurieux (sic), a certainement ete communique par cet avocat aux
                        administrateura delegues (dont M. Davey) a moins que de ce chef encore ce
                        dernier n'accuse l'honorable Me Carton de l'avoir lui aussi maintenu dans
                        son etat d'ignorance chronique. Attendu done que Poutrol ne pouvant meme pas
                        soupenner que Davey put ignorer les ope- rations Say, il a'envuit qu’il
                        n’alien pa faire pour eotretenir une ignorance qui, a ses yeux, n’existant
                        pas. Attendu que dans ces conditions le licen- ciement dont Poutrol a ete
                        victime est aussi arbitraire qu’injustice. Attendu que ce
                        licenciement,injuriex pour Poutrel, est deriicA k raisra durir^buioea ' nn
                        qootid ra do matin. Qaa oette inisrtioa, eommandAe A Hem- nut par oslai l*
                        mfime qui svalt btfirfit k ; %Tgu„ do son ignorance dee folts, 0 encore
                        ^gmtA, k raison do eon oarao’tro quasi-’ ' dAtietoeux. b nsponsabilitA prop
                        re et pmeoa* nolle do Davey, rospoosabilitAdAjk emit pot
                        fosagisaeatnttntmen*lonta.</p>
                </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                        <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, Thursday, NOVEMBER 9 190S.</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE RUSSIAN HORRORS</head>
                        <head>“SURPASS IMAGINATION.”</head>
                        <head>VILLAGES BURNT.</head>
                        <p>St. Petebsburg, November 8. An official communique says that it is not to
                            be denied that, in some places, the local anthori- ties are hostile to
                            the reforms and have encouraged the recent excesses. A judicial enquiry
                            has been ordered in all the localities where it is suspected that such
                            has been the case. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Batoum, November 8. 120 Cossacks under the Governor of the district were
                            burning the villages in a turbulent district in the interior when they
                            were sur- rounded by armed rioters. 105 were killed after a desperate
                            resistance of 17 hours, (R)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Odessa, November 8. Yesterday 412 Jewish victims were buried in the
                            presence of vast crowds. They were buried, without coffins, in trenches
                            of seventy each. (R)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>St. Petersburg, November 8. Despite the general cessation of strikes, the
                            Railway Union has issued a significant circular to the railway men
                            saying that they must store their arms, and when the decisive mo- ment
                            comes rise as one man, and never lay them down until a complete victory
                            be won. The details of the horrors of the past ten days are gradually
                            leaking out. They surpass imagination. In one instance, at Minsk,
                            several detachments of troops poured a cross-fire into an unarmed crowd,
                            killing and wounding 400 in a few moments. It appears that 50,000 troops
                            with guns were landed by the warships at Helsingfors on the 3rd instaht.
                            The situation became most critical, when the Imperial manifesto arrived
                            and relieved the tension. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RELIEF ORGANISED BY JEWS.</head>
                        <p>New York, November 8. A mass meeting of Jews has formed a relief
                            committee in aid of the Russian sufferers ir- respective of religion.
                            56.800 dollars were received from Jews in London, Paris, and Berlin
                            offering to participate in an international relief organisation.
                            {Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GRAND DUKE VLADIMIR.</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, November 8. The Grand Duke Vladimir has resigned his
                            command of the Guard. (Hovaa)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>M. WITTE’S CABINET.</head>
                        <p>London, November 8. The "Times" learns from St. Petersburg that M. Witte
                            has completed his Cabinet. Prince Urosoff becomes Minister of the
                            Interior, Prince Eugene Trubetxski takes the portfolio of Public
                            Instruction, M. Shipoff that of Agriculture, while M. Nimjechaieff
                            becomes Minister of Railways. All bare liberal views. M. J. Sbipoff
                            takes the portfolio of Finance; the others are unchanged. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RAILWAY STRIKE IN AUSTRIA.</head>
                        <head>UNIVERSAL 8UPPRAGE MOVEMENT.</head>
                        <p>Vienna, November 8. Ten thousand Austrian railway employees have struck.
                            Their demands inclnde universal suffrage. The movement is spreading.
                            {Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE CRETAN INSURRECTION.</head>
                        <head>AMNESTY PROCLAIMED.</head>
                        <p>Canea, November 8. A proclamation has been issued by Colonel Benedetti,
                            chief of the international troops, calling upon the insurgents to lay
                            down their arms, and promising them an amnesty. (H)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BRITISH SQUADRON IN AMERICA.</head>
                        <p>Washington, November 8. After a week of the most cordial amenities from
                            naval and official circles here and at Annapolis, tbe British Squadron
                            went to Baltimore, where it was ovated by a crowd of 30,000, and thence
                            to New York. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>TYPHOON IN JAPAN.</head>
                        <p>Tokio, November 8. A typhoon has ravaged the peninsula of Oshima.
                            (Hovas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>POWERS AND TURKEY.</head>
                        <head>NAVAL DEMONSTRATION.</head>
                        <head>BLOCKADE OF DARDANELLES.</head>
                        <p>London, November 8. It is expected that the oombined fleets of tbe
                            Powers, composed of 15 worships, will appear in the Levant at the end of
                            the week. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Vienna, November 8. It is stated here that if the demonstration does not
                            modify the opposition of the Porte to the Macedonian reform scheme, the
                            pacific blockade of tbe Dardanelles will be proclaimed. {Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                        <p>The Sanitary Administration is, we under- stand, in future to be known as
                            the Public Health Administration.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Cairo-Alesandria Navigation, except-by way of the river, is at present
                            impracticable as the Bagonrieh Canal is closed for the time being.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Survey Department -The Finance Minis- try has opened a credit of L.E
                            4,0(0 for the Survey Department, in order to facilitate the land
                            survey.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>New Doctors—Abd-El-Arii Mohamed El- Ghamry, Dadd Suleiman Bulus, and
                            Shukri Khalil Maluf, doctors, have been authorised to follow their
                            profession in Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Pilgrimage. — The Ministry of the Interior has selected the personnel
                            for the escort of the Mahmal. The Khedive will shortly nominate the Emir
                            el Hag.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Late Grand Mufti. -- The late Sheikh El Rafei left two works on the
                            Hsnifi rite, to which he put the finishing touches only a few weeks
                            before his death. His sons intend to publish those works after
                            Ramadan.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Suez Canal.—29 vessels passed through the Canal on the 4th and 5th inst.,
                            17 of which were British, 5 German, 3 French, 1 Austrian, 1 Dutch, 1
                            Swedish, 1 Egyptian. The receipts from the lst to the 5th inst were frs.
                            1,958,634.39.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Salt &amp; Soda Co., Ltd. —The sales of salt during Ootober produced L.B.
                            21,163 828, against L.E. 20,599 025 in October, 1901, the total sales
                            daring the ten months of each year being:—1905, LB. 209,216.165 ; 1904,
                            LE. 206,690.367.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Canal Cleaning.—All the canals in the Menoufieh and Gharbieh provinces
                            will have lower levels or will be closed to navigation by the 20th
                            December and navigation will be impossible, or at any rate very
                            difficult, from that date to the 20th Janaary, 1906.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Railway Fatality. - An express train was passing by E'phent station, at 1
                            a.m. on the 7th inst., when a native woman fell on to the line under the
                            train. Her head and hands were cat off. The next morning the doctor said
                            the moawen of Fashn marker examined the body, but it was not
                            identified.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Cairo ‘ Zoo.”—By kind permission of the military authorities the Egyptian
                            Army In- fantry Band will play in tbe Ghizeh Zoolo- gical Gardens every
                            Sunday afternoon during this season, commencing on Sunday, 19th inst.
                            The Ghizeh Boys Band will play as usual in the Zoological Gardens every
                            Friday after- noon.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Affray with Robbers.—A party of night robbers broke into an ezbeh near
                            Da- lamsha, Bilbeis markaz, on Tuesday night, but were repelled by the
                            gbaffirs, who fired upon them, killing one. Tbe police com- ing rapidly
                            up, cut off the retreat of the remaining members of the gang, who are
                            now in prison</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Recruiting Department. — The Electorship of the Recruiting
                            Department, now vacant owing to the appointment of Sarhank Pasha to
                            succeed Lord Edward Cecil Pasha as Under-Secretary of State for War,
                            will probably be conferred on Miralai Mahmoud Bey Tewfik, head of the
                            Military College, who in his turn will be replaced by Hussein Bey
                            Jherif, chief of the Recruiting Department in be Gharbieh province.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>KING’S BIRTHDAY REVIEW.</head>
                        <head>KHEDIVE PRESENT.</head>
                        <p>The presence of H.H. the Khedive and of Lord Cromer, the bright weather,
                            and the occasion of the 64th birthday of King Edward VII. drew large
                            numbers of sightseers to this morning's review on Abdeen-sqaaro, Cairo,
                            and though, as a spectacle, the sight was perhaps not as impressive as
                            in 1904, owing to the reduction of the Army of Occupation, there was
                            still any amount of oolour and life in the scene, and the troops bore
                            themselves admirably. Comparisons are of course odious, and we have no
                            intention of attempting them. We need only say that the parade movements
                            were very good, the marching, dressing, wheeling, etc., being
                            excellently carried out, and that the physique of the men was admirable.
                            The British soldier in Egypt is a far more satisfac- tory sight than too
                            many of the rank and file of tbe line battalions that one sees at home,
                            and which often appear to be composed of weedy boys. The police were in
                            readiness before 9 a.m., and the square, which had been cleared of
                            vehicles and loiterers, awaited the coming of tbe troops. At the
                            entrances of the streets leading to the square, except those that had
                            been kept free for the troops to enter and to leave by, large crowds
                            gathered betimes, and the enclosures filled up rapidly. By a
                            quarter-past nine all the troops had moved into the square and taken up
                            their posi- tions, facing westward, the Rifles being on the left nearest
                            the Palace, the Inniakillings next, and the Royal Engineers, Mounted
                            Infantry, and Royal Garrison Artillery on the right. At 9.80 Lord Cromer
                            drove up, the troops saluting to the strains of "God save the King,”
                            while the Royal Standard was hoisted. The British Consul-General, after
                            a short oonversa tion with Brig-General Bullock, then drove along tbe
                            rank, the troops presenting arms as he passed. H.H. the Khedive
                            afterwards arrived, escort- ed by his Body Gaard, and mounted on a
                            magnificent white Arab, tire bands playing the Khedivial Anthem as his
                            Highneea took up his position close to the Royal Stan- dard. A general
                            salute followed, the national anthem being played again, and the troops
                            gave three cheers for H.M. the King with great heartiness, to the
                            accompaniment of the guns in the CitadeL The troops then marched past,
                            H.H. the Khedive taking the salute, after which came the interesting
                            ceremony of trooping the colour. The review closed with the Khedivial
                            salute, alter which officers and men returned to barracks. We understand
                            that the Khedive expressed his great satisfaction to General Bollock at
                            the fine appearance and admirable drill of the troops.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CELEBRATION AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                        <p>At Alexandria, the usual parade took place on Mustapha Pasha
                            parade-gronnd at 10 a.m. a feu dejoie being fired by the Royal Dublin
                            Fusiliers. At the same time a salute of 21 guns was fired from Fort
                            Kom-el-Dik. The Royal Standard Boats over all stations occupied by
                            British troops to-day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                        <p>Immediately after the review this morning the Khedive returned to Abdeen
                            Palace, where he received the Russian Agent and Consul- General, who
                            presented his credentials in solemn audience.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LORD EDWARD CECIL</head>
                        <p>The following Order has been published by H.R the Sirdar :— H.B. the
                            Sirdar wishes to express the great- est regret at the retirement from
                            the Egyptian Army of El Lewa Lord Edward Cecil Pasha, D.S.O., who is
                            taking up a new appointment under the Egyptian Government as Under-
                            secretary of State in the Ministry of Finance, As Military Secretary,
                            Director of Intelligence, Agent-General, and Under-Secretary of State
                            for War, Lord Edward Cecil has shown most marked ability and tact, and
                            the excellenoe and brilliance of his work has been very con- spicuous.
                            The Sirdar desires to place on record his sincere appreciation of this
                            officer's most valuable services, and on behalf of the Army wishes him
                            every success in his future career.”</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE PILGRIMAGE.</head>
                        <p>The Ministry of Finance has agreed to a credit of LB. 14,000 for the
                            sanitary and other measures to be taken on the return of tbe pilgrims
                            from Mecca and Medina.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The Cunard S.S. Pavia arrived at Liverpool yesterday afternoon. The S.S.
                            Royal Prince, with passengers and general cargo, from London, left Malta
                            yester day, and is due to arrive at Alexandria on Sanday. The Westcott
                            S.S. City of Dundee arrived last night from Newcastle, London, snd
                            Malts, with passengers snd general cargo. Tbe EIIeiman S.S. Andalusian
                            arrived yes- terday from Glasgow and Malta with general cargo. The
                            Ellerman S.S. Avon tails to-day for Liverpool direct.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BIRTHDAY HONORS.</head>
                        <head>LOCAL RECIPIENTS.</head>
                        <head>(Gazette's Special Service).</head>
                        <p>London, Thursday, Nov. 9. Among the recipients of Birthday honors are Dr.
                            Buffer and Harari Pasha, who have been made C.M.G.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EARL OF MINTO AT PORT SAID.</head>
                        <p>(From our Correspondent.) Port Said, Wednesday. The P. &amp; O. Victoria,
                            by which Lord and Lady Minto are travelling to India, has a large number
                            of prominent people on board, among whom are Major F. L Adam (Lord
                            Minto’s A.D.C.), Sir G. Arbothnot, Surgeon Lieut. Col. and Mrs. W. R.
                            Crooke-Lawlesa, Dr. K Dolman, Lord C. Dundas, Lady E Elliott, Lady R.
                            Elliott, Lady V. Elliott, Lady Fawkes, Hon. and Mrs. R Lyttleton, Sir
                            Francis and Lady MaoLean, with two daughters, Lord Francis Soott,
                            Lieot-Co. J. R. Dunlop Smith, Lady Sampson, and the Hon. Vansittart-
                            Lord Minto, with a large party of friends, dined at the Eastern Exchange
                            last night</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EXPRESS SERVICE TO EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>The Ellerman, Hall and City Lines announced a monthly express service
                            from Liverpool to Egypt Bombay, and Knrrachee. The service will commence
                            on December 14 with the Trafford Hall, a new steamer launched last week.
                            The average passage to Port Said is to be ten and a half days, and to
                            Bombay twenty-one days' sea passage, the Seer Canal excluded. The
                            steamers allocated to this service include the new steamer City of
                            Calcutta, which recently made a passage to Calcutta under twenty-six
                            days.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SALVAGE OF DERELICT CRANE.</head>
                        <p>During the homeward voyage of the New castle steamer Aureole, from the
                            Black Sea to Shields, the crew came across a self-propelling floating
                            crane, supported by means of a pontoon about 100ft long, used for ship
                            repairing in rivers or harbors. It was in the direct route of steamers
                            bound from Cape Matapan to Cape Pasoaro. The Aoreole took the pontoon in
                            tow with three 7in. hawsers. For a time some of the sailors remained
                            aboard the deraliot to bale out the water, but it labored so heavily in
                            tbe heavy seas that they were obliged to come on board tbeir own vessel.
                            The pontoon crane which was worth £l 5,000, was bound for Port Said, but
                            nothing is known as to wbat has beoome of its crew or the tag which
                            presumably bad charge of it. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAIRO MIXED TRIBUNALS.</head>
                        <p>The Cairo Tribunal Correctional met yester- day morning under the
                            presidency of Judge Nyholm. supported by Judge Hexligera and Judge
                            Yonuef Axis The assessors were Dr. Voronoff, Dr. A. Schoober.and Messrs.
                            J. Payn, R. Bnriqoez, and Charles Batten berg, the Parqnet being
                            represented by Mahmond Bey Rashdy. Three appeals against sentences for
                            contra- ventions were heard, a British and Russian and a French snbject
                            having all got into trouble for keeping an establishment for hashish
                            smokers. In two cases the hearing of the appeal was pat off for a month
                            ; in the third the sentence was upheld by default. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LAND AND GENERAL TRUST.</head>
                        <p>Mr. Hooker, we learn, is only awaiting the dispositions of the London
                            board, before sever- ing his connection with the Egypt Land and General
                            Trnst Limited. Mr. A. P. Maok, a director of the Land and General Trust
                            left London on Tuesday last for Egypt, in connection with the business
                            of the Trust.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ROBBERY OF ANTIQUITIES.</head>
                        <p>There have been a large and increasing number of robberies at Karnak
                            lately among the workmen employed by M. Legrain in excavating on behalf
                            of the Department of Antiquities. The most honest and hardest workers
                            have one after the other been caught in the very act, and in every case
                            the theft was done to the temptations put in the way of the workmen by
                            the dealers in antiquities, who offer the men very high prices. At
                            Karnak there are agents paid by these dealers, who deliberately corrupt
                            the workmen and the night watchmen.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NOTES FROM MENA.</head>
                        <p>The following residents are staying at Mena Honse: Mrs. Sidney Carver and
                            Min Carver, Mrs. Madden and fsmily, Mr. C. F. Armstrong, Ugo La-ena Bey.
                            Mr. J. M. Dodd, Mr. C. N. Firth, Rev. and Mrs. Gordon Proctor. Dr. and
                            Mrs. BUiot Smith and Mr. P. 8. Anderson and family will spend the winter
                            at Mena Honse. Mr. James P. G. Hopkins and family are »lao booked for a
                            short stay there. Among others staying at Mena are Dr. and Mrs. Hayes,
                            Mr. Wright Henderson, Mr. 0- Crockett, Mrs. Charles Pease, Min Bewley,
                            and Herr Kart Wuttke.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CATTLE PLAGUE.</head>
                        <head>FRESH OUTBREAK IN SUDAN.</head>
                        <p>Cattle plague has again broken out in the Sudan. 8,000 doses of serum
                            have been dis- patched from Cairo, and it is hoped that the outbreak
                            will be oonfined to the small area at present infected. We learn that
                            several veterinary inspectors, who have up to the present been employed
                            on cattle plague work in Egypt, are to be transferred for duty in the
                            Sudan. The Serum Institute that was opened at Abassieh has been given up
                            altogether, the remaining bulls having been bled to death for serum. A
                            quantity of this rinderpest serum is now stored with the Nile Cold
                            Storage, Co., sufficient to keep within bounds any serious outbreak.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>IMPORTATION OF CATTLE.</head>
                        <p>The Quarantine Board has decided to with- draw, as from the 29nd inst.,
                            the decision to admit into the abattoirs is the interior of Egypt
                            bovidue coming from Syria, Asia Minor as for as the Dardanelles, Turkey
                            in Barope (Macedonia, Bulgaria), Ronmania, and Russia, and from any
                            other country which may not be recognised as healthy and free from any
                            suspicion of episooty. These bovidic, however, will be admitted at
                            Alexandria and Port Said, with a view to their slaughter in quarantine.
                            Bovide coming from the Somali coast and from the Eastern Sudan will be
                            landed at Suez. there to be slaughtered in quarantine. Tbe present
                            dispositions concerning sheep remain in force.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head>
                        <p>Another case of plague has been discovered at Alexandria, the patient
                            being a Greek pastry- cook of the Midan quarter. In consequence of this
                            case the usual qua- rantine measures on the departure of vessels from
                            Egyptian ports have been re-established.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FINANCE MINISTRY.</head>
                        <p>In all likelihood Lord R Cecil Pasha, as co-Under Secretary of State for
                            Finance with Mr. Mitchell Innes, will be allotted the Free State Land
                            and the Direct Taxes Departments. The remaining departments will be left
                            for Mr. Mitchell Innes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
                        <p>Lieutenant G. Stewart, Coldstream Guards, has been specially selected for
                            service in the Egyptian Army. Leave of absence, on private affairs, has
                            been granted to El Lewa St. George C. Henry Pasha, O.B., Adjutant
                            General, B1 Kai" akam Bray Bey, Medioal Corps, Bl Kaimakam Com- u ins
                            Bey, Medioal Corps, Bl Kaimakam Ismail Bey Himmet, Beoraiting
                            Department. Bl Bim- ba«hi Clayton, Deputy Assistant Adjutant General,
                            and El Bimbashi Teacher, 19th Sudanese. The undermentioned offioers
                            passed the Intermediate Arabio Examination held on the 2nd Ootober: El
                            Bimbashi Feilden, Inspector, Bahr El Ghsztl Province, El Bimbashi Lewin,
                            Assistant Financial Secretary, El Bimbashi Carey, 16th Battalion, El
                            Bimbashi Nickerson, Inspector, Sennar Province, and El Bimbashi Jennings
                            Bramly, Cavalry.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STATE DOMAINS.</head>
                        <p>Messrs. N. M. Rothschild and Sons an- nouncee that a drawing amounting to
                            £29,800 nominal capital of the Egyptian State Domain Mortgage bonds will
                            take place this month in accordance with the terms of the general bond
                            of this loan. The numbers and descrip- tions of tbe bonds drawn will be
                            advertised, and all bonds so drawn will cease to bear interest from
                            December 1.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>COTTON EXPORTS FROM EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>During the week ending the 29th October over 37,000 bales of cotton
                            reached tbe port of Manchester, of which 20,951 were from America and
                            the remainder from Egypt. American shipments of cotton to Manchester
                            this season have now reached 35,596 bales, a number behind the record of
                            1904. Tbe im- portations from Egypt show an increase over this
                            corresponding period of last year of about 3,000 bales.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CAIRO STREET NUISANCE.</head>
                        <p>A correspondent writes:- Some annoyance has recently been caused at Cairo
                            by the increases of that annoying class of bicyclists which prefers the
                            pavement to tbe road. Out at Gherireh, or beyond Shocbra and Abbasaieb,
                            there is, no doubt, less to be urged against tbe habit, but it is no
                            joke to walk on the pavements of, say, Suleiman Pasha-street, or the
                            streets leading toward tbe Ministries, if one is constantly called upon
                            to get ont of the way by the bells of youthful bicyclists, many of whom
                            seem to steer so badly that one easily understands why they avoid the
                            neighbourhood of the arabiyas. Of course, if one refuses to move the
                            cyclists must avoid the pedestrian, bnt he often steers so badly that it
                            is better to run no risks.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN.</head>
                        <head>SERIOUS DAMAGE TO RAILWAY.</head>
                        <head>(From oub Correspondent.)</head>
                        <p>Suakin, November 1. Washouts have taken place on the Suakin- Athars line,
                            and serious damage has resulted in several places. Trains stopped
                            running from both ends between the 95th and 98th Ootober, when tbe line
                            was repaired and put in good order. Kaimakam Loogfield Bey, E.E.,
                            Asaristant Director of Railways, left hereby special train on the night
                            of the 98th ult on inspection duty and returned on the 80th, -after
                            having found everything in perfect working order. Mr. Thomas Purvis,
                            Suakin-Atbara Railway, returned from leave of absence by the Khedi- vial
                            mari steamer Neghileh on 80th nit, bringing with him Mrs. Purvis and
                            child. Dr. Crispin, S.M.O., Buskin Mondirieh, is leaving for Port Sudan.
                            He will organise the Mondirieb medical staff and hospital then. Dr.
                            Pahmy win remain here as S.M.O. in charge of the hospitals and the
                            Suakin railway employee. Among the signs of the development of the
                            Sudan, and the benefits resulting from the opening of the new port, I
                            may mention the fact that Messrs. Loremato Bros., a large firm of
                            merchants, who have branches at almost every port in the Red Sea, have
                            already established themselves af Port Sedan. Both there and at Buskin,
                            they are largely patronised by English people. Their goods come chiefly
                            from England and are in price. Mr. George Lorenxtato is the general
                            manager, and all orders pass through his hands and receive his personal
                            attention.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MYSORE CO. AND EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>In the report of tbe Mysore Reefs and General Exploration Company for the
                            year ended September 30, the directors propose another reconstruction.
                            Tbe present company was formed as recently as July, 1909, as a
                            reconstruction of tbe Mysore Reefs (Kangundy) Mining Company, but the
                            directors now explain that a large proportion of the capital is repre-
                            sented in the balance sheet by the property originally worked in India,
                            upon which opera- tions have been suspended, and they considsr that the
                            time has arrrived when this unproduc- tive expenditure should be dealt
                            with. They, therefore, propose to form "The Mysore Reefs and General
                            Explorers, limited," to take over the assets and liabilities of the
                            present company. The capital of the new company would be £50,000,
                            divided into 40,000 Preference and 160,000 Ordinary Shares of 6s each
                            thus providing for the allotment of one fully-paid Ordinary Share for
                            each old Ordinary Shan, and one fully-paid Preference Share for each old
                            Preference Share. Tbe existing shares are £l fully paid, and the
                            proposal is thus to write down the capital account by 76 per dent The
                            report shows a balance of profit for the year at £1,673.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                        <p>Princess Nazli Hanem arrived at Alexandria from Tonis early this morning
                            by the S.S. City of Dundee. On the vetsel being signalled the Governor
                            went ont to meet her in a Ports and lights tender, and her Highness then
                            landed. She is proceeding to Cairo to-day.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Lady Cromer arrived at Cairo at 5 o’clock yesterday afternoon from Port
                            Said.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>M. de Kerber, ex-President of the Council in Austria, is expected in
                            Egypt in a few days. He will make a lengthy stay in Cairo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Baron de Villebois, the Dutch Agent and Consul-General at Cairo, is
                            expected to return on Saturday next</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Connt G. de Zogheb has arrived in Cairo from Europe.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Captain Gedge, R.N., Deputy Controller of Ports and Lighthouses, returned
                            to Alexandria from leave yesterday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. Edmond Robertson, M.P., left London last week for Gibraltar and
                            Egypt</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The latest bulletin indicates a alight improve- ment in the condition of
                            Maitre Molteni.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>M. Mermont, chief inspector to the French Eastern Railways and Mine
                            Mermont have arrived in Cairo, where they an making a short stay
                            preparatory to visiting Laxor and Assouan.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. Robert Williams, F.R.I.B.A., consulting architect to the Central
                            Buildings Co, Ltd., has returned to. Alexandria from London, there he
                            was called on important business. among other matters being the mosque
                            which it is proposed to build in the Metropolis. Mr. Williams,
                            notwithstanding the immense cost of the scheme feels asnguine that it
                            will be arried out sooner or later. The chief difficulty appears to be
                            finding a suitable site in tbe City. Mr. Williams, who was at one time a
                            member of the London County Council, is an authority on the boating
                            ques- tion, and has published a very interesting work on the subject,
                            which deserves the persual of many who an interested those in this
                            oouatry, </p>
                    </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <div type="item">
                        <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 10 1905</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE RUSSIAN CRISIS.</head>
                        <head>TREPOFF RESIGNS.</head>
                        <head>JEWS BURNED ALIVE. STREETS FLOWING WITH BLOOD.</head>
                        <p>St. Pbtersburg, November 9. Yielding to the popular demand, General
                            Tropoff has resigned. The authorities at Kishineff deliberately
                            organised the rabble against the Jews, giving the troops a pretext for
                            unbridled massacre aud pillage which lasted two days. There are 70.
                            killed and 120 wounded, all Jews. The mob at Ismail arranged an
                            auto-da-fo, burning alive 11 Jews who hid taken refuge in a haystack 59
                            Jews were killed at Kalaraech. Similar stories have been received from
                            other towns of Bessarabia. Soldiers and sailors at Cronstadt joined the
                            workmen in pillaging and bnrning. There was desperate fighting between
                            loyalists and revo- lutionaries, and there are pools of blood in the
                            streets. The inhabitants are fleeing. The war- ships have-been ordered
                            out of the harbour. It is reported that a force of lanoers sent from
                            Peterhof joined the riotors. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>St- Petersburg, November 9. General Trepoff has coated his functions.
                            (Throat)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Cronstadt, November 9. Disorders have occurred, accompanied by pillag
                            vand incendiarism. (Havas) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ACTION by consuls.</head>
                        <p>Odessa, November 9. In view of the possibility of farther disturb- ances
                            the Gerrnau, Austrian, and Italian Con- suls have requested their
                            Governments to send the guardships now at Constantinople to this city.
                            (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LONDON RELIEF FUND.</head>
                        <p>London, November 9. The Rothschilds and Mr. Schiff of New York have each
                            subscribed £10,000 to the Ixmdon relief fond. The money will be
                            distributed by the British oonsuls, who have been authorised by Lord
                            Lansdowne to undertake the task. (R.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE GRAND DUKE VLADIMIR</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, November 9. Grand Dake Vladimir has resigned his position
                            of commandant of the military district of St Petersburg. His resignation
                            has been accepted. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE ROYAL TOUR</head>
                        <head>ARRIVAL AT BOMBAY.</head>
                        <p>Bombay, November 9. The Prince and Princess of Wales have arrived here.
                            They received a splendid re- ception. ( Renter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BRITI8H SQUADRON AT NEW YORK ENTHUSIASTIC RECEPTION.</head>
                        <p>New York, November 9. The British squadron has received a most
                            enthusiastic reception. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CHURCH AND STATE IN FRANCE. DEBATE IN SENATE.</head>
                        <p>Paris, November 9. The Senate has commenced the debate on the Bill for
                            the separation of the Churches from the Senate. Several motions tor
                            adjorn- ment were rejected by a large majority. (H.)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>BIRTHDAY HONORS.</head>
                        <p>London, November 9. Birthday honors. The Duchess ol Pife will in future
                            be styled the Princess Royal and her daughters princesses. Doctor Buffer
                            and Henri Pasha are created Companions of the Order of St. Michael and
                            S. George. {Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>TAMMANY HALL VICTORY.</head>
                        <p>New York, November 8. It is believed that Mr. MacClolan, the Tammany Hall
                            Candidate, has been re elected Mayor by a small majority. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MUTINY IN BRAZIL</head>
                        <p>Rio Janiro. November 9. The troops in the fortress of Santa Cruz than
                            mutinied, but order has been restored. (B) </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>JOSEPH COMAS. TECHNICAL ENGINEtR</head>
                        <p>Sorveyor and Contractor in shipping. Take charge of Engines and Boilers.
                            Undertake repairs of same, guaranteeing success. First class references.
                            Address: Bue el Warena Maisoh Gabriel, ALEXANDRIA. 26685-12A-1</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Brindisi Mail will close at the G.P.O, Alexandria, at 3.10 p m. on
                            Sunday.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Egyptian Markets, Ltd—The decree au- thorising the reopening of the
                            cattle markets has been signed.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A Patal Kick. — A native youth, twelve years of ago, died yesterday from
                            the effects of a kick from a horse in tho Mobarrem Boy quarter of
                            Alexandria.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Syrian Emigrants.—The Menageries Ma ritimes S.S. Niger, which arrived at
                            Alexan- dria to day from the Syrian coast, has 700 Syrian emigrants on
                            board.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Wakfs Administration.—The Superior Conncil of the Wakfs Administration
                            will meet on Tuesday next, under the presidency ol Abdol Halim Pasha
                            Asrem.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Cairo Slaughter-house — Tho director of the Cairo Slaughterhouse, Chokib
                            Effeudi, will shortly be appointed chief veterinary surgeon at the
                            Asaioot Slaughter-house.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Electrocuted.—A tramway wire in Moha- med Aly-street, Cairo, snapped on
                            Wednesday night and fell on a native, named Ibrahim Mohamed, who was
                            killed on the spot</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Ramadan Salaries. — Owing to Beyram falling on the 28th inst., the
                            Government has decided that tho salaries for this month shall be paid on
                            the 25th ard 26th of the month.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Copts at MitGhamr. — A deputation of Coptic notables of Mit Gbsmr has
                            gone to Cairo to ask Boutros Pasha Ghali to recon- stitute the conncil
                            of the Coptic community at Mit Ghamr.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Suez Canal.—13 vessels passed through the Canal on the 6th inst., 9 of
                            which were British, 2 German, 1 French, 1 Aostrian. The receipts from
                            the 1st to the 6th inst. amounted to frs. 2,316,209.07.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mena House.—There will baa la'e tramway service to the Pyramids on tho
                            10th, lltb and 12th inst., the last tramcar leaving Meua House at 10.50
                            p.m. The management at Mena Hooac Hotel will provide special dinners for
                            residents at 25 piastres a head on these days. It goes without saying
                            that the menu is an excellent one.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LAND ALLOTMENT CO.</head>
                        <p>The founders' shares of the Land Allotment Company oiosed on the Cairo
                            Bourse yester day at P.T. 182, which was a somewhat considerable advance
                            on the previous day Dealing with the question why the ordinal) shares
                            remain below par while the founders shares are so sought after, a Cairo
                            firm o: stockbrokers make the following observation! in there circular
                            of yesterday’s dare : — II est, en effot, evident quo si la part d(
                            fondatenr vaut 132 piastres (et nous croyow qu’olle vaudra beauooup
                            pins) Faction vaot au mu ins, 532 piastres. La repartition dti benefices
                            ae fera, effeotivement, de la fo^oi auivante : D'abord b / * la reserve,
                            puis 6 ”/ aux actions. Sar le surplus, il est attribui dix poor cent au
                            Conseil d'Administration Le restant sera attriboe 70 % *ox actionnaira
                            et 30 % boa parts de foudateura.— Da sorb quo si la Socidte fait un
                            Wndfioo minim on annnel, par example, de 60,0t>0 livres, la par de
                            fondatenr touohera environ 10 piastres e Faction 5 %, plus environ onto
                            piastres e demio. Le caloul eerait le memo, quel qee soi le mont &amp;
                            nt do btotooe eveutuel. Si done, oi estime que la part de foudateor vaot
                            182 piat res, en capitalisant Faction dans les mdme proportions, elle
                            devrait valoir aojourd'ho environ 650 piastres: Or, on a ddtore A 3
                            13/16 c'est-A-dire A 381 piastres environ.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE EGYPTIAN POLICE. A MODEL FORCE</head>
                        <p>A leading New York newspaper, in ai article on the shortcomings of the
                            Philippino con-tabulary, remarks "Experience in Bgypt and elsewhere has
                            shown that it is £sr better to oontrol the natives by means of natives
                            than by foreign soldiers, who understand little of the local language
                            and still lose of the customs an feelings of the people. In Egypt the
                            establish ment of the Bgyptian gendarmerie was neither an easy task nor
                            wholly unattended by abnsai Yet it is one oi the successes of the Cromer
                            regime in their neatness, politeness, and effi oiency the Bgyptian
                            mounted constables are well worthy of imitation. The men who organis- ed
                            the Philippine Constabulary nndonb'edl had Cromer’s police in mind, and
                            were on the right track. It is only in the execution of their plsns that
                            mistakes have been made. Pri marily, they orgauised their Con«tabolsry
                            as peaoe fores. It was hardly onder way whe they were forced to nse it
                            in aotual warfare in competition with the Philippine Scouts. now an
                            adjunct of toe United States army, an were even called upon to fight
                            alongside regular soldiers."</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE ROYAL TOUR. VISIT TO EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>We learn on the beet authority that H.R.H. the Prince and Princess of
                            Wales will pay a visit to Cairo on their way back to England from India
                            in April next One result of this visit will be to prolong the season,—a
                            fact which will be welcomed by all.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LORD CURZON’S VISIT.</head>
                        <p>The home papers announced recently that Lord Co iron had abandoned his
                            contemplated visit to Cairo on his way back from India. We understand,
                            however, that ha and Lady Carton will oome on to Cairo and will spend a
                            clear day in the Capital ba*ore rejoining their ship.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                        <p>After the review in honor of the King's birthday H.H. the Khedive gave
                            aodienoe to i he Belgian Minister, M. Maskens, M. Charles Beyerle, Omar
                            Bey Lontfi, and Mr. Bond. In the afternoon the Khedive gave a Special
                            and official aodienoe to M. Smyrsoff, the new Russian Diplomatic Agent,
                            who presented his credentials and was received with the stately
                            ceremonial proper to anoh oocasions. The Khedive gave further receptions
                            in the ooarse of the afternoon to M. Barois, the Governor of Cairo, and
                            Sheikh el Sherbini, who present- ed the son of tks late Sheikh Abdel el
                            Kader El Rafehi to the Khedive. After an ijtar at 6 p.m. H.H. the
                            Khedive proceeded to the Citadel Mosque to attend a special service in
                            memory of Mohamed Aly. This morning he visited the Matarawi mosque, near
                            Matarieh, for prayer.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KING'S BIRTHDAY.</head>
                        <p>After the review yesterday visits were ex- chauged between Lord Cromer
                            and H. E. Bjutros Pasha Ghali, Minister for Foreigu Affairs.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Telegrams were sent by Mr. Alban in the name of the British Colony and by
                            Brig.- Oeneral Bollook in the name of the Army of Oooopation loyally
                            ocmgratulating H. M. the King on his 6ith birthday. list night two
                            important dinner parties were given in honor of the oocasion, one by
                            Lord Cromer to the principal civilian members of the British colony,
                            inclading of oourse the chiet British officials of the Egyptian Govern-
                            ment, aud the other to the Staff, commanding offioers, and departmental
                            beads of the Army of Occupation, given by Brigadier-General Bullock. Mr.
                            P. G. Freeman, H.B.M.’a Vice-Consul, held a leoeptiun at H.B.M.'s
                            Consulate yester- d.y morning, among the callers being H.K the Governor
                            and the Consols of the various Powers, besides a number of
                            representatives of the British Colony.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>QUARANTINE IN TURKEY.</head>
                        <p>Owing to the recurrence of plagne at Alex- andria, arrivals in Terkey
                            from this port are sabjeoted to a medical examination.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE STATE RAILWAYS.</head>
                        <p>According to a contemporary, an official belonging to one of the great
                            railway compa- nies in England is expeoted to arrive from London about
                            the end of the month, la order to give his advioe to the oommission
                            entrusted with the reorganisation of the State Railways.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE UM RUS MINE.</head>
                        <p>The operations during the fortnight ending Oet 16 were as follows: - Main
                            shaft was sunk A ft, total depth 678 It. Work here was delayed by water
                            from the old stapes entering through the winze above the 460 north-east.
                            660ft’ Cross-cut was advanoed 6 ft, total length 61 ft. Here also some
                            delay was caused by water from old stops 460 ft level north-east was
                            advanced 13 ft, making connection with the 860 ft No. 1 wins*, total
                            length 92 ft The Vein, 16 ins wide, assayed 19 dwts 14 grs. per too. 460
                            it level south west was driven 11 ft to a distance of 105 ft The quartz,
                            20 ins wide assayed 2 dwts 14 grs per ton. 450ft main winze was deepened
                            8 ft, total depth 81 ft The vein has averaged 15 ins, mixed with oountry
                            took, and assays a.traee onlj. 360-ft level north-east was advanoed 6 ft
                            to a distanoe 0(998 ft The flrive passed through the dyke mentioned in
                            last report into oonntry rook; the vein not yet located. 850-ft No. 2
                            winze north-east Was. sunk 9 ft, total depth 68 ft. The quartz averaged
                            10 ins in width and 14 dwts 9 grs per ton in value. 350 ft level south
                            west was driven 12 ft, total distance 346 ft The quarts averaged 26 Ids
                            wide, worth 1 dwt 7 grs per ton. 830 south- west No. 2 winze was sank 8
                            ft to a depth of 64 ft. Btill in dyke. 246-ft level north-east was
                            driven 9 ft, total length 937 ft Quarts avenged 8 ins wide, worth 2 dwts
                            14 grs per ton. In two slopes below this level the qoartz, 21 ins wide,
                            is worth 18 dwts 6 grs per ton. 245-ft level sooth-weet was advanced 8
                            ft, total length BOO ft. The quarts is 8 ins wide; no samplrs 'aken.
                            245-ft No. 8 wirza sooth-west was deepened 13 ft total depth 101 ft The
                            qearts, 6 ins wide, assayed 1 dwt 7 gn per ton. Western shaft was sank 8
                            ft total depth 948 fr. Western shaft 75-ft level south-west was advanoed
                            6 ft total distanoe 148 ft The quartz, 8 ins wide, assayed 8 dwts 22 grs
                            4 er ton.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MUSTAPHA PASHA KAMEL.</head>
                        <head>A GERMAN REPLY.</head>
                        <p>The following note from Berlin on the reoen rtisle by Mastepha Pasha
                            Kamel appears ii be "Megdebotgiche Zeitaeg.” The italicized portions of
                            the article are printed in large type in the paper :— The principal
                            organ of the Social Democratic arty has onoe more made a great "ado
                            about othing." A Berlin paper has inserted an rtiole by the Anglophobe
                            leader of the inde etadent party in Bgypt Mostapha Kama ’aeha, in whioh
                            he Complains that the Raise Vilhelm, who has of tea shown himself a warm
                            riend of Islam, did not step forward at the ight moment to secure tie
                            independence of Egypt. The Pashoda affair would have been tin ight
                            opportunity to assure himself of Fraud assistance against the English
                            protectorate designs. Mustapha Kamel himself Could have given the reply
                            to his article. Germany has never shown any desire to meddle with other
                            nation's affairs, the has alwyas been content with securing her own
                            interests. Only by the desires have we been led into the Morocco affair,
                            which has new been brought to a pacific conclusion. The Vorwaests need
                            not be afraid that in England the suspicion could arise, that Germany
                            intends to betray England owing to he France-English understanding.
                            Regarding Egypt we received a reliable state ment straight from England
                            to whioh German had no need to make any kind of protest She has never
                            intended to go against English cities, because the good administration
                            wkic iat been established in tki Nile Valley unde he English
                            protectorate is undoubtedly useful to German interests. The difficulties
                            which Ingland encountered in Egypt came mor rom other sources. Certainly
                            the appearance a Mustapha Kamel Pasha is of symptomatic im portance, as
                            was also that of Maharqjih Dhu leep Sing, who caused snob a great
                            sensation by his passionate oomplairfta against Boglam o 188'. The
                            English Press acts always as if danger meuaoed the British Empire onl
                            rom without. But here also is true the of proverb about the skeleton in
                            every cupboard.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE GRAND CADI'S RETURN.</head>
                        <p>Ghazi Mukbtar Pasha has received a cable from the Grand Cadi to the
                            effect that he is etarning shortly from Stamboul and is due to arrive
                            here next week. "AI Lewa" will be pleased to bear this new as it
                            declared that it was apprehensive this inless the Cadi returned very
                            soon the Englis Vould take the advantage of bis absenoe "t bake hay
                            while the son shines," by interfer- ing in the Mehkemehs, etc.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>DEATH OF ME. MOLTENI.</head>
                        <p>We deeply regret to record the death of Me Molteni, which took place
                            between 10 and 1 a.m. yesterday at the house of M. Goido-Moron with whom
                            the deceased was staying whan 1: fell a victim to a paralytic stroke. Me
                            Molten sho was fifty years of age, worked under Me Figari on first
                            oomiog out to Egypt and finall became Contentieox to the Ministry of Fi
                            larice ; his tenure of the post lasted for 18 tears and was only
                            terrains tod by his death His pleatant disposition, joined to a great
                            capacity for work and a profound knowledge of aw, won him the respect
                            and friendship of h xilleagoes of tbs Jar Of Cairo, and of his Italian
                            and other European colonies ; and the lumber of sympathetic messages
                            addzeased the lim during the few days of what proved to be lis last
                            illness, and the host of friends wwho ?aid visits of condolence to the
                            house where is now lies, testify to the regard felt for the
                            liatinguished lawyer. Mme Molteni, who has been staying at Milan, is
                            expeoted to arrive with her daughter lu Sunday next, and the question oi
                            the form the last rites are to take will be decided after ber arrival at
                            Cairo. The body has been em balmed in the meantime. Oar most sinoere and
                            respectful sympathy is dne to Mma Molteni and to the relatives and
                            friends of the decease- ed who have instaioed so creel a loss.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE RUSSIAN MASSACRES.</head>
                        <p>A private meeting of Prctatmtaoba was held at Alexandria yesterday
                            evening in order! bonsider the advisability of holding a gener ILLEGIBLE
                            TEXT -- MISPRINT massacres of the Jews in Russia. The Margberita
                            Society, the honorary presi- dent of which is Prince Haidar, has held a
                            extraordinary meeting, at which it was decide to give a theotrical
                            performance at Alexandra for the benefit of the victims. The Alexandria
                            Socialist Society are holding a meeting on Sunday afternoon to consider
                            the present situation in Rettia.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>CHERIF PASHA STREET.</head>
                        <p>A correspondent writes:—Can nothing t done to clear out the fruit and
                            other hawkers who infest the lane between the back of the Bourse aud
                            Pappas shop Seeing that they are all natives there should be do
                            difficulty. If those responsible for the management the Bonne were to
                            close the small door of in Cherif Pasha-street, I feel sure that they
                            would get the hearty thanks of the public and the police. The traffic
                            there is too congested. Why should the members of the Bourse not enter
                            by the main door, where then is ample room for all, carriages in front,
                            included. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NOTES FBOM THE FAYOUM.</head>
                        <head>THE WATER SUPPLY.</head>
                        <head>(From our Correspondent)</head>
                        <p>Fayoum, November 8. The Mixed Municipality is negotiatiog with an
                            artesian well oompany for the boring to the Fayoam of wells lor the
                            supply of pare potable water to the inhabitants. In case this is (band
                            to be asfoasiM*, it is intended to tostal a filter similar to the one
                            recently inaugurated at Alexandria.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FAYOUM LIGHT RAILWAY.</head>
                        <p>Mossrs. Lambert and Ralli arrived - hen to-day to inspect the light
                            railway whtoh tbsp have purohaaed on behalf of an Aoglo-Belgiaa oompany.
                            The new proprietors will shortly have to spend a good deal of money on
                            building stations, as all the existing stations are made of wood and do
                            not fulfil the requirements of a modem station. The new company will
                            also have to lay new rails. Six new engines are urgently required.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEGRO GHAFF1RS.</head>
                        <p>I am informed that it is intended to employ negro ghaffirs for Medinet el
                            Fayoum instead of the native ghaaffirs, and some Sudanese ex- soldiers
                            have arrived here lately for this purpose.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE OA98BL FOND.</head>
                        <p>The intinerant eye hospital has left Damietta for Beni Souef to work
                            there during the winter season, uner the superintendenoe of Dr.
                            MacAllan.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE NATIVE TECHNICAL SCHOOL.</head>
                        <p>Up to date the subecriptions collected for the proposed Native Technical
                            School amount to £4,800, all contributed by native notables. Resides In
                            of the Fayoum expect help from the foreign benevolent societies and hope
                            that the Bank of Bgypt and the National Bank will also give their
                            support.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A WEDDING.</head>
                        <p>Mr. Simpson, the agent of the National Bank's branch here, has left for
                            Alexandria to meet his fiancee, who is coming out from Eng- land. The
                            couple are to be married to at Mark’s Church today, and Mr. and Mrs.
                            Simpson are expected here in ten days time, after a stay at the Carlton,
                            Bulkeley.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ELECTRIC LIGHT IN CITADEL MOSQUE.</head>
                        <p>The mosque of Mohamed Aly, better known perhaps as the Citadel Mosque, ii
                            heuoeforth to be lit up with eleotrio light The trials of the; 2,000
                            lamps which have been installed in the mosque under the direction ot M.
                            Pastoar were made last night with great success, no sort of hiteh
                            occurring. The foot that the installation, has been complated in five
                            months, without any accident, reflects great credit on the con-
                            tractors, the Lebon Co., and on M. Pastour, and the Wakfo
                            Administration. The total cost of the new installation amounts to about
                            L.E. 1,750.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW LUNATIC ASYLUM.</head>
                        <p>Sir Horace Pinching, Dr. Warnock, and Mr. Courtenay Clifton started lor
                            Khanka this morning to look for available site to ease to should be
                            decided to fix upon Khanka aa the most favorable locality for the new
                            lenatie1 asylum.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE FORGED DIPLOMAS.</head>
                        <p>Professor Measure, df the University of Athens, who is accused of
                            complicity in the matter of the forged pharmacists’ diplomas, has
                            arrived at Alexandria in charge of three Greek gendarmee'from Athens,
                            and'been handed over to the looal oonaeUi authorities, who are to open
                            an enquiry into the affair.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ORIENT-PACIFIC LINE.</head>
                        <p>The latest addition to the existing accom- modation for third-claas
                            passengers by the Orient-Pacifio Lise is a special dining saloon. In the
                            routes, the fret vessel so fitted, the saloon is painted white
                            throughout, and is provided with eleotrio fans and revolving chairs. The
                            pantry is fitted with a hot-press and other modem conveniences for the
                            ex- peditions'service ot meals. The other vessels of the line are having
                            similar accommodation fitted up as they arrive in England.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SPORT AND PLAY. FOOTBALL.</head>
                        <p>E. T. C. v. D. Co. R. DUBLIN FUSILIERS. The match played yesterday at
                            Mostapha between the*. T. C. and D. Oa Royal Dublin FosOien resulted to
                            a win for the B. T. C. by two goals toons. The conditions were seme-,
                            what against good football. The sand was fast thick on parts of the
                            field; there were no touch flags, no touch line, and any quantity of
                            bricks. The heaviness of ths going seemed to affect j the Dublins more
                            than their lighter opponents, who soored twice to the first half. Both
                            goal- keepers allowed one to trickle through, the Dublins goal being
                            rooted to about ten seoonds from the kickoff in the second half. The
                            game was a good one *ILLEGIBLE TEXT* oonditions, *ILLEGIBLE TEXT*
                            *ILLEGIBLE TEXT* *ILLEGIBLE TEXT* *ILLEGIBLE TEXT*</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LETTER TO THE EDITOR</head>
                        <head>THE SUCRERIES CRASH.</head>
                        <p>To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette- Sir,—It was a great pity, that the
                            "Action- aire,’’ who wrote to you. from Veirq under the hove heading
                            recently, did not send his letter before. laameose interests ware ut
                            aUka HU "Actionaire" sent in this article before the pay- nent of the
                            Suetalasent of £64,600, U, before be 1st November, the Judge on the
                            Comerodat would most probably have opened his eyes and ordered its
                            non-paydment; thus ths unfor- anato Susserian shareholders would be the
                            richer by that amount. It must be remembered that the Societe des
                            Succeries issued mostly in France and Egypt 20,000,000 fnancs of
                            debetures only nine months back—a earn twday pmetieelly wholly ost by
                            there poos new sobssrihacs. Now if the Sugar Coorperation had not
                            received this semestrial installment, when due, immediate steps would
                            have been taken by the Corporation both against the Succeseries, which
                            is now covered by the Coaoordat, and the Dalra Banish Company, UmStei.
                            This latter company, on the 1st instant, issued a hurried notice calling
                            a general meeting for the 25th of this month for the purpose of winding
                            up, dispersing of reading up and h'speeiag of the boohs. Winding up,
                            mow, means distributing all the funds; the foounders shares alone will
                            receive one million teeriag jut of these fends hs smplos from the
                            £780,906 paid last month) which paaotfoallv reproetets me million
                            stedtog tram the Bare* Bufeh togwr Coepemtioo. % Th* oiae Gowesirewnt
                            sugar foCtjria* VMM worth, mdastrialfy.psaetfoallywrey httiewben take*
                            by the ©aim Basieh,lrerited, and than relfaama old foetodre
                            bnghteatMtqeently by the Suoreriee d'Egypte with a narrow gaagt penaonmt
                            way eonnreMd with thru, hr to Lere than £*,000.000, an mereorer today
                            worth really nothing in eoaseqaeoee of ths defiaioeay in sugar orea-u
                            defioietey atoeh will innresmngly be folt year after year, foe ■
                            cultivation ut cotton repfoeing flat of sugar. Consequently the .Dsisa
                            -Sugar -Gen*ation will, if the Socrerirego tote fiqoidatin to tee end,
                            be left wkh foetories the plant df which can bautihaed asaorep tron
                            oifly; the rdBway, inotadbg 100 renallgaage Idoemdfitoe retd 2,000
                            trucks bought with fbefoCtorfco, alone representing an available asset
                            Itu safe to aay that th* patehare prise Of £2,0O0,e00 agre*d upon in Mw
                            oontmet hr Cronier was elearly and indobittMy a frwndst the expense of
                            the Suenrito' ahatohotfen ; h fact a demand is won to be plaeed before
                            the Mixed Tribanals by the debentan hcOden fat the annulling of
                            thataodtraet df idle oftbe foetories to the Suoreries. Fnrthyrmon,this
                            same amount was likewise aotidng lees tfcn deliberetoly drained ftom the
                            Bogre Corpora- tion 60m the very day of its promotion, and paid into the
                            hands of the Dalra SanMh, limit- ed : this explains why so large a
                            bahtoos il ready for distribution on the 29 &amp; instant. Now, to 'pot
                            the matter perhaps dearer, if the letter in question had keen pubHAafi
                            earilsr aolaim would then without doubt have bean made by the Sugar
                            Corporation on the find! of the Daira Sanieh, Umfted, now read* for
                            distribution at the National Bank-The wealthy direotora Oi the
                            Corporation would to Wefy probability have been nude liable to suoh a
                            decision aswoold fix a rwmbmsemgnt to their Boglish shareholder* in the
                            oare of not having taken to time such proper steps to protect them.
                            These English shareholders of the Sugar Corporation are also as
                            interesting footer, although in the background at preedit. But they will
                            awaken no doubt—to time to bk jut too late, i.a, when their gold has all
                            bean methematioally distributed among the lesdiqg group of the founders
                            dfthe Daira Strileb, limited.—Truly yours.HIGHLY ILLEGIBLE DUE TO INK
                            SMUDGES. </p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Observer. Cairo, November 9. PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head>
                        <p>Prinoe Leopold of Battenberg and suite will oome as for as Egypt with
                            Priuoess Louise of Schlewig-HoIstein in the Orient steamer Ormuz. The
                            Princess is travelling to Burma, via Ceylon.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Lady Cromer will be "at home” during the aessjn oa Saturday afternoon,
                            from 8 o'clock.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Baron Max von Qppenheim is expeoted to return to Cairo on the 95th
                            inst</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Mr. J. Wilkie Yoang, late .noting British Vi oe Consol at
                            Alexandria,has-bsen.txansfoned from ths VionConsukte at Diakalrir to
                            that of Monastir.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The latest arrivals at the Carlton, Bulkeley. are r. and Mrs. Simspon,
                            Mr. Adameon family, Mr. Mrs. and Miss Harwell Reeves Sabbagh Bey, Miss
                            Sabbagh Mme Mostapha Bey. Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel,
                            Port Said, we notice Mr. Walker, Miss Seal Rev. and Mrs. Thornton, Mr.C.
                            J. Brown, Mr. Bruee Foot and fomily. Rev. J. J. Curling. Major Delavoye,
                            Mme Nungovials, Capt and Mr. Littleton.Mr. and Mrs. Potts, Mr. and Mra.
                            Chanter, Ut. Markhem, Mr. Mortimer.</p>
                    </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                      <div type="item">
                        <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 11. 1905.</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>MUTINY AT KRONSTADT.</head>
                        <head>RIOTERS SHOT DOWN.</head>
                        <head>A DESPERATE FIGHT.</head>
                        <p>St. Petersburg, November 10. Mutinous soldiers and sailors at Cronstadt
                            have killed ten unpopular officers. Two quad- rons of Hosaara and two
                            battaliona of the crack Preobrajenaky regiment have arrived. Kronstadt,
                            November 10. Reuter's correspondent has arrived and found that the
                            mutiny bad been quelled by the most trustworthy troops, who vigorously
                            con- trol the town. The eurvivore of the mutineers have been arrested.'
                            (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>St. Petersburg, November 10. The Tsar has proclaimed a financial mora-
                            torium. The situation at Kronstadt was at one time most serious, the
                            mutinous seamen, artillery- men, and infantry joining in wild pillage
                            and incendiarism. Eventually the fortress artillery trained tho
                            qoiokfirers on the rioters, killing and wounding a hundred in the coarse
                            of a desperate fight with the mutineers, who resist- ed stubbornly.
                            30,000 troops now ocoupy the town. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Kronstadt, November 10. The disorders were oaused by the mutiny of the
                            sailors and soldiers. The troops which came from St Petersburg pot down
                            the riot. A hundred people were killed. A state of siege has been
                            proclaimed. (Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>M. WITTE’S CABINET.</head>
                        <p>(Official). M. Ivan Shippoff is nominated Minister of Finance. M. Cutler,
                            Minister of Agriculture, M. Timiriatceff, Minister of Com- merce, M.
                            Neineaheff, at present Director of Southern Railways, Minister of
                            Communica- tions, M.' Filifosoff, Controller General of the Empire.
                            Bxoept M. Nemeschaeff all the heads of departments give to M. Witte's
                            Cabinet a strong ‘bureaucratic complexion. These ap- pointments are'a
                            further indication that the Liberals are standing aloof. General Trepofi
                            has been appointed comman- dant of the palaoo troops. Grand Duke
                            Nicholas Nioolaievicb replaces the Grand Duke Vladimir. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>FRENCH PARLIAMENT. STORMY SCENE IN CHAMBER.</head>
                        <p>Paris, November 10. The attitude of the Government towards trades uniotis
                            and cavil servants led to a orisis in the Chamber. M. Berteaux resigned
                            beoause the Government received the support of the Nationalists on that
                            question. After stormy scenes a vote of confidence in M. Rouvier was
                            adopted by 317 to 147. M. Rouvier averted defeat by appealing for snp
                            port for the oomplete separation of Chnroh and State. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Paris, November 10. Chamber ok Deputies.—M. Drnmont baa asked to
                            interpellate on the policy of the Government The interpellation was
                            adjourned- M. Berteaux, Minister of War, resigned because the majority
                            obtained on the 7th inst. was composed of Deputies of the Right. M.
                            Ronvier claimed the right to explain his policy and repeated that he
                            only wished to rely on the Republicans. The Chamber passed a vote of
                            oonfidenoe in the Premier by 317 votes against 147. (Havas)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RACING.</head>
                        <p>London, November 10. Liverpcol Automn Cup. 1. St. Wolfram ; 2. Chaucer ;
                            3. Gleramoy. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Dr. Rucker-Jenitch, German Diplomatic Agent and Consul Genera), is doe at
                            Cairo from Berlin on the 20th inst.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Dr. Isiigh Caoney left Marseilles yestordsy for Port Said by the P. and
                            O. Mooltan.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>M. Mustachi, bead cashier of the Credit Lyonnais' Alexandria branch, has
                            been ap- pointed cbir f accountant of the Credit Pranoo- Egyptian, with
                            a salary of £50 a month.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The following passengers left Cairo by the P.S. Nefertari yesterday for
                            the Nile trip:- Mr. and Mrs. Hlow, Mme A. Corsini, Mile N. Roudakoff,
                            Mr. A. Efimoff, Mr. and Mrs. Smallman, Mr. and Mrs. Broughton, Mr. and
                            Mrs. R. Nevill, Mr. and Mrs. J. M. A. Wyatt, Mr. and Mrs. A. Gilbert,
                            Mr. Ernst Haukohl, Mr. and Mrs. L. Amberton, Mr. and Mrs. Glaser, Mr. W.
                            H. Glaser, Oberbnrgermeister Becker, Mrs. and Mies Becker, Mrs. and Miss
                            Newell, Mr. A. E. Ross</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GUILDHALL SPEECH.</head>
                        <head>PREMEIR AND UNEMPLOYED</head>
                        <head>RUSSIA’S CONDITION.</head>
                        <head>THE PROSPECTS OF PEACE.</head>
                        <p>London, November 10. Mr. Balfour, speaking at the Guildhall, made a long
                            statement on the question of the unemployed. He dwelt on the difficulty
                            finding a remedy which wonld not do more harm than good. He appealed to
                            the benevolent support of the pablic, especially those present of aid
                            the Governmeut in the employment he means at its disposal. After having
                            mentioned the appearacoe Japan among the Great Powers he spoke of the
                            internal condition of Russia, and express- ed the hope that the future
                            will not be sullied by the horrible soenes whioh have marked the
                            beginning of the movement in the direction of self-government. He
                            afterwards spoke of the efforts of Great Britain in the oonne of the
                            last ten years to make war impossible, and to develop the field if
                            arbitration. He remarked that now there is no question of a frontier in
                            Afrioa or else- where which might give rise to misundersUnt ngs. He has
                            the firm hope that we shall see 10 war in the fntnre except some ruler
                            should arise to trample on the rights for bis own aggran disement. There
                            is no pro-prot of such a calalamity falling upon Europe. (Reuter)</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>The Savoy Hotel, Cairo, will be op one or the season on Monday, 27th
                            inst.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Official Expenses —The Government bi decided that there is to be a fixed
                            allowance if £25 for the journey of new officials from Europe to
                            Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Egyptian Land and General Trust.—W are authorised to state that the
                            rumour that Mr. Hooker is retiring from the Egyptian Land rod General
                            Trust is devoid of foundation</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>False Hall Marks. — Savon well-know lative jewellers at Port Said are
                            accused urging the Government's hall-mark on jewellery 'hey are also
                            aoonsed of having sold fait awellery at Cairo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>E. T. C.—Mr. Giles, superintendont of El Jastem Telegraph Company at
                            Alexandria, going on leave next week. His duties will be indertaken
                            during his absence by Mr. Davey ate snperintendont oftheoompai y at
                            Bombey</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Train Derailed —A goods train at Kent was derailed while crossing the
                            Nile bridg Both the wagons and the bridge were damage- Railway traffic
                            has been suspended, and no trains will pass across the bridge until it
                            epaired.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Eden Theatere—A gala performance will be given at the Bden Theatre this
                            evening in honor of the birthday of H.M. the King of Italy. The
                            programme includes Esmeralda I Misteri Fumo, and I Due Sordi. The
                            Ernesto Rossi dramatic society is taking part.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Coal Imports.—From the 1st January l ;he 9th November, 938,772 tons of
                            ooal we mported into Egypt Wales wot 6'0.61. Newcastle 221,413, Sootland
                            117,140, York shire 64,803, and other places 35,302 ton Daring the
                            corresponding period of last year 908,418 tons were received.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Motor Mishap.—While Yonssef Bey Army was driving a motor car along
                            Kamel-street Cairo, yesterday afternoon, the car became unmanageable and
                            dashed against the pave ment The Bey’s friend, who was with him the
                            motor, was hurled ont of the oar but did not sustain any serious
                            injuries.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Concert.— A vocal and instrumental oonoe will be given on Thursday
                            evening next Lifonti’s oonoert-room, for the benefit of M Aohille
                            Teperino, violinist, and Mme A reperino, soprano, who will be assisted
                            by Mil Mary Lopes and Betsy Cariso, both of the pianists. The programme
                            is a most attractive one me.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>Brutal Fight.--A shocking scene of brutal- ity was witnessed yesterday in
                            a fight between a coffeehouse keeper and a seaman in the Custom House
                            quarter of Alexandria. The coffee-house keeper closed with his
                            antagonist and, getting hold of his head, bit off his left ear with his
                            teeth. The police then appear on the scene and separated the
                            combatante.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>A Little Wanderer.—A poor native girl 4 yean was fonnd by thp police, six
                            days a; wandering abont in the Jewish quarter of t town. Carefol
                            enquiries have been made witl view to finding ont the child's parents,
                            bnt efforts have been in vain. In reply to qnestio the child could only
                            say that her motbe name was Patimab, bnt could not furnish any
                            indication of her abode. She has now been sent to the Malja El Abbaesi,
                            which belongs to the Mekarim B Akhlak Society.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KING’S THANKS TO THE ARMY OF OCCUPATION.</head>
                        <p>The G. 0. C. telegraphed on Thursday to bis Majesty the King as
                            follows:—"Brigadier- General Bullock and the Army of Ooonpation, Egypt,
                            send their respectful congratulations to his Majesty." The following
                            gracious reply has been reoeived:—"I am commanded to thank yon and the
                            Army of Ooonpation in Bgypt for yoor loyal telegram and congratulations.
                            — Equerry." As we have already stated in our columns, a dinner was given
                            on Thursday night by Lord Cromer at H.B.M.’§ Agenoy to the principal
                            British offioials and others now in Cairo. Among those invited were Sir
                            Vinoent Cor bett, Mr. Mach ell, Mr. Mitchell Innas, Lord Bdward Cecil
                            Sir M. Mollwraith, Mr. Webb, Mr. Perry, Capt Lyons, Mr. Dnnlop, Major
                            L'Estrange Johnston, Johnson Pasha, Dean Butoher, Mr. Alban, Mr.
                            Sdorttoo, Sir William Willcocks, Corbet Bey, Han ter Pasha, and the
                            personnel of H.B.M.'s Agency.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
                        <p>H.H. the Khedive attended a solemn reli- gious service on Thursday
                            evening in memory of Mohamed Aly. The mosque was lit up for the first
                            time by electricity, and a large and brilliant assembly took part in the
                            oeremony, including the Prinoes of the Khedivial House now in Cairo, the
                            Ministers, Ghari Ahmed Mokhtar Pasha, the Imperial Ottoman High
                            Commissioner, the principal offioials of the Khedive's cavil and
                            military hoosehold, in- olnding Ahmed Zaki Pasha, Abdel Halim Pasha A
                            Mem, the Dirootor General of the Walds Administration, the Grand Mufti,
                            and many of the ulema. On the close of the memorial service the Khediva
                            paid a short visit to the mausoleum of the great founder of his honse
                            and then returned to Koubkeh Pekoe. The Khedive arrived at Abxandria
                            from Cairo this afternoon at 2 o'clock. His High- ness, who was received
                            by H.K the Governor, proceeded to Montazsh.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE LATE ME. MOLTBNI.</head>
                        <p>We understand that the body of the late Me. Molteni has been embalmed and
                            that the funeral will take place on Monday or Tuesday next.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>NEW ASYLUM.</head>
                        <p>Sir Horace Pinohing, Dr. Warnook, and Mr. Courtenay Clifton visited
                            Khanka Unlay with a view to selecting a site for the new lunatic asylum
                            whioh is to be oo ns traded next year,and which will probably require
                            abont 200 feddans for site and grounds. We hear that it has been deoided
                            in principle to bnild the asylum at Khanka,and that a suitable site has
                            been fonnd in the hard desert lying to the east of the small town, or
                            large village, of Khan Ira, not very for from the old pilgrim road, the
                            Darb el Hag. As far as the air is oonoerned no place could be belter
                            than Khanka, bnt it remains to be seen whether the water supply is
                            entirely satisfactory as regards quality, and tests will be made to that
                            end before the Government finally oommits itself to the oonstrnotion of
                            an asylum at this spot.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ADULTERATION OF FOOD.</head>
                        <p>The Pablic Health Department intend to Uke measures against the
                            adulteration of food by Europeans. At the present time there are no
                            measures in foroe for the punishment of Europeans gnilty of snoh
                            offenoes. Natives, on the other hand, are liable to from a month to one
                            year’s imprisonment, in acoor- danoe with Article 980 of the Penal Code.
                            The Pablic Health Department will draw op a scheme for the approval of
                            the Ministry of the Interior, end if that Ministry approves it the Mixed
                            Appeal Court will be asked for its opinion on the sohome, in order that
                            it may be made applicable to Europeans as mil as to natives. It is to be
                            hoped that the Pablio Health Department will be oarafol in drawing np
                            the scheme so as to avoid the fiasco of the original Pharmacy
                            Regulations.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE BOURSE LANE.</head>
                        <p>The Alexandria Municipality is not granting any more roksas to the
                            hawkers in the lane by the Alexandria Bourse, and as the present roksas
                            fall in they are not renewed. A large number of natives without roksas
                            ply 1 their trade there at oertain times of the day. To obviate this
                            abase the Municipality some time ago gave orders to the Tarrm officials
                            to send off these people. The noose of the Municipality is that the
                            frequenters of the Bourse enoourege the traffic owing to their patronage
                            of these people.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
                        <p>The Ellerman S.S. City of Cambridge railed from Liverpool on Friday for
                            Lisbon, Gibraltar, Malta, snd Alexandra. The Moss liner Tabor sailed
                            from Malts yesterday afternoon and is doe beta on Toes day morning, with
                            passengers, m«JV. H>d general cargo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE GRAND CADI’S VOYAGE.</head>
                        <head>STILL WROPT IN MYSTERY.</head>
                        <p>The Grand Cadi Sheikh Yehya, is expected to return from Constantinople in
                            a few days' time. According to news received by the family of the Cedi
                            he is on the point of leaving the Turkish Capital and has reoeived the
                            permis- sion of the Saltan to return st once. Meantime the native Press
                            oan give no oertain informa- tion as to his errand, snd the “man in the
                            street" is lost in conjecture.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RAMLEH WATER SUPPLY.</head>
                        <p>In regard to the oompkints made that there is no water avaikble at night
                            throughout Ramleh, we understand that the oontnot for the piping for
                            oarrying filtered water to Ram- leh has been given ont, and the work
                            will in all probability begin next January. This new series of pipes
                            will only be for filtered water. The existing pipes will oonttooo to be
                            need for nnfiltered water for the gardens. Than will be an all-night
                            supply of water throngh thsTnew pipes.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ALEXANDRIA WATER SUPPLY.</head>
                        <p>To the Editor or thr Egyptian Gaxbtte Sir,—Your leading artiole on
                            Alexandria’s water supply in yesterday’s issue of the "Gssetta" was an
                            exoelknt pieoe of special pleading for that altroiitio and most phil-
                            anthropic ooncern known as the Alexandria Water. Company, limited. As a
                            matter of fact, however, there were some inaoonraoies, all of which
                            possibly nnoonscionsly were to the advantage of the oompany. In the
                            first place, I should be obliged if you will permit me to point oat that
                            at the time the Alexandria Municipality first attempted to exercise come
                            supervision over the company, it was discover- ed that the ktter were
                            charging the doable of what they were legally entitled to for a girbeh
                            of water. The result was that the poor native who took hk water from the
                            "homes fontainee" bad to pay mnob more than his more fortonste brethren,
                            who oonld afford to subscribe for a permanent supply of water. The
                            Municipality pot a stop to this extortion in the interests of the
                            public. The question of the meters and the monthly subscription were
                            gone into soon sfterwards,and the tariff, whioh is still in vigoor for
                            sn un- limited supply of water, was then arranged. This reform was duo
                            to the Municipality. There is an omission in the article of the name of
                            Amin I aaha Fikry, one of the best Governors Alexandria ever bad, who,
                            during the short time he was Governor, contributed greatly to the work
                            of coming to an agreement with the oompany. The original oontnot was
                            that the Municipality should pay three quarters and the oompany one
                            quarter, with a maximum of LE 10,000: Subsequently the Municipality
                            arranged that they should give a lump sum of LE. 60,00 and that the
                            company should provide the balance. The construction of the filters has
                            been admirably carried out, and this balance paid by the company has
                            exceeded to a certain extent the LB 10,000 calculated upon.—Truly,
                            yours. Alexandrian. Alexaadria, November 10.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>]ALEXANDRIA'S NEW THEATRE.</head>
                        <p>One of the questions, whioh will have to be settled soon, ia that of the
                            new theatre at Alexandria whioh is to take the plaoe of the Zinnia,
                            which has only a short time to ran before its demolition. The idea
                            prevailing among the leading lights of the Alexandria pkygoen is that
                            tha Municipality should give the site for a new theatre free, and that
                            it should be bnilt by looal capitalists and beoome the property of the
                            Maniaq>*lity after the capital has been amortised. Great divergenoy of
                            opinion exists, firstly, as to what site should be asked for, and
                            second, ly, what sum should be spent on the bnilding. Some ardent
                            pttronc of tha drama want a bnilding of the paktial character of the
                            Paris Grand Opera, while others think £40,CC0 to £60,000 wonld be quite
                            sufficient to spend on saoh a bnilding. Owing to these conflicting
                            opinions, to far no application has been to the Municipality, which is,
                            we believe, quite disposed to favorably oonsider any reasonable
                            proposals that may be made.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>GREEK NATIONALITY.</head>
                        <p>The Greek and Bgyptkn Governments intend to examine the various
                            disunities, which are from time to tiipe raised here by the local
                            anthorities end tha Greek consulate authorities, on the subject of the
                            nationality of Greeks resident in Egypt.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>SYRIAN STUDENTS AT AL-AZHAR.</head>
                        <p>Owing to the death of their Sheikh, the late Grand Mufti Bl B.M, the
                            Syrian students of Al Atbar have submitted a petition to both the
                            Khedive and the president of Al-Axbar Uni- versity asking that Sheikh
                            Yabza Bl Khalili be appointed as their sheikh. Other ulema of Al-Ashrt
                            have offered themselves as candidates for the position, hot the'Syrian
                            Mnjawireen will acoapt nobody exoept Sheikh Yabxa.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>ARISTON AERATED WATERS Guarenteed Distilled.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>RIFLE BRIGADE’S DEPARTURE EMBARKATION FOR BOMBAY.</head>
                        <p>The 9nd Battalion Rifle Brigade will embark at Sues for India on the 22nd
                            inst in the transport Plasty. His troops will leave Gain main station by
                            special train at 6.80 p.m. on the 21st inst, arriving at Snet abont 1.80
                            a.m. tha following morning. They will remain in the train until daylight
                            when they will detrain and embark on the transport The detachment 2nd
                            Battalion Royal Berks. Regiment with the married families, will proceed
                            from Sidi Gaber, Alexandria, by special train at 9.60 a.m. on the 99nd
                            inst, to Cairo, arriving at 1.40.. They will be quartered at the Citadel
                            on arrival. An advauoe party, consisting of 1 offiosr and 8 N.C.O.’s and
                            men, will leave Sidi Gaber by the 7 am. train on the 18th inst for
                            Cairo, for the porpoee of taking over the bemoka, eta, from the Rifle
                            Brigade. His General Officer Commanding proposes holding a Staff ride on
                            December 8. Lient.-Col A. M. MantoU, C.R.B. to Egypt came down to
                            Alexandria from Cairo today.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>LAND BANK OF EGYPT.</head>
                        <p>The following extract from the report of the Land Bank of Egypt presented
                            at the extra- ordinary general meeting held on the 4th tost, will be of
                            interest It is taken from theaooonntfc np to 31st October , - 1. Pitta
                            hypotbfoairea amor- tissables par annnitfo. . LK 1.688.787178 9. Prtt
                            hypothecates en oomptooonnnt.......... „ 76.679 917 8. Avanoes anx
                            proprtotai- res onltivatenra...... „ 89.176 616 4. lmmenbles Zogheb et
                            Antoniadia (destines kk construction d'nn edifice poarkBanqoo...........
                            „ 94 616 894 LK 1.898.953 064 Capital et rfsnve.....LK 683 819 600
                            Obligation 6mitea (net prodnit)......... 846 989 068 LK 1.880.061568</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>A GLOBE TROTTER AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
                        <p>An interesting visitor to Alexandria has arrived to the person of M.
                            Joseph Gerard, a Frenchman, who celebrates his 84th birthday today, and
                            who started from Bros roll on the 1st March, 1901, on a walking tonr
                            round the world for a wager. Gerard was to have completed his journey to
                            three yean, bnt be was stricken down with fever in Shanghai and had
                            consequently to return to Franoe to reonperate. and tiros lost the bet.
                            He it, however, sn indefatigable traveller, and was not long to Franoe
                            before he staited on his peregrinations again, so that he has been globe
                            trotting more or lees for the last 4 1/2 years, and has more than
                            oomp'eted the tons of the world. The countries ha has visited on his
                            travels are Bulgaria, Germany, Denma k, Norway, Swoden, Finland, Russia,
                            Siberia, Korea, Japan, Chins, Cochin China, India, Franoe, Spain,
                            Portugal England, Sootland, Ireknd, Canada, United States, Mexioo, Cuba.
                            From Cuba he returned to Borope, visiting Luxemburg, Switzerland, Italy,
                            Spain again, Moroooo, Algeria, Toni, Tripoli Malta, and on to
                            Alexandria, where he gives a Jeoture this evening describing his
                            experiences, at the Cerole de 1’Union Artisti- que Francaise, S.
                            Stambonl-street, at 8.00 p.m. M. Gerard left Brunets without a penny in
                            hk pocket and k solely dependent on the aesiftaaoe which be U Lhk to
                            obtain through describing hk experiences to the various places be
                            visits. He will particularly treat the even- ing of Russia, Siberia, and
                            Japan, on which the eyes of the world have been fixed for some time
                            past.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>ANOTHER LANGUAGE</head>
                        <p>To THi Editor or thx Egyptian Gaottk. Sir,—Within the last few years, I
                            note with pleasure the increasing nse of the Ktglish kngusge in Egypt I
                            have just been (coking at a new periodioel entitled "The Oriental
                            Truth,” whioh, the editoT says, will ha ran entirely on American lines,
                            and of which the first part k written in what appean at first wight to
                            he English. I do not find any fault with the editor's ideas, and some of
                            the articles are interesting and cheerful hat many of the words he usee
                            on every page are so utterly st variance with three to be found to any
                            English dictionary, that I am led to suppose that the language as well
                            as the lines on whioh the paper is to be run is American. I regret to
                            say that I have but a very alight acquaintance with current American
                            periodics literature, but if this is a specimen of it, our langnage must
                            be fast approaching a line of oleavage ; some such nnoomfortable
                            position as that of Sweden snd Norway. If this fa the care, I wish to
                            ray that the experience of many years in thk oopntry leads me fo think
                            that one of the hardens onder which it kbours k doe to the excessive
                            num- ber of languages used here, and I should like to ask the editor of
                            "The Oriental Truth" to pause and reflect for a little while before he
                            inflicts another on a long-suffering, hot already over-laden
                            community.—I am, etc, Observer Alexandria, 10 Nov.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE SAHARAN OCEAN </head>
                        <head>AN IMPORTANT SCHEME</head>
                        <p>It wonld not.be a very, difficult undertaking to oonvert the great
                            depression of the Sahara into an inland ocean, as once it. was. Such a
                            scheme is already being mooted, and talk is sometimes the prelude to
                            action. It is reckoned that the depression comes up nearest to the sea
                            midway between the twentieth and thirti- eth parallels of latitude on
                            the Atlantic tide, and that a canal sixty miles in length would flood
                            the whole interior with salt water. The result would be both good, and
                            bad. It wonld open op an immense region to shipping communication, and
                            there would be many large islands still above wator-level. It would also
                            obliterate vast realms of barbarism. On the other hand, the vineyards of
                            Southern Europe, which depend much on the hot, dry winds from the
                            African desert, would suffer severely, many even to destruction.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE JEWISH MASSACRES.</head>
                        <p>A meeting of the leading members of the Jewish colony at Cairo took place
                            yesterday evening, to considsr what steps should be taken in regard to
                            the relief of their brethren who havecoffered by the massacres in
                            Russia.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>AMERICAN COTTON MARKET.</head>
                        <p>Messrs. Colltoge Brothers, of Liverpool, cable as follows this morning:-
                            Barren may cause withdrawal of some sup- port given to the market but
                            any spot decline of moment improbable. We think present prices safe ;
                            even if the market should go temporarily lower. Do not be influenced by
                            the reaction ; with 70% of the crop picked condition report
                            valueless.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>THE DAM'S WATER POWER.</head>
                        <p>A curious photograph has been sent home by the engineers of Meseit. John
                            Aird to illustrate the surprising liftirgpower of flowing water, as
                            illustrated by the efffete of water pouring from the aluices of the Nile
                            Dam at Arsonan. The dam sometimes holds up a height of 60ft. of water,
                            but the aluices are of different heights, and give the stream that pours
                            through them a head of no more than 3fft and therefore a velocity of
                            little toon than 30fL a second. Yet the discharge has been able to lift
                            a blook of quarts 17ft -by 12ft. by 7 ft., and weighing approximately 60
                            tone, and fling it took, head over heels, as it Were, on to the masonry
                            of the dam. Such occur- rences are not rare-on sea-walk, where there :
                            is an impact of storm-driven waves. At Wick Harbour, for example, to
                            1872 a monolith weighing 1,870 tons was lilted fay the wave* and later,
                            when thk had been replaced by one of 9,610 tone, the heavier stood was
                            also washed- away. But at Assouan the impelling force was only running
                            water.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>VISITORS’ LIST.</head>
                        <head>HOTEL DU Nil CAIRO.</head>
                        <p>Mr. Manson, Mr. Walton, Locdan ; Herr A. Baris ban, Niurnberg; Carl Kuhne
                            Tier Win. Herr Adolf Fitierle, GmUod; Mr. A lerabaeh. Paris; Herr Conrad
                            Tiring. Herr Ferd. Sokweiss- thal, Vienna; Herr Alfred Leo, Berlin; Harr
                            K Goldstein, Herr R. Pleirohmsnn, Vienna; Herr W. Bielefeld, Herr rtd
                            Fran Bomb, Herr G. Stephan; Herr Frits Giese, Berlin ; Stoohan Bey,
                            Alexandria ; Mr. Bdward R, Ayrton, London; Dr. Albreoht Penck Hofaat,
                            Mr. Joseph Kummer, Vienna; Mr. and Fran Eleoler, Ziirich ; Mr. M.
                            Hoffmann, Berlih; Mr. Ed. Questor, Cologne ; Mr. Bichard Blaw, Vienna ;
                            Mr. and Frau H. Vogel, Frankfort; . Sig.A.Fratti,Milan; HrrrH.Abel
                            Haasboig; - Sig. K Pratti, Triaete; Hen R. Hader,Vienna; Hen Paul Spohr,
                            Germany ; Mr. Gins Alex- andria ; Mr. F. Penny, Frankfort, Herr C.
                            Wuttke, Mon;oh ; Hen Rodolf Katsoher, I Alexandria ; Mr. Andi Dolfini,
                            Park ; 8ig. Ginseppe Franoo, Genos, Hen B. Brod,Vienna, Hen F:an* David,
                            Bonsdorf ; Hen Fez. Urbalrobeek, Vienna Meat re: M. and G. Sobons,
                            Maastricht; Messrs.- Consegraohi and I von Oppen, Maastricht, Hen K
                            Koimgiola, Vienna ; Mr. John K Hops, London; . Hon Bdmond Pogsonik,
                            Hofta ; Hen Otto . 8pi«xer, Vienna; Sig. Luigi Trjanl Milan ; Hen
                            Hermann Engel, Vienna ; Hen Otttoar 8oergel, Gmnnd; M. Henri Castvta,
                            Bordeaux,- Hen Theodor Boss, Paris ; Mr. David B. Reid, Scotland ; Mr.
                            M. Ramsey, Port 8aid ; Hen Alfred Posner, Belfast; Hen Emil Sohmidt,
                            Berlin ; Herr Emil Kutsohbaob,. Bucharest; Hen G. Wohlforth, Leipelg ;
                            Hen Morits Fisohos, Vienna ; Hen Peter KCnig, Pinaa- sens; Hen and Fran
                            Kortenhaas, Alexandria; Herr H- Sohoen, Kaiscralantorn; Hen A: Wit-
                            lander, Stockholm ; Hen Dr. Horevits, Herr Dr. Kern, Harr H. Zibringer,
                            Berfia ; Mies Griffith, London.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <head>Angle-Aineriean Nile Steamers</head>
                        <head>HOTEL COMPANYM</head>
                        <p>RIVER TRANSPORT OF GOODS BETWEEN ALEXANDRIA AND CAIRO THREE SAILINGS
                            A-WEEK AGENTS OF ALEXANDRIA</p>
                    </div>
                    <div type="item">
                        <p>BECK &amp; CO'S PILSNER BEER BREMEN FEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR
                            QUALITY ILEGIBLE TEXT*****</p>
                    </div>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>

