<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Olivia Evanoff</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-10-01</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-11-06</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, Monday,November 6, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, NOVEMBER 6 190S.</head>
<head>RUSSIAN HORRORS
JEWS BUTCHERED </head> 
<head>REVOLTNG BARBARITES.
FINLAND WINS.</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, November 4.
The Amnesty is of the widest description,
Applying especially- to political offenders.
There are no signs of Russia becoming
quieter. Great disturbances and bloodshed are
reported daily from fresh places.
The latest reports show that the horrors at
Odessa were not exaggerated. Hooligans aided
by the police slaughtered whole families of
Jews, with inconceivable brutality. It is impos-
sible to estimate the number of the killed, but
there ate at present 5,500 wounded in. the
hospitals. 300 corpses have already been
buried.	(Reuter)</p>
<head> London, November 4.</head>
<p>The “Times" learn from.St. Petersburg
that Finland has won a manifesto of freedom,
embodying all the popular demands, which
was submitted for the Imperial signature yes-
terday evening.	(Reuter)</p>
<head>St. Petersburg,' November 4. </head>
<p>Warships have left Reval for Helsinugfors as
a result of the continuance of alarming reports.
In reply to a representation from the British
Government regarding the safety of British
subjects, especially in the south, the Embassy
has also informed that stringent orders have
been sent to Odessa and elsewhere to restore
order. The other Embassies have made similar
representations.	(Reuter) </p>
 <head>A Petersburg, November 5.</head>
<p>The railway strike in Russia is ending. M.
Witte has informed the strikers that their
demands have been granted. The police at
Odessa have tardily taken measures to put an
end to the slaughter of the Jews.
Bloodshed continues elsewhere. A hundred
were killed and six hundred wounded at
Minsk.
The resignation of the' Minister of the
Interior, M. Bouliguine, has been accepted.
A manifesto of the Tsar convokes the
Finnish diet for the 28th December, in view of
the revision of electoral representation. It
abolishes the Dictatorship. Meanwhile four
warships, convoying ten thousand troops, have
anchored at Helsiugfurs.	,
A great Socialist demonstration which had
been, arranged for to-day has been abandoned
owing to the stem threat of General Trepoff to
repress disturbances rigorously.
An official communication declares that it
is indispensable that all classes should refrain
from mutual friction in order to avoid'disturb-
ances, which the Government must repress for
the protection of Russian citizens without
distinction.	(Reuter) </p>
                <head>Odessa, November 5.</head>
<p>Eight factories have been wrecked in the
vicinity.
The massacres were accompanied by the
most revolting barbarities ; eyes were gouged
out, tongues were torn ont with pincers, and
n valids were burned alive.	(Reuter) </p>
                <head>St. Petersburg, November 4.</head>
<p>Quiet prevailed to-day throughout Russia.
The Tsar will grant the demands of Finland.
(Hovas)</p>
                <head>St. Petersburg, November 5.</head>
<p>The Minister Bouliguine has resigned. (H.)
Odessa, November 5.
A riot has broken out. 300 people have been
killed and 3,000 injured.	(Havas) </p>
                <head>Tomsk, November 5.</head>
<p>The revolutionaries have set fire to a build-
ing in which the reactionaries had taken refuge,
massacring those who attempted to escape.
(Hovas)</p>
<head>WEI-HEI-WEI NOT TO BE
ABANDONED.
London, November 5.</head>
<p>The "Observer" states that Great Britain
does not intend to abandon Wei-hei-wei. (It) </p>
<head>THE ROYAL TOUR
    Aden, November 4.</head>
<p>The Renows left this afternoon. (Reuter) </p>
<head>SIR TREVOR PLOWDEN DEAD.
    London, November 5.</head>
<p>Sir Trevor Plowden is dead. (Reuter) </p>
<head>CELEBRATING INSPRUCK.
    Vienna, November 4.</head>
<p>Brawls took place between German and
Italian students on tbe occasion of the anni-
versary of the Inspruck incidents. (Havas) </p>
<head>M'DEROULEDE IN PARIS.
    Paris, Novrmber 5. </head>
<p>M. Deroulede has arrived. He was oheered
(Hovas)</p>
<head>POWERS AND CRETE.
INSURGENTS ACCEPT TEEMS.
Canea, November 4.</head>
<p>The Cretan insurgents have agreed to accept
tbe terms offered them by the Powers, provided
that the surrender of their arms be arranged
in a manner that will spare their susceptibilities. 
(Reuter) </p>
<head>PRINCE LOUIS OF BATTENBERG.
RECEPTION AT WASHINGTON.
Washington, November 4.</head>
<p>Prince Louis of Batteuberg and tbe officers
of tbe British aquadrou are visiting this city
for three days.
They have been received by President
Roosevelt at White House with great ceremony
and cordiality. Prince Louis of Battenberg
presented a personal message from the King.
(Reuter) </p>
                <head>Washington, November 5.</head>
<p>Prince Louis of Battenberg has been enter-
tained at a banquet by President Roosevelt.
(Reuter)</p>
<head>GERMANY AND AMERICA.
TREATY OF COMMERCE.
Washington, Novomber 5.</head>
<p>Negotiations for a Germano-American treaty
of commerce have been opened.	{Reuter) </p>
<head> GERMANY AND ABYSSINIA.
APPOINTMENT OF MINISTER
Berlin, November 5.</head>
<p>It is stated here that Germany intends to
appoint a Minister in Abyssinia. (Reuter)</p>
                <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
<p>Um Rus Gold Mines of Egypt.— This com-
pany has sold tbo September gold for £1,552.
(Mill ran 19 days.)</p>
<p>Execution. — Beyioumi Bedawi, who was
sentenced to death for murder, was executed
this morning in Tantah prison.
Military Camp. — The 2nd Company of
Royal Engineers will move into camp on the
Polygon. Abbassieh, on the 13tn inst., for field
works and musketry.</p>
<p>Theft in a Gouvernorat.— A sum of about
L.E. 20 has been stolen from a safe in tbe
private enquiry department at the Cairo
Gouvernorat. The safe contained L.E. 66.</p>
<p>The “Egyptian Graphic."—We hear that
our contemporary the "Egyptian Graphic" will
soon reappear for the season of 1905-06 under
the editorship of Mr. William Houghton.</p>
<p>New Judges.—Tbe Egyptian Government
is negotiating with the French and Greek
Governments for the appointment of two
Mixed Court judges in place of Judges Ruhland
aud Boaphidis.</p>
<p> Egyptian Land & General Trust.—Mr.
John Chini, of the firm of Messrs. P. Glyme-
nopoulos & Co., has been appointed the agent
of the Egyptian Land & General Trust, Limit-
ed, in Alexandria.</p>
<p>Seven at a Birth.—A native contemporary
states that a poor woman of Damanhour has
given birth to seven children, four males and
three lerooles. The mother is doing well, but
two of tbe boys and two of the girls died
shortly after birth.</p>
<p>Thefts at Alexandria —A local contem-
porary persists in denying the existence of a
band of robbers at Alexandria, who have
recently committed a number of thefts. The
statement can be proved by repairing to tbe
scene of their operations in Sisters-street and
at the establishment of the Sisters of St.
Vincent de Paul.</p>
<p>Woman Strangled.—A native woman, 35
years of age, of the name of Aysha and belong-
ing to Jerza village, has been found dead in
the Saida Zeynab quarter of Cairo with a
handkerchief bound tightly round her neck.
The medical examina ion shows that the poor
woman was strangled, and that the crime
occurred only a few hours before its discovery.</p>
<p>Y.W.C.A., Cairo.—By kind permission of
H.R.H. the Duchess of Connanght, in remem-
brance of her visit to the home last spring,
the name “Connaught House" will now be
incorporated with that of Young Women’s
Christian Association. We are asked to state
this to correct tbe impression that tbe name
of tbe institution has been changed. Miss
Maclnnes, tbe acting president, returned to
Cairo last month.</p>
<head>MINISTRY OF FINANCE.
A SECOND UNDER SECRETARY
OF STATE.</head>
<p>Owing to tho greatly increased pressure of
work at the Ministry of Finanoe, it has been
decided to appoint anothor Under-Secretary
of State, and Lord Edward Cecil Pasha has
been selected to fill the new post. Great sa-
tisfaction is expressed both in British and
native circles at his appointment.
During his career in the Sudan servioe
Lord Edward Cecil has displayed in a marked
degreo the qualities of a good administrator.
He is thirty-eight, a brilliant soldier, and a
man of business as well as of affairs. The be-
sieged in Mafeking owe him a large debt.
They hod pretty bad times there long before
the siege was over, but had it not been for
Lord Edward Cecil they would have starved
long before relief came. He took upon himself
the responsibility of providing the town with
just four times the quantity of food the military
authorities found necessary, and when the
contractors hesitated to exeoote a seven
thousand pound order on the young major’s
sole responsibility, Lord Edward promptly
got Baden-Powell to back the bilL. But
Muafeking was only one incident in his
career. He has served in Egypt several times,
accompanied the famous special mission to
King Menelik ot Abyssinis, gained two medals
for his services with the Dougoia Expedition,
earned more fame at Atbara, and added to it
at Omdurman the D. S. O. and two clasps. The
mission to Menelik, by the way, nearly put an
end to Lord Edward’s career. While the party
was on its way uue of the camels fell down a
deep ravine, aud Lord Edward and Captain
Swayne clambered down a rope of puggarees
with the idea of rescuing the animal. They
could not roach the camel, however, and one
of the Abyssinians went down. A moment
later two shots rang out—one ot them came
pretty near to hitting Sir Rennell Rodd—-and
the native caino up hand over hand in doable-
quick time. He had found two lions devour-
ing tbe camel! Lord Edward, who is, of course,
a younger brother of tbe Marquess of Salis-
bury, married in 1894 Miss Violet Maxse,
daughter of tbe late Admiral Maxse, and
sister to the editor of the “National Review."
As a girl, Lady Edward Cecil sat for Millais'
"Puss in Boots,” and during the Boer war she
did splendid work among the sick and
wounded. </p>
                <head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
<p>The Khedive will grant an audience to the
newly-appointed Russian Consul-General in
Cairo next Thursday afternoon, when the Con-
sul will submit his credentials to his Highness.</p>
                <head>GERMAN CONSULATE.</head>
<p>Baron von Humboldt-Dachroeden, German
Consulat Alexandria, has been appointed Consul-
General at Capetown. He is expected at Alex-
andria next week, on his return from leave,
and will take up his new post in the beginning
of December.</p>
                <head>MUNICIPAL ELECTIONS.</head>
<p>A preliminary meeting was held yesterday at
the Alexandria Gonvernorat to consider the
new electoral list for tbe forthcoming munici-
pal elections, which will be held in March next.<p>
    <head>AGRICULTURAL BANK OF EGYPT.</head>
<p>The Committee of the London Stock Ex-
change has fixed Wednesday, Nov. 15, as a
special settling day in Agricultural Bank of
Egypt—Scrip certificates to bearer, fully paid,
for a further issue of 248,000 Ordinary shares
of £5 each. (Nos. 375,001 to 623,000), and
has ordered the same security to be quoted
in the offioial list. </p>
<head>AMERICAN INSURANCE SCANDALS.</head>
<p>Our recent article on the American insurance
scandals has been interpreted by some persons
here, whose knowledge of English is limited,
as reflecting on the agents in Egypt of the
companies concerned. But the idea that the
article had any reference to anyone in Egypt
is of coarse quite absurd, and it will not bear
that interpretation for a moment to anyone
conversant with the English language.</p>
    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
<p>The Messageries S.S. Dumbea, from Mar-
seilles, passed the Straits of Messina on Satur-
day and is due at Alexandria to-morrow.
The Moss liner Seti arrived on Saturday
morning from Liverpool, via Gibraltar and
Malta, with passengers, mails, and general
cargo.
The Ellerman S.S. Andalusian sailed fran
Malta ou Saturday afternoon and is due here
on Tuesday night with general cargo.
The S.S City of Dundee (Westcott and
Laurence Line) left Malta on Saturday night
and is due here on Wednesday, with general
cargo from London and coal from Newcastle.</p>
<item>ARISTON AERATED WATERS
Guarenteed Distilled. 
ALEXANDRIA:
F. Rue de la Poste.</item>
<head>THE LATE GRAND MDFTI.
    SUCCESSOR APPOINTED.</head>
<p>The funeral of the late Grand Mufti, Sheikh
Mohamed Abd El Kader El Rafei, took place
early on Saturday afternoon. The Prime Min-
ister, Mustapha Pasha Fehmy, Fakhry Pasha,
Fuad Pasha, tbe chiefs of the ulema, and the
principal dignitaries of the University of Al
Azhar, Mr. Moberly, acting Commandant of
the Cairo Police, and a great number of
notables and sheikhs were present. The fu-
neral service was bald at the Mosque of the Al
Azhar University, after which the foneral
cortege moved on to the cemetery at El Me-
gaonerin, where the interment took place.
The late  Grand Mufti appears to have suc-
cumbed to heart failure while driving from the
house of H. E. Boutros Pasha Ghali to that
of H.E. Ahmed Pasha Mazloum to con-
clude a series ot official visits which seem to
have proved too fatiguing for his years. His
friends state that he showed no signs of illness
when leaving his house in the late afternoon.
A successor to the Grand Mufti has already
been found in Sheikh Bakri Ashour, the acting
Grand Cadi, who has aocepted the appointment.
Sheikh Bakri is reputed to be a learned theo-
logian and bears a high personal character.<p>
<head>FLOATING DOCK TO PASS
    THROUGH CANAL.</head>
<p>The Navy Department at Washington is
negotiating for the passage through the Suez
Canal of three colliers and also a large steel
floating drydock which will be towed to tbe
station of Olongapo, in the Philippines.
No anxiety is expressed over the voyage,
which will be notable in many respects. The
dock will be the largest structure ever to pass
through the Suez CanaL
It is estimated that the cost of taking the
dock to Olongapo will be £250,000.</p>
    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
<p>The Hon. Mr. Iddings, American Diplomatic
Agent and Consul-General at Cairo, arrives at
Alexandria this afternoon by the North
German Lloyd S.S. Schleswig.</p>
<p>Archbishop Briante and the Marquis Soragna
were among the passengers who arrived
yesterday by the Italian mail steamer.</p>
<p>The new Under Seoietary of State for War
is H. E. Ismail Sirhauk Pasha.</p>
<p>Sir Thomas Sutherland, Vice President of
the Suez Canal Co., is giving a dinner to his
brother members of ths British section of the
board of directors, at the Elysee Palace Hotel
London, on the 15th inst.</p>
<p>Lews Mansfield Pasha, Commandant of the
Cairo City Police, arrived to-day by the
Austrian Lloyd steamer.</p>
<p>Admiral Sir Massie Blomfield, K.C.M.G.
has arrived at Cairo.</p> 
<p>Chitty Bey has arrived at Cairo from
Alexandria.</p>
<p>Kaimakam Macaulay Bey left Cairo for
Khartoum on Saturday night by the sleeping
car train to Loxor.</p>
<p>We understand that Mrs. Sydney Farrar is
rather indisposed, and is coming to Egypt
shortly. It is hoped that the mild climate of
the Nile Valley will greatly benefit her health.</p>
<p>Mr. and Mrs. R. J. Moss and Miss Moss
arrived here to-day by the Austrian Lloyd
S.S. Cleopatra.</p>
<p>Mr. Reeves is expected at the Carlton early
next week.</p>
<p>Lieut. R. J. Cooke, Inspector of Army
Schools, leaves Port Said for Malta on the
9th inst. by the S.S. City of Corinth, on the
conclusion of his inspection in Egypt.</p>
<p>Naguib Bay Chikour, chief signalling en-
gineer of the Egyptian Railway Administra-
tion, has retired with an indemnity of L.E
1,060.</p>
<p>Among the visitors now staying at the
Carlton Hotel, Bulkeley, are Mr. J.C. Clarke
Mr. B. Nathan, Mr. Ch. Christian, Mr. F
Nathan, England, Miss Mary B. Moffat,U.S.A.
Miss F. Clarke, U.S.A., Mr. C.H. Bernhard
France, Mr. B. Gorra, Syria, Dr. S. Schmeil
Cairo, Mr. A. Mosseri and family, Cairo Mrs.
Bogdadli and family, Cairo, and Mr. E. L
Edgar, England.</p>
<p>Among the latest arrivals at tbe Eastern
Exchange Hotel, Port Said, are Mr. C. R.
Muratori. Mr. A. Macaulay, Mr. A. Benzinra
Capt Moberly, Mr. P. Cowlas, Mrs. E Macau
lay, Mr. and Mrs. M. Summers, Mrs. H
Mayne, Dr. E. H. Ross, Mr. Batler. Mrs. C.E
Malby, Mr. A. Nathan, Mr. P. Beohara, Mr.
and Mrs. A. Brown, Mr. James F. Waterlow
M.C B.A., Mr. G. Geoman, Capt. Byarke, Mr.
RH. Parker, Mr. R. W. Wright Henderson
Dr. and Mrs W.A. Hayes, Mr. and Mrs. MoKay.</p>
<head>CHRYSANTHEMUM. SHOWS.
SUCCESSFUL EXHIBITS AT
ALEXANDRIA.</head>
<p>The eighth of the Alexandria Horticultural
Society’s Chrysanthemum Shows was held in
the San Stefano Casino on Saturday and
Sunday last. It was the largest yet held here,
and was remarkable for the number of novel
exhibits it contained, this, evidently, being
the result of according a oertain number of
points in tho programme for new varieties not
hitherto exhibited in Egypt. Every year brings
one or two new exhibitors who show extra-
ordinarily good blossoms. Mr. Rolo surprised
the public last year by his beautiful cut flowers a
in boxes, and this year Madame Salvago and
Yehia Bey, who never exhibited before, were
able to carry off prizes in every class for which ,
they (competed. The group of Mme Salvago,
though small, was quite charming, and the
fine heads of flowers that Yehia Bey produced
were as good as any that have been seen at
San Stefano. But to those who really under-
stand chrysanthemums and their culture, the
great feature of the show was undoubtedly
the mass of pot plants in the centre of Mr.
Zervndachi’s gronp, which had been so culti-
vated that while the plant remained small,
the bloom was as large as if the roots had not
been touohed.
The ball-room of the Casino was completely
filled by four large groups, three of which were
for competition, while the fourth was the
exhibit of the Municipality, which never com-
petes. All showed great taste in arrangement,
and the harmony in colour in each was well
thought out. The difficulty consequently lay in
judging the strength of the plant and in the
value of the new importations into Egypt
Perhaps among all the exhibitors the greatest
stride has been made by the Municipality; the
difference in the grouping of their plants was
greatly noticeable. The Municipality is now
taking great interest in the culture of flowers.
The reading-room was also quite full of
plants; the blossoms were enormous and
although most of the prizes seemed to go
to three or four (competitors, yet in every class
there was much competition. Cultivation of the
chrysanthemum has become so general in
Alexandria, that it almost seems as if the
committee might venture to take a further
step, and offer prizes for special classes suoh as
Pompou, Incurves, etc. We must not omit to
mention the boxes of well-grown flowers staged
by General Bullock, nor the interesting exhibit
of Mrs. Crafton, consisting of the leaf, flower,
and fruit of the Philodendron pertusum. It is
not generally known that the fruit, which
tastes like pineapple, takes 18 months to ripen.
There was a mass of vases arranged by
natives, most of them well thought oat, though
perhaps the harmony of colour which generally
pleases the Earopean eye, was somewhat
wanting. Asa trial the oommittee offered prizes
for collections of vegetables, salad, and fruit,
without speoifiying too varieties. These exhibits
were a success, and showed the pnblic several
vegetables which they probably had no idea
were at the present time to be obtained in the
market. We noticed, for instance, peas, figs,
and strawberry grapes.
The attendance on the opening day showed
a marked increase on former years, while on
Sunday the attraction of the Armenian bend
helped to swell the large number who were
drawn to the show.
The following are the names of the judges :—
Miss Borchgrevink, Mrs. Crafton, Messrs.
Ebell, Monfront, H Seffer, and Tramontins.</p>
<head>PRIZE LIST.
    CHRYSANTHEMUMS.</head>
<p>Pot Plants.
1. Gronp of at least 200 plants.—Silver
gilt medal, Mr. E. C. Zervudachi; silver
medal, Prince Omar Toussoun ; bronze medal,
Mme Charlotte Debbane.
2. Group of from 75 to 100 plants.—1. Mme
- Salvago ; 2. Judge S-ndars.
3.	18 plants, cultivated for large flowers ;
 6 varieties at least—1. Yehia Bey ; 2. Mr.
Jacques Rolo.
4.	6 plants, cultivated for large flowers.—
No entry.
5.	6 plants, each at least 15 flowers.—1. Mr.
E. C. Zervudachi; 2. Yehia Bey.
6.	7, and 8.—No entry.
Cut Flowers.
9. 24 Blooms, 12 varieties at least.—Silver
medal, Prince Omar Toussoan ; bronze medal,
Mr. E. C. Zervudachi.
10. 12 Blooms, Mixed.—1. Yehia Bay; 2.
Prince Omar Toussoun.
11. 12 Blooms, one colour.—1. Prinoe Tous-
soun ; 2. Mme Salvago.
12. 6 Blooms, mixed.—1. Yehia Bey; 2.
Prinoe Omar Toussoun.
13. 6 Blooms, one colour.—1. Prince Omar
Toussoun ; 2. Yehia Bey.
14, 15, and 16.—No entry.
Floral Decorations,
17, 18, and 19.—No entry.
20. 1. Abdou Hassan ; equal 2. Ibrahim
Amer aod Shaban Ahmed.
VEGETABLES AND FRUIT.
21. 1. Ahmed Mohamed ; 2. Ali Said ; 3.
Haffez Soliman.
22. 1. Daddour Mohamed ; 2. Ahmed Mo-
hamed.
23. Salad.—1. Ali Said; 2. Daddour Moha-
med
Best chrysanthemum in the show. —Prince
Omar Toussoun.</p>
<item>Beck & Co's Pilsener Beer.
BREMEN.
Obtainable from every Respectable Firm.
IN CAIRO, ALEXANDRIA AND THE SUDAN.
Otherwise apply to
E.J. FLEURENT, F. MIALLEF, Bole Agent
Cairo, 11,Rue Miden, Alexandria. </item>
<head>THE CAIRO EXHIBITION.
    HIGH STANDARD Of EXHIBITS.</head>
<p>Saturday and Sunday's Chrysanthemum Show
at Cairo was a thorough saocess from the point of
view of the judges, and the weather was delight-
fully cool and pleasant, with the result that
the attendance was satisfactory and ths visitors
to the K. A.S building were content. The
exhibits in nearly all cases reached a very
high standard, some of the groups being
remarkably beautiful, and the cut flowers
attracting great attention. Mrs. Foaden, who
was by far tbe most successful exhibitor,
secured no less than eleven first prizes, her
groups consisting of splendidly healthy
blooms, and her other exhibits being extremely
tastefully arranged. Lord Cromer visited the
Show early on Satnrday afternoon, as did the
Prime Minister and Husseith Fakhry Pasha
and many other well-known Cairo personalities,
and there was a very fair attendance on the
second afternoon of the show. We need not
say that the arrangements were excellent, and
that the excellent tea that was provided and
the music, for which we have to thank the
C. O. of the 2nd Royal Inniskilling Fosiliers,
were heartily appreciated.
The following were the prize-winners in the
various clasaes of exhibits:-</p>
<head>AMATEURS.</head>
<p>Flowers Cultivated in Pots.
1.	Group of at least 25 pots of Cbrysanthe-
mums.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 1. Ahmed Bey Kho-
loussi.
2.	Group of at least 12 pots of Chrysanthe-
mums and not exceeding 22 pots—1. Mrs.
Foaden; 2. Ahmed Bey Kholoussi.
3.	Group of at leaat 6 pots of Chrysanthe-
mums and qot exceeding 12 pots.—1. Mrs.
Foadon ; 2. Miss F. Curtis.
4.	Group of at least 3 pots of Chrysanthe-
mums grown for decorative purposes rather
than for large flowers. — 1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2
Ahmed Bey Kholoussi.
5. One specimen or standard Chrysanthemum
plant.—No exhibit
6.	The best collection of at least 10 pots
in flower other than Chrysanthemums.—2.
Ahmed Bey Kholoussi.
Cut Flowers.
7.	Collection of 48 blooms of Chrysanthe-
mums.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; equal 2. Mrs. Mac-
kenzie and Capt. Owen.
8.	Collection of 24 blooms of Chrysanthe-
mum.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Mrs. Mackenzie.
9.	Collection of 12 blooms of Chrysanthe-
mum.—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 9. Mrs. Mackenzie.
10 6 blooms of Chrysanthemum.—1. Mrs.
Foaden ; 2. Mrs. Mackenzie.
11.	Zinnias (one box).—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2,
Mackenzie.
12.	Cannas (one box).—No award.
13. Dahlias (one box).-1. M. Giliberti; 2.
Ahmed Bey Kholoussi.
14.	Collection of Flowers not previously
specified ; 2 boxes at least—1. M. Giliberti.
15.	Collection of Flowers not previously
specified ; 1 box at leaat—1. M. Giliberti.
BASKETS AND VASES OF FLOWERS.
16.	Basket of Chrysanthemums.—1. Mrs.
Foaden ; 2. Mrs. Butcher and Miss Crewe.
17.	Vase of Chrysanthemums ;1. Mrs.
Foaden ; 2. Miss F. Curtis.
18.	Basket of Flowers (other than Chrysan-
themums).—No exhibits.
19.	Vase of Flowers (other than Chrysaathe-
mums).—1. Mrs. Foaden ; 2. Miss F. Curtis, -
NURSERYMEN.
20.	Group of pot Chrysanthemums.—1.
Moh. Said el Kebir; 2. Said Mohamad.
21.	Best collection of cut blooms of Chry-
santhemums. 1. - Moh. Said el Bakri; 2. Said
Mohamed.
Extra prizes for a basket of chrysanthemums
and for buttonholes awarded to Ahmed Mus-
tapha.
22.	Exhibits from Government Garden,
Royal Horticultural Society's S.G.M. and an
Objet d'Art. </p>
<head>THE SUCRBRIES COMPANY.
    MEETING OP DEBENTURE HOLDERS.</head>
<p>A meeting of tbe debenture-holders of the
Egyptian Sugar Refineries was held recently in
Paris, at which, on tbe initiative of the French
Council of Foreign Bondholders, a committee
was formod (the Paris correspondent of the
"Financial News" states) with the fullest
powers to safeguard their interests before the
Cairo Tribunal of Commerce. The creditors of
the unfortunate concern have again been con-
vened for November 17, after having met on
October 18 last, to receive the report of the
experts.This dcoament,the correspondent says,
particularly incriminates the board of di-
rectors which up till last year distributed
dividends, whilst the company’s business never
resulted in a single centime profit. On the
contrary, for the last five years the Egyptian
Sugar Refineries constantly worked at a loss,
which did not appear in the obviously
"doctored” balance-sheets.
As to tbe notorious Cronier bills which the
managing directors aocepted, unknown to their
colleagues of the board, the experts declare
they were duly entered in the oompany's
books; but the items reffering to that account
were subsequently omitted from the balance-
sheets. Moreover, the bills once paid by the
company could not be found until they were
discovered at the private residence of a subor-
dinate employe, who had staetd that he bad
never seen them.
The debenture-holders will now await the
meeting of November 17,when the experts will
read a supplementary report, whioh will also
set forth the exact state of the assets and
liabilities of the company. </p></div> 
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Olivia Evanoff</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-10-01</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-11-07</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"> <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 7, 1905</head>
<head>RUSSIA’S LAST FIGHT.
REVOLUTIONISTS' SWAY. </head>
<head>M. WITTE AND HIS CABINET.</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, November 6.
News of continual anti-Semitic and anti-
liberal riots continues to arrive from all parts,
from Archangel to Tiflis and from Poland to
Tomsk. They are generally the result of what
are called patriotic or conservative manifesta-
tions, which are organized under the auspices
of the police, and formed of mobs headed by
the Imperial banner or by a portrait of the
Tsar.
There have been hundreds oi killed and
wounded at Rostoff-on-Don and at Krement-
chug.	(Reuter)</p>
<head>St. Petersburg, November 6. </head>
<p>The Tsar's manifesto restoring all the an-
cient liberties of Finland has been published
at Helsingfors.The constitutionalists are sa-
tisfied, but the revolutionaries demand further
concessions.
The revolutionists have proved their control
over the masses by countermanding yester-
day's demonstration, announcing that they
would choose their own day, and not accept
one of Trepoff's choosing, for the last fight.
M. Witte has not made the least progress in
the formation of a Cabinet The Conservatives
avoid him ; the Liberals show themselves dis-
trustful, while the reactionaries detest him.
A few weeks' full is expected, during which
the revolutionary party will perfect their
organisation.
A fresh manifesto assures the people that
the reforms will be inflexibly carried out
despite the efforts of the enemies of reform,
but the Government must have the coopera-
tion of the pacific majority.	{Reuter)</p>
<head>St. Petersburg, November 6.</head>
<p>The day has been quiet here. In Odessa the
troubles are decreasing.	(Hovas) </p>
<head>AUSTRIA.</head>
<head>UNIVERSAL SUFFRAGE WANTED</head>
<head>Vienna, November 6.</head>
<p>Great manifestations in favor of universal
suffrage have taken place in the principal
cities of the Empire. At Prague they were the
occasion of grave rioting.	( Reuter)</p>
<head>MONTENEGRO.</head>
<head>PARLIAMENTARY GOVERNMENT
ESTABLISHED. </head>
<head>Cettigne, November 6.</head>
<p>The Prince bes established, parliamentary
government in Montenegro.	(Reuter) </p>
<head>RING ALFONSO IN BERLIN.</head>
<head>Berlin, November 6.</head>
<p>The King of Spain has arrived on e visit to
the Emperor.	(Reuter) </p>
<head>Berlin, November 6.</head>
<p>King Alfonso has arrived and was greatly
cheered.	(Hovas)</p>
<head>SLAVO-ITALIAN CONFLICTS.</head>
<head>Vienna, November 6.</head>
<p>The conflicts between the Slavian and
Italian students continue.	(Hovas) </p>
<head>FRENCH BUDGET.</head>
<head>Paris, November 6.</head>
<p>The Chamber of Deputies has commenced
the debate on the Budget.	(Hovas) </p>
<item>DECK & CO’S PILSENER BEER
BREMEN
FEARS NO HONEST COMPETITION FOR QUALITY
N B. — Inferior Brands now being offered to
Managers of certain good circles.
Beware of evilly disposed competition running
down this very
SUPERIOR BRAND OF BEER.</item>
<item>Anglo-American Nile Steamers
and HOTEL COMPANY.
River Transport of Goods between Alexandria and Cairo
three sailings a-week.
agents at Alexandria:
ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO. LTD. </item>
<item>CARLTON HOTEL.
Bulkley (near Alexandria) 
RAMLEH’S FASHIONABLE HOTEL
PATRONED BY THE ELITE.
Full Pension from P.T. 60 a day. Visitors from
Cairo alight at Bidi-Gaber station.
G. AQUILINA</head>
    <head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
<p>Quarantine in Malta.—Alexandria is no
longer considered as an "infected plaoe” by
the authorities in Malta.</p>
<p>Suez Canal.—23 vessels passed throogh
the Canal on the 1st and 2nd inst, the amount
of dues received being frs. 637,795.37.</p>
<p>Cairo Mixed Court.—The judges of the
Cairo Mixed Court have held a general meet-
ing under the presidency of M. Prunieres, and
approved the "reglement do service” for the
judicial year 1905-6.</p>
<p>False Jewellery. - Some Alexandria jewel-
lers have been arrested for selling imitation
gold ornaments falsely stamped as being real
gold. Recently, also, three Syrian brothers were
imprisoned at Hadra for the same offence.</p>
<p>Native Benevolence. TLo “Mokattam”
learns from Fayoum that the omdehs and
notables of that town held a meeting and
decided to establish a benevolent society, the
object of which is to build a technical school.
A subscription on the spot realised £3,000.</p>
<p>New Doctors. — Drs. Hassan Hosny Afifi,
Kamel Fahmi, Mohamed Abdul Hamid, Nassif
Fahmy Mencarious, Mohamed Kamil Baradab,
Tewfik Naguib, Abdel Hamid Sami, Abdel
Aziz Helmi, Riskalla Moussa, and Mohamed
Sidky, have been authorised to practise in
Egypt.</p>
<p>Union Fonciered’Egypte.—It is announced
that definitive share warrants to bearer in the
Union Fonciere d'Egypte are now ready for
delivery, in exchange for fully-paid allotment
letters, at the Anglo-Foreign Banking Com-
pany, Limited, 2, Bishopsgate-street Within,
London, E.C.</p>
<p>A. L M. & D. S.—The annual general meet-
ing of the members of the Alexandria Literary,
Musical and Dramatic Society has been fixed
to take place on Wednesday, 15th inst., at
H.B.M.'s Consulate, at 6.30 p.m. Business:
1.To pass ths acconuts for past session ; 2.
To elect a oommittee end office-bearers for
ensuing session; 3. To prepare programme
for next season.</p>
<p>Revue Internationale D'Egypte —The
November issue of the 'Revue Internatio-
nale d’Egypte” is as interesting as usual and
contains the following contributions:—L'Expe-
dition d'Egypte: 1798-1801 (R.G.C.). Le Pay-
sage Egyptian (Louis Fieri), II Moderno
Teatro Italiano (Giovanni Munduls), Les
Morta (J. M.), Le Bonheur (Henri Sarvee).
Un Poete (Pierre Andibert). Jose-Maria De
Heredia (Georges Dumani), Fata Morgana
(U. Fleres).</p>
<p>Mysterious Murder —A servant of Abdel
Latif Bey Faid was murdered in His master’s
house Cadabah village, Gharbieh, on the
2nd inst. by some unknown persons. The mur-
derers appear to bare first beaten him most
savagely and then strangled him, forcing the
point of a stick which reached the brain into
his skull. Ths Kafr el Zayat authorities have
opened an enquiry. Hassan Effendi Faid, the
omdeb, and some ghaffirs are suspected of the
crime, because, it is said, the omdeh was on
bad terms with the murdered man. They have
been arrested, but as yet no proof has been
advanced of their guilt.</p>
    <head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
<p>Princess Nazli Hanem is expected to arrive
here from Tunis next Wednesday accompanied
by her husband, in order to spend the winter
season in Egypt. They will, probably, proceed
to Cairo on the same day by the evening
express.</p>
<p>H. H. the Khedive will grant an andienoe
to the Russian Agent and Consul-General on
Thursday next</p>
<p>The Marquis de Soragna has returned to
Cairo.</p>
<p>An extension of leave for one month has
been granted to Harvey Pasha.</p>
<p>The Norddentescher Lloyd S.S. Schleswig,
which arrived at Alexandria last night from
Marseilles, had a large contingent of passen-
gers. Among the more prominent people on
board we noticed General Djellal-el-Diu Pasha
(who was met on arrival by T. H. Prince Aziz
and Prince Omar Toussoun, and drove off in a
motor car with them), Fouad Pasha, Hon. Mr.
Iddings, the new American Diplomatic Agent
with Mrs. and Miss Iddings, Mustapha Pasha
Kamel, Count de Zogheb, Adly Pasha Yeghen
Governor of Cairo, Baron E. de Menasce, etc.</p>
<p>Among the passengers who arrived by the
Messageries Maritimes steamer this morning
were Abani Pasha, Minister of War, the family
of M. de la Bonliere, French Diplomatic
Agent, Mr. and Mrs. John Ross, etc.</p>
<p>The King of Greece has bestowed the Cross
of the Saviour on Mohamed Shafik Bey, chief
engineer of the Sharkieh Moudirich.</p>
    <head>MR. STEAD ON SITUATION.</head>
<head>INTERVIEW WITH
    THE DOWAGER EMPRESS.</head>
    <head>REFORMS TOO LATE.</head>
<head>(Gazette's Special Service)
    London, Monday, Nov. 6.</head>
<p>Mr. W. T. Stead has arrived in Copenhagen
from Helsingfors and has had a long private
interview with the Dowager Empress ot Russia,
in which he said that the gravity of the situa-
tion in Russia cannot be overestimated. Mr.
Stead predicted gigantic massacres, and he
believes that the reforms have oome too late.
Wireless telegraphy has been installed
between Peterhof and Berlin. The Kaiser has
sent an autograph letter to the Tsar.</p>
    <head>ACTIVE SERVICE IN CRETE.</head>
<p>The following order was issued yesterday
by Brig.-General Bullock, C.B. commanding
the Army of Occupation :—
The General Officer Commanding hereby
declares that, by reason of the recent exis-
tence of active service in the Island of Crete,
it is, in his opinion, necessary for the Public
Service that the British Forces in the Island
aforesaid shall continue temporarily subject
to the Army Act as if they were on active
service, with effect from 31st October, 1905,
and until 30th November, 1905, both dates
inclusive.</p>
    <head>THE NEW GRAND MUFTI.</head>
<p>The new Grand Mufti, Sheikh Bakri Moha-
med Ashour El Sedfi, has entered immediately
on his new post. He is a well-known personality
among the Moslem religious notables and a
follower of the Hanafi rite. He was educated
at Al Azhar, where he became ulema after
showing considerable theological proficiency,
and was for a long period Mufti to the now
suppressed Beit-el-Mal Administration. He
was later appointed to the Mehkemeh High
Court as Cadi and showed such legal and
theological acumen that he gained the good
opinion of the bulk of Egyptian Moslems.
He was acting as Grand Cadi in the place of
Sheikh Yehia, who has gone on an important
errand to Constantinople, when the death of
Sheikh Abdul Kader El Raffei threw open to
him the Grand Muftiship of Egypt.
One of our Cairo contemporaries states that
the Ministry of Jnstice is at present discussing
the question whether the new Grand Mufti
can still perform his functions of Grand Cadi
per interim, or whether some one else must be
appointed to replace Sheikh Yehia during his
absence in Turkey.</p>
    <head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>
<p>MM. Fourneron Bey and Sanpaolo, who
returned last Friday night from their visit to
the Ibrahimieh sugar factories, left Cairo by
the night train yesterday for a fresh tour of
inspection. This time the experts will examine
and report on the factories at Nag Hamadi,
Arment, and Mataana, a task which will, it
is expected, employ their energies for at least
another week. The third and, let us hope, the
final report of the experts is expected to be
completed by Thursday, the 18th inst.</p>
<head>ANGLO-EGYPTIAN LAND
    ALLOTMENT.</head>
<p>Letters of allotment for the shares of the
Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment Company
have been posted. The allotment was carried
through by Messrs. Russell and Kerr, chartered
accountants, of Cairo.
Dr. Axil Th. Preyer has joined the board
of the Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment Co.
Mr. Crewe, who was till now agent for the
National Bank of Egypt at the Mousky branch,
Cairo, has been appointed sub-manager to the
Egyptian Land Allotment Co., under a con
contract of ten years, and with a salary of£720
per annum.</p>
<head>NORTH EGYPT LAND CO.</head>
<p>With reference to the statement of a local
contemporary in its issue of last Saturday,
re the North Egypt Land Co., L-d, we may
point out that the oompany are not wholly
dependent on “providential rainfalls” for
raising their crops on their Mariout property,
as there are already a number of wells which
irrigate the land, and many more are to be
sunk. But leaving aside the decision of the
Irrigation Department not to extend the Nu-
barieh Canal for the present, there is another
scheme about to be proposed to the Govern-
ment which will afford ample means for irrigat
ing not only the fifteen thousand feddans at
present owned by the company, but a good
deal more.</p>
    <head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
<p>The Ellerman S.S. Britannia sailed from
Malta on Sunday night and is expected here
on Friday morning with passengers, mails
and general cargo.
The Moss liner Menes sailed from Liverpool
on Saturday afternoon last, and is due here
on the 18th inst. with passengers, mails,
an general cargo.</p>
<head>AMERICAN GIRL SLAVE IN
    EGYPT.</head>
<head>HER HUSBAND'S TREACHERY.</head>
<p>We cull the following from a New York
oontemponry :—
The extraordinary case of Mollie Katain
who was married last July to Harry Liederer,
No. 170 Delancey street taken by him to
Egypt sold as a white slave into bondage, and
rescued by the efforts of the International
Society for the Suppression of the White Slave
Trade, has just come to light through a letter
sent by the girl to her brothers in New York.
Her courtship was a short one, and she was
married at her home, No. 132, Attorney street
last July. Four weeks later she disappeared
and was not heard of until last weak, when
the society sent her to her brothers after they
had rescued her.
Her introduction to Lederer, it was said,
was brought about by Mrs. Nathan Weber,
who lives at No. 122, Suffolk street She had
$300 in bank in her own name and this must
have been, withdrawn without her knowledge,
for in her letter she asks that her fare home
may be paid out of this money.
The letter to her brothers is in her own
handwriting and is as follows:
“My Dear Brothers—I am unable to express
the sad position in which I find myself My
husband has been treacherous and has fooled
me all along. He brought me to Alexandria and
has made me a prisoner of other men. I wish
you to go to court and get duplicates of the
documents which show that I am his wife, as
he has stolen the original papers from me.
Buy a ticket for me to return, for he has
taken all my money from me. Iam very sick
and cannot write much more. Molfie.” </p>
    <head>NEW SUDAN AGENT.</head>
<p>Captain R. C. Owen has been appointed
Director ot the Intelligence Department and
Sudan Agent at Cairo.</p>
    <head>THE PHARMACY REGULATIONS.</head>
<p>We mentioned in our issue of the 16th
ultimo two serious infringements of the new
pharmacy regulations which oome into ope-
ration about a year ago. These prove how
necessary it is for the Sanitary Adminis-
tration to use the utmost vigilance for safe-
guarding the public. In one case a Greek
named Pistis, when applying for permission
to open a pharmacy, sent in a diploma that
was ascertained to have belonged to a man
who had been dead since 1896! In the other
case three individuals sent in diplomas pur-
porting to have been issued by the Faculty
of Medicine of Athens bat which, when
subjected to expert examination, were found
to be forged.
The officials of the Department, since the
new regulations came into operation, have
taken in hand the inspection of pharmacies
but it seems they are greatly hampered by
the action of the Tribunals, who, when clear
cases of irregularities are brought to their
notice, inflict such a ridioulously small punish-
ment that it cannot possibly act as a de-
terrent. Recently, we are informed, at Man-
sourah, two individuals, one a Greek and
the other an Italian, were summoned for
keeping a pharmacy open for three months
without a certificated chemist. The Tribunal
Mixte de Contravention inflicted for this grave
offence the minimum fine of P.T. 5 in one
case and P.T. 10 in the other!</p>
    <head>NEW KHEDIVIAL HOTEL.</head>
<p>The New Khedivial Hotel at Alexandria,
whioh is at present being entirely renovated,
will be quite ready for occupation again by the
coming Christmas. It will, when completed,
contain altogether 150 bedrooms and twenty
suites of special apartments fitted with bath-
rooms, closets, and other accommodation. The
grill-room will be open on the 1st December,
and afternoon teas will be served in the new
pavilion on the terrace. A fine Tzigane band
has been specially engaged for the hotel and
will play three times a day.
A special feature of the hotel will be the
residential apartments for bachelors and fami-
lies, who will be able to live at the hotel at
an inclusive and moderate cost for board and
lodging.It is expected that this innovation
will be taken full advantage of, and owing to
the poor restaurants aud high rents at Alex-
andria such accommodation will be a great
advantage to residents.
Another special feature of the hotel will be
the cooking.The leading "chef” at the Metro-
pole Hotel, Moote Carlo, has been engaged,
and arrived on Sunday last with an entire
brigade of gastronomic artists selected with
the utmost care from among the leading
European hotels and restaurants. During the
winter the Khedivial Hotel management will
give a ball once a fortnight, as is the custom
in Cairo. There is to be a grand “Reveillon”
at the hotel at Christmas, which will be
the formal opening fete of the hotel. Every
night when there is a performance at the
Zizinia Theatre there will be a special supper
menu at a fixed inclusive price, and a band
will play from midnight until 2 p.m.
A large American bar is to be opened on
December 1, which will be equal to the finest
bar in Egypt. The hotel is under the manage-
ment of Mr. E. Fleury, late manager of the
Nonvel Hotel at Vichy and of the Alexandra
Hotel at Monte Carlo. </p>
<head>BANK OF ABYSSINIA.</head>
<head>ALL CAPITAL APPLIED FOR.</head>
    <head>(Gazette's Special Service).</head>
    <head>London, Monday, Nor. 6.</head>
<p>The Berlin Bank fur Handel and Indus-
trie has applied for 100,000 £5 shares in the
Bank of Abyssinia.</p>
    <head>London, November 6.</head>
<p>Tbe prospectus of tbe Bank of Abyssinia
has been issued.	(Reuter)</p>
    <head>THE RODAH LAND SALE.</head>
<p>At the recent land sale at Rodah, according
to 'Le Progres,” Dr. Nimr bade L.E. 2,470 per
feddan for tbe Menekley estate and this was
the highest bid. But owing to a dispute as
to the validity of the bid it is possible that
Maitre Carton de Wiart's offer on behalf of
an English group rail hold good. The ques-
tion will be decided at the next meeting of
the Superior Council of the Wakfs.</p>
    <head>NILE VALLEY CO.</head>
<p>The "Financial News" is officially authoris-
ed to deny tbe report that the Nile Valley
Company is to be reconstructed.</p>
    <head>WALKER AND MEIMARACHI.</head>
<p>The latest London papers contain the report
of the proceedings at the meeting of Walker
and Meimarachi, Limited, held in London on
Monday, Ootober 30. This ia said to be the
first English company founded in Egypt, and
owing to its good management we are sure
that the shareholders will be pleased-to hear
that the capital is to be increased so that the
company may be able to develop its business
throughout Egypt and the Sudan. The board
of directors will henceforth be in Cairo, with
only two directors in London. The company
will remain an English company and the
meetings will be held in London.</p>
<head>BIG FIRE AT ASSIOUT.</head>
<p>One of the wealthiest families at Assiout is
the Khaehabah family, writes our Assiout
Correspondent. They had four large houses at
Assiout. One was burnt down four months
ago, another two months ago, and the remain-
ing two last week. The fire broke out at
11 p.m. and in aboat two hours, the two
houses were a blazing mass. The loss is
estimated at £8,000. It is a remarkable coin-
cidence that in all three cases the cause of
this outbreak was accidental.
Our correspondent states that Assiout. is
very badly supplied with pumps. In the fire
mentioned the house was burning for a whole
hour before the pumps arrived, and after they
came it took another hour to put them in
working order.
Thanks are due to Mr. Russell, the Interior
inspector, who worked hard all night, as on
the previous occasions.</p>
    <head>NEW ENGLISH PAPERS.</head>
<p>A new illustrated political weekly, styled
"The Oriental Truth,” has just made its
appearanoe at Cairo. It is dedicated to Oriental
civillisation and the editor and proprietor is
Captain Joge Neokan y Weldberg. There is
also an Arabic and a Freneh part in addition
to the English.
Another new English publication is “Egyp-
tian Cotton,” published at Alexandria. We
wish our new contemporaries every success.</p>
    <head>BANCO DI ROMA</head>
<p>Ainsique nous l'avons deja publie, le conseil
d'administration du "Banoo di Roma” a decide
de porter le capital de oet important eta
blissement financier de O a 30 millions.
L’emission das cent mille actions au prix de
fr. 120,80, jouissance premier janvier -1905,
aveo un dividende assure non inferieur aux 7
francs ordinaires par action aura lieu du 6 au 9
novembre.
Les nouvelles actions sont donc souscrites a
moins de 115 francs, car depuis de nombreuses
annees deja, le dividende du "Banco di Roma"
eat consolide a fr. 7; ce qui vent dire que ces
actions presentent le rare avantage d’un place-
ment aussi sur que le consolide italien a plus
da 6 pour cent.
Les noeveaux titres aeront offerts a option
aux porteurs dos anciennes actions a raison
d’une nouvelle action contre deux anciennes.
L’emission est garantie an eotier par deux
grands groupes feanciers.
Cette augmentation du capital da "Banco di
Roma” s’explique par la croissante expansion
de cet etablissement financier non senlement en
Italie maia encore a l’etranger.
En effet, les sieges de cette banque existant
a Paris et a Alexandrie d’Egypte ont donne
des resultata si encourageante que de nouvelles
succursales seront instituees dans d'autrees
pays d’Europe.
Ce succes depend aurtout de la prudence et
de l'habilete financiere de la direction qui a su
an quelques annes faire d’une petite Banque
una des plus puisantes organisations financie-
res d’ltalie.</p>
<HEAD>THE PRINCES AND THE DAIRA
    SANIEH</head>
    <HEAD>THE MAIN CLAIM.</head>
<p>Mr. H.E Garle again writes to the "Times"
with references to the above, as follows:
Sir,—May I, in view of tbe references to this
matter in your issue of the 23td inst., again
trespass upon your space.
Tbe proceedings in question had nothing
whatever to do with the trial of the action and
the merits of the question were not even gone
into. The next-of-kin’s legal adviser in Egypt
was of opinion that, in all the circumstances,
the Egyptian Courts should be asked to restrain
any payment of the surplus in the hands of the
Daira Sanieh Limited to the Egyptian Govern-
ment; and this is all that was done, and is all
that has failed
The next-of-kin's main claim is against the
Egyptian Government and tho Daira Sanieh of
H.H. the Khedive ; it has not been tried, and
will not be tried for some time to come. The
proceedings that have taken-place are in truth,
little more than the equivalent to a stop order
in this country, and even so, are being appealed
against.
I earnestly trust that you will see your way
to give the same prominence to this letter that
you did to my last, for it is even more impor
tant that your statement in your issue of the
23rd inst. be answered than that in your issue-
of the 18th Inst.
I am. Sir. your obedient servant
H. Ernest Garle Solicitor the next-of-kin.
61, Lincoln's inn-fields, London, W.C,Oot 29. </p>
<head>THE LATE SIR TREVOR PLOWDEN.</head>
<p>Sir Trevor Chichele Ohichele-Plowden,
K.O.S.L,whose death was announced yesterday,
connects two famous names in his own person,
while the marriage of his daughter with the
Earl of Lytton, end his own second marriage
with a Fitzherbert of Swynnerton, connect
him with two other names of note. Chichele
began with the Archbishop, whose younger
brother was Sheriff of London, and father of
the Admiral, and Master-General of Ordeuance.
Plowden has produced not only Sir Trevor
and other Plowdens, familiar in the annals of
the Indian Civil Service but also Sir Trevor's
elder brother, the Cadi of Marylebone, the
"scintillae juris” of whose, judgement east
perennially enliven the police reports.</p>
<head>Pasenger List</head>
<head>Arrivals</head>
<p>Per S.S. Sohleewig, arrived at Alexandria
yesterday frtm Marseilles end Naples:-M,
D. Arif Bey, M,-and Mme P. Agoapian, Miles
Marie and Ketty Agopian, Mile .E Dexarena
M. and Mme Heinrich Bindernagel. M. Ludwig
Bindernagel, Milles llse and Freida Binder-
nagel, Mme Ph. Back, Mme Cecilia Buallachi,
Mlle Olly Bolts, Mlle Beor, M. and Mme
Leopold Blariaux, M. and Mae D, Caedagli,
Mme K. and Mlle M. E Cettier, M. and Mme
Cherky Pachs, M. Ahmed Checky Bey,
Mlle Viseae, Dr. von Campe, Mrs. W. Cum-
mings, General Ahmed Djelaleddin Pasha,
Miss Helen Denison, Mr. C. Duffield, M.L.
Dombre, M. Henry Dubois, Mme Ida Boy Edd,
Fouad Pacha, Mr. and Ms. Percival Foster,
Mr. and Mrs. Edward R Hoyt, Ms. Rendal,
Hoyt, Mr. and Mrs.Chas Humpers Mr.Andre
Humpers, Mrs. Hood, Mrs. W. Hammond Mr.
F. Hinkley, Mr. A. Hehanoff, Adly Yeghan,
Pacha and Mme, Mmme Lamalun, Mme and Mlle
Alfred Ismalun, Gonaull General Mrs., and
Miss Iddings, Mohamed Jaffer. Mme, J. G.
L Kooh, Mlle W. Kloes,. M. Aug, Kiene
Muatafa Kamel Pasha, Col Hon. R. T. Law-
ley. Capt and Mme von Langadorf, Mr. Ri-
chard Louth, Baron E de Menace, Mrs, C.
J. Milton, Mrs. Mahony, Mme. Idanka
Mayer, Mlle Lina Mayer,, Mrs. MacPherran,
Noury Bey, Lieuteniant van Neumann, Mr.
W. M. Noyes, Mr. and Mrs. R. Neville, Emille
Nagel, Mlle Johanne M. Naude, M. and
Mme Emila Paravioini, Mr. and Mrs. Parker,
Miss Parker, Miss Peel, Mrs. and Miss. W.F
Peel M. Theodoore J. Rodocanachi, M. Mohsen
Rifky, Mr. and Mrs. A. Robinson, Sabit Bey,
Mme Sabit, Mlle Leonnie, Gamille Sabit Bey,
Mr. and Mme., M.M. Scott, M. and Mme. Alfred
Suares, M. J. Shute, M. Sursook, M. A. Stul-
ken, M. Georg. Schmidt,Mlle A. Dan. Sommer,
Mile J. Sigert, M. Albert Tilohe, Mlle Tilche,
Cav. Uff. A. Tilche, Mme Tilche, Hon. J. C.
Vessey, Mr. and Mrs. Wyatt, M. and Mme.
Wierdals, Mlle Wierdals, M. Wierdals, Mr.
Watt, M. Ed. Wantz, Comtesse de Zogheb,
Mlle Jeanne de Zogheb, M. and Mme. Rhfoasd
Zander, Mlle Fanny Zander, Herr Oberburder-
meister Becker, Frau Ghemalin and Toohter,
Mr. R Baezner,Dr. and Mme F. Borchardt,Mr.
M. Billwiller, Mr. Ghstdve Cattaui, Mlle J.
Coczalmann, Mr. Cantalamesss, Mr. and Mme
Drakidis, Mr. J. Dobsult, Mr. Elie Francis,
Baronesse Halkett, Mr. Chr. Hornatein, Mlle
Ismailoff, Herr Landrat Krietzler, Mr. Lepeoh-
kine, Mr.Legoulles,Mr. Uaseoo,Mtared*Ueti*,
Said Mob. el Mokry, Said Mob. Benani, Mr.
and Mae P. Michel Mr.G. Madon.Mr. P. Mao
chi, Aw. P. Maochi, Ms. Georges Malic, Mile
Momtt, Mre. Mdngerin, Mra E Matiuea, Mr.
Neddi Meddin, Mr. E Nioholsde, Mr. P.
Philippo and family, Mr. G. Pbilippo. Mr. A.
Percy, M. and Mme A. Rocha. Mlle Rossi-
Pran.</p> </div>
            <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Olivia Evanoff</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-10-01</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-01-01">1905-11-08</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, Wednesday ,November 8, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
<head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 8,1905</head>
<div><<head>JEW EXTERMINATION.</head>
<head>MORE TERRIBLE SCENES
IN RUSSIA</head>
<head>THE NEW CABINET</head>
<head>QUIET IN ST. PETERSBURG</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, November 7
The strikes in Finland are ended.
The total killed during the recent riots in
Odessa number 964.
Tho number of the excesses committed in
the provinces is diminishing, which indicates
that the tardy orders of the Government for
the suppression, of disorders are being carried
out.
The St. Petersburg. Gazette annonnces
that M. Witte has been appointed President
of the Coancil. of Ministers, which had been
reorganised. It is stated that M. Shipoff, chief
of the Moscow Congress of Zsmstvos, has
accepted the post of Controller General of the
Empire and Minister of the interior. It is also
stated that occupants have been found for the
portfolios of finance and Communications.
(Reuter)</p>
<p>St.Petersburg, November 7.
(Official). M. Witte has been • appointed
President of the Council. </p>
<p>London, November 7
The Chief Rabbir has received a. telegram
from a leading Russian Jew stating that many
Jewish communities have been entirely de-
stroyed, and asking for help. Tho Rothechilds
and others are concerning measnres.
A meeting of the leading Jews was held at
Rothechilds this afternoon. It was decided to
appeal for funds lor the relief of the victims in
Russia. (Reuter) </p>
<p>St. Petersburg November 7. 
M.Witte, has prepared a new electoral
franchise for the National Assembly, increas-
ing its members to 600, inclnding 25 workmen,
greatly reducing tho property qoa’ifiations,
and widening the suffarage generally.
Numbers of shops and banks are being re-
opened, and ordinary life is being resumed
here and at Moscow, Helsingfors, and else-
where. There are, however, still terrible scenes
being enacted in the neighbouring villages and
at Odessa, where all the houses of Jews have
been destroyed. The killed number many
hundreds, and thousands are wounded and
starving.		(Reuter),</p>
<head>ABYSSINIAN BANK.</head>
<head>SUBSCRIPTION LIST CLOSED. .</head>
<p>	London, November 7.
Subscriptions to the Abyssinian Bank open-
ed to-day, and closed at noon, over subscribed.
(Reuter)</p>
<head>UNITED KINGDOM’S TRADE
RETURNS.</head>
<p>London, November 7.
The imports for the ten months ending
Ootober show an increase of £11,000,000, the
exports an increase of £50,000,000. (Reuter)</p>
<head>DEATH OF LADY FLORENCE DIXIE</head>
<p>London. November 7.
Lady Florence Dixie is dead. (Reuter)
Lady Florence Dixie was a daughter of the
seventh Marquis of Queensberry and was born
in 1857. She was married in 1875 to Sir Bean
mint Dixie. §he acted as war correspondent
for the “Morning Post" during tbe Boer War.</p>
    <head>KAISER AND KING ALFONSO.</head>
<p>Berlin, November17.
Cordial toasts were exchanged between the
Emporor and King Alfonso.	(Hovas) </p>
<head>FRENCH PARLIAMENT.</head>
 <p> Paris, November 7.-
The new elections to the Senate have been
fixed for January 7.
The Chamber has passed a vote of confi-
dence in M. Rouvier,refusing State employes
the right to strike.	(Hovas) </p>
<head>THE.NEW ZEALANDERS’ SCORE.</head>
<head>OXFORD BEATEN.</head>
<p>London,November 7..
Football. The New ZsaUnders' beat Oxford
by 47 to 0. The total more until now is 540
against 15.	(Reuter)</p>
<head>JOSEPH COMAS.
TECHNICAL ENGINEER</head>
<p>Surveyor and Constructor in shipping. Take
charge of Engines and Boilers. Undertakes
repairs of same, guaranteeing success. First
tvalues references. Address: Rue fl Warsha
Maison Gabriel, ALEXANDRIA.
26685-J2A1</p></div>
<div><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
<p>The Frindisi Mail will arrive at Alex-
andria at 3 pm. to-day and will be distributed
at tbe G.P.O. at 5 p.m.</p>
<p>Quarantine in Italy.—Quarantine restric-
tions against arrivals from AUxandria in Ita-
lian ports have been removed.</p>
<p>Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the
Abdeen district of Cairo daring the night of
Thursday will be poisoned by the police.</p>
<p>Greek Immigration. — A large number of
Greek immigrants from the Turkish islands in
tbe Arcbipelago have arrived at Alexandria
within the past few weeks.</p>
<p>Veterinary College—Nine pupils have
been admitted this year to  the college, which
now numbers 31 students. Tbe curriculum
will henceforth require four instead of three
years’ study.</p>
<p>The Egyptian Institute held its opening
meeting of the season yesterday. Professor
Maspero delivered a eulogy of tbe late M.
Oppert, and M. Legrain read a detailed
aoconnt of the latest excavations at Lexor.</p>
<p>Alhamrba Theatre. — The Crepy Simons
French operetta company will commence a
series of 60 performances at this theatre on
December 1 next. The company’s repertoire
includes all the latest creations.</p>
<p>Fatality —A native workman, remedies a
bouk Hassan, while digging yesterday in a
pit at Roud Point, Alexandria, was buried
under a heavy mass of earth which fell upon
him. The unfortunate man succumbed.</p>
<p>London Stock Exchange— Application has,
been made to the comittees of ths London
Stock Exchange to grant a settling day for -
Eridea (Egypt) Exploring Company, Limited.
—10/07 shares of £1 each fully paid (Noe.
1 to 8 and 65,008 to 75,007).</p>
<p>Zizinia Theatre—Mr. A. Lamtert, fils,
the celebrated French actor, opens at tbe
Zizinia Theatre this evening in Emilo Angier
4-act comedy, L'Aventuriere. M. Lambert, it
will be remembered, represented the French
stage at tbe funeral of tbe late Sir Henry
Irving.</p>
<p>Kask el Nil.—Owing to the increase in
the river traffic it has beea decided to alter
the hours at Kasr el Nil Bridge for traffic.
From Friday next, 10th inst., the bridge will
be open to admit the passage of river traffic
from 1:15 to 3 p.m., instead of from 1:30 to
3 p.m.</p>
<p>King’s Birthday.—To-morrow (Thursday)
will be observed as a holiday in the Army, in
honor of the anniversary of the birthday of
H.M. the King, and all offices and schools wil
be closed. Tbe headquarters offices will be
opened for business of an urgent nature from
7.15 a.m. to 8.15 a.m.</p>
<p>New Khedivial Hotel - Among the im
provements which are being made in tbe New
Khedivial Hotel, we omitted to mention in
yesterday’s article on the subject,that a feature
of tbe hotel which will be much appreciated
will be tbe private dining-rooms. This will
meet a much-felt want in Alexandria.</p>
<p>British Chamber or Commerce. — The
November issue of the Journal of tbe British
Chamber of Commerce of Egypt has appeared
The contents include: Points for Manufactu-
rers, Egypt's trade in Explosives, Acceleration
of, weekly Brindisi Mail for Alexandria.Customs
Returns, Imports during September, Manches-
ter Goods, etc.</p>
<p>Walker A Meimarchi — In reference
to the paragraph on Messrs. Walker &
Meimarachi, Limited, which we published yes
terday, we are authorised to state that this
company has decided to remain in its present
business premises at Alexandria and Cairo. So
there is no need for brokers and house agents
to apply to the firm with offers of new offices
eligible sites, etc. </p>
<p>New British Club.—A sufficient number
of replies having been receivad to warrant the
formation of the new British Club at Alexan-
dria, a general meeting of those who have
signified their intention of joining will be held
at tbe Eastern Telegraph Company’s head
quarters on Weinesdiy, 15th inst., at 9:15
p.m. Business: Election of Permanent Com
mitee; Selection of suitable premises (plan
will be submitted).</p>
<head>SPORT AND PLAY.</head>
<head>FOOTBALL.</head>
<p>There will be a football match tomorrow
at Mostapba between the E.T.C and ”D."
Compy. Royal Dublin Fusiliers. Kick off at
3:30.</p></div>
<div><head>NO CATTLE PLAGUE.</head>
<head>DISAPPEARANCE OF DISEASE</head>
<p>The reports sent in by the inspectors of
the Sanitary Department regarding tbe cattle
plague in tbe provinces are unanimous in
declaring that the malady has completely
disappeared.</p>
<head>OPENING OF CATTLE MARKETS.</head>
<p>No cases of cattle plague having been report-
ed since August 14, it has been decided, should
no further case occur, to open the cattle mar-
kets on the 22nd inst.</p>
<head>THE NEW GRAND MUFTL</head>
<p>We hear that it has been decided that Sheikh
Bakri el Sedfi, the new Grand Mufti of Egypt,
may continue to act as Grand Cadi till the
return of Sheikh Yehia from Turkey. The
Grand Mufti has officially called upon the
Ministers since his appointment</p>
<head>THE GRAND CADI.</head>
<p>The Grand Cadi of Egypt has wired to his
household in Cairo, informing them that he
has arrived at Constantinople in safety. It is
said, declares “Al Moayad,” that the Grand
Cadi promised his family before his departure
that, if no troubles were in store for him in the
Capital,he would let them have each a telegram.
Although the Saltan's summons to tbe
Cadi is still a mystery,continues “A1 Moayad,”
the romoor to the effect that he had been
called to Stamboul in order to go into tbe
question of tbe Caliphate, in other words, the
question of the succession to the Ottoman Throne
is quite baseless. The Cadi of Egypt has
nothing to do with such a question so long as
the Sheikh-ul-Islam and the other Ulema of
high standing reside in Constantinople.
If the Sultan wishes tbe succession to pass
to tbe sons instead of to tbe eldest Prince
he matteresn be settled at once by a single
1 sign from his Majesty.</p>
<head>SIR WILLIAM GARSTIN.</head>
<p>We understand that Sir William Garstin,
aocording to the latest accounts received by
his friends, is making most satisfactory pro-
gress and will almost certainly be in Egypt
before tbe new year.</p>
<head>VITALITY STATISTICS.</head>
<p>From the latest returns of tbe Statistical
Department in Cairo we find that the total
number of births in that city during the
week ending 28th Ootober was 563, including
7 of foreign parentage; this being equal to
a rate of 47 per thousand of the estimated
population. For the week ended last Saturday
the births were 527, of which 9 were of
foreign parentage, the rate being 44.3
per mile. The deaths for the first week
under review numbered 411, inoluding 24
of foreign nationality; this is equivalent
to a rate of 32.7 per thousand for the native
and 35.4 for the European portion of the inha-
bitants. For the week ending the 4th instant
the deaths were 402, which included 16 foreig-
ners, and the ratios 33.0 and 23.0 per mile
for the native and foreign portions respec-
tively.
At Alexandria the births for the first week
were 295, which was inclusive of 15 children
of foreign parentage, the rate per thousand
being 46.0. Last week there was registered
329 births, of which 17 were of the latter
category. During the week ending tbe 28th ult.
the mortality returns were 202 natives and
12 foreigners and the ratios 33.2 and 13.5
per thousand. For the week ending on Saturday
last the figures were 207 natives and 18 Euro-
peans, the rates being 34.4 and 20.3 per mile
respectively.
For tbe guidance of those of our readers
who are interested in statistics, we may men-
tion that according to the official table
recently published tbe native population of
Cairo and its suburbs was estimated on the
1st July last at 615,152. No exact esti-
mate can, however, be made of the foreign
resident inhabitants of either Cairo or Alex-
andria, as no returns are obtainable from the
Consulates. The last census of June 1897
gave the foreign element at 25,219 and 46,118
for each of the above cities respectively
but, of course, these figures must have been
considerably augmented since then by im-
migration and excess of births over deaths.
The same tables give the estimated number
of the native population of Alexandria on
the date above mentioned as 316.639.</p>
<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
<p>The new Moss liner Menepthah sailed
hence yesterday afternoon for Liverpool, via
Malts with passengers, mails and general
cargo.
The S.S. Asiatic Princa from Antwerp and
Middlesbrorgh, left Malta yesterday, and
doe to arrive at Alexandria on Saturday
next.</p>
<head>Beck & Co s Pilsener Beei
BREMEN.</head>
<p>Obtainable from every Respectable firm
IN CAIRO, ALEXANDRIA AND THE SUDAN.
Otherwise apply to
E J. FLEURENT, F. MICALLEF, sole agent</p></div>
<div><head>LIFE OF M. WITTE
THREATENED.</head>
<head>TREPOFFS REMOVAL
DEMANDED.</head>
<p>(Gazette's Special Service).
London, Tuesday, Nov. 7.
Quiet continues to prevail in St. Petersburg.
The Tsar’s manifesto abolishing exclusive
laws is unconfirmed.
The Duma is to consist of 600 members,
elected on the basis of property, education, and
class representation.
MWitte’s appointment as Premier of
Russia’s first Cabinet has beea gazetted.
The revolutionary leaders have threatened
to take the life of M. Witte if General Trepoff
is not removed from his post within three days.
M. Witte is residing in the Winter Palace. 
The Tsar is expected in St. Petersburg on
Friday.</p>
<head>LORD MINTO AT PORT SAID.</head>
<p>(From our Correspondent.)
Port Said, Tuesday.
Lord Minto, the new Viceroy of India
arrived here to-day by tbe P.& O. mail
S.S. Victoria on his way to India.</p>
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
<p>H. H. the Khedive spent yesterday at
Koubbeh.</p>
<head>THE PRINCES AND THE DAIRA.</head>
<p>The legal department of the Finance Minis-
try has sent a note to the Under-Secretary of
State for Finanoe on the subject of the Khedi-
vial Princes’ claims re the Daira Sanieh. The
note shows that the Princes have little chance
n of winning their case.</p>
<head>NATIVE APPEAL COURT.</head>
<p>The Ministry of Justice has decided to
create a new judgeship in the Native Court
of Appeal at Cairo. Hussein Bey Rouchdy, a
judge ot the Cairo Mixed Bench, has been
selected for this post and will enter on his new
duties on the 1st January.</p>
<head>NEW INSECT PEST.</head>
<p>Considerable damage has been done in one
or two local idea in Upper Egypt to the pome-
granate by the larva of a small but pretty
butterfly scientifically known as Dendoriz
livia and a relative of the' well known “blues”
and “copeprs.” It seems that the caterpillar,
to which usually devours tbe pods of the “fitneh”
accacia enters the pomegranate immediately
after leaving the egg and eats long tunnels
into tbe fruit Three galleries get rapidly
filled with mildew and the "frass” of the
insect, and the fruit is spoiled.</p>
<head>THE PISANI CASE.</head>
<p>The hearing of the Pisani case, which took
place at H.B,M.’s Consulate Cairo, yesterday
resulted in the defendant being ordered to
appear for trial before the judge of the Supreme
Consular Court, who is expected to arrive in
Cairo in about ten days to a fortnight’s time.
The accused was allowed to find bail, gua-
ranteed by two sureties of j£160 eaoh.</p>
<head>NILE VALLEY OPERATIONS.</head>
<p>The following report, dated Ootober 14,
has been received from the Mine:-No. 1
shaft, 900 ft level.—North drive—This drive is
now a total length of 27 ft. from the centre of the
shaft. South drive.—The face of this drive is
18 ft 6 ins from the centre of the shaft. No. 5
shaft, 2nd leveL—North drive.—This drive is
now a total leng’h of 212 ft 3 ins from the
cross-cut. Tbe face of this drive is now some
20 ft north of point at which the ore pinched
out in the level above and is directly under
the point at which the cross-head cut off the
fisure. Occasional specks of gold are met
with. No. 7 shaft, 2nd level.—South drive.-
This drive has again advanced to 216 ft 6 ins.
from the cross-cut. Battery. The consignment
of oil arrived on Sunday morning last, since
when the battery has been running steadily
night and day, the ore crushed being from
development. </p>
<head>BAND PERFORMANCE.</head>
<p>By kind permission of Col H.F.M. Wilson
and the officers, tbe band of the 2nd Batt.
Rifle Brigade will play the following program-
me at the Continental Hotel to-morrow
(Thursday) at 8 p.m, on the occassion of the
King’s Birthday.
1. March- Long live the King - Hume.
2. Overture- Festival- Lenteur.
3. Selection- The Dancing Doll- Bayer.
4. Funeral March of a Marionette- Gounod
5. Intermezo- Rendezvous- Aletter
6. Selection- Faust- Gounod
7. Landler- Grossumtterchan- Lungey.
8. Velze- Morgenblatter- Trauss
Khedivial Anthem- God Save the King
R. Wood, Bandmaster </p></div>
<div><head> BRITISH GARRISON. </head>
<head>NOW COMMANDED BY SIRDAR.</head>
<p>The British troops stationed at Khartoum
have been placed under the command of
his Excellency the Governor-General of the
Sudan, and have been struck off the strength
of tbe Egyptian Command with effect from
6th inst, inclusive.</p>
<head>RAMBLEH'S WATER SUPPLY</head>
<p>To the Editor or the Egyptian Gazette.
Sir,—As everybody is aware, we have had
two fires at Ramleh within the last month, and
at both of these the Fire Brigade promptly
turned up ,but was quite useless as there was
no water. This news has already appeared in
the columns of the “Gazette,” but we have had
no reply or contradiction from the Alex-
andria Water Company, which turns off the
Ramleh water supply about 5 p.m. Fortanately
on eaoh of the nights on which the fires
occured there was no wind. Otherwise in
the case of tbe fire at Bacos, all that
thickly populated part of Ramleh might have
devastated. I presume that nothing will
be done to remedy this deplorable state of
things until the palatial residence of some
Municipal Councillor or of one of the Kbedivial
Princes is completely gutted. Then, and not
till then, will pressure be brought to bear on
the Alexandria Water Company. Meanwhile,
all the inhabitants of Ramleh must go to bed
every night with the apprehension that if their
home does gat on fire, all they can do is to
watch it burn—Truly yurs,
A Ramlehite.
Balkeley, 7th November.</p>
<head>CAIRO STREET PERILS.</head>
<p>Dear Sir,—I was recently told the following
story by a friend, which I repeat in the hope
that those to whom we vaguely refer as “the
proper authorities” will read, mark, and learn.
My informant was walking slowly one after-
noon along one of Cairo’s streets—and by no
means its meanest—and found time to pause
for an instant and admire the demeanour of two
Arabs who were walking along tbe pavement
hand in hand cleanly dressed, silent—for a
wonder—and their faces illumined with an abject
and ruatio happiness which was worth going miles
to see. Suddenly a loud gargling noise came
from overhead, and from a spout that project-
ed apparently aimlessly from a third story a
jet of soapy water descended on the pair. They
first exhibited a wild surprise and then in-
dulged for a couple of minutes in excusable,
if unrestrained, profanity, after which they
wiped their garments and moved on, still
cursing, amid demonstrations of amused sym-
pathy from the passers-by. Now, Sir, I like a
harlequinade as much as any man—the spectacle
of a policeman falling through a trap door or
coming in contact with a red hot poker has
always and will always please me. There is a
strenuous humour ia the oartoons of eighteenth
century caricaturist that also appeals to me,
and the decent of a tub-full of soap suds on
an immaculately dressed passer-by has been
immortalised by their pencils. But I frankly
admit that I dslike practical jokes when they
are directed against me ; my motto is flat ex-
perimentum in corpore vili, and I now make a
detour whenever I notice one of these projecting
spouts which, I hear, carry away the overflow
of baths and washhouses. If our city authori-
ties can do something to prevent their being
need in this way they will earn the gratitude
of many besides. 
Meticulous.
Cairo, November 7.</p>
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
<p>Adly Pasha Yaghen called upon the Prime
Minister yesterday.</p>
<p>The salary of Lord Edward Cecil Pasha as
Under Secretary of State for Finance has been
fixed at L.E. 2,000 per aonum.</p>
<p>M. de la Bouliniere arrived at Cairo from
Alexandria at 8 p.m. yesterday and was met
at the station by MM. Bonin, Bonequet, and
the remaining members of the personnel of
the French Agency and Consulate.</p>
<p>Among tbose leaving for Egypt on the
India at the end of the month are the Dow-
ager Lady Kensington and Miss Winifred
Edwardes, Lady Messsrene and Sir W.E.
Cooper.</p>
<p>Count A. Gouzaga will pay a short visit to
Jerusalem in tbe near future.</p>
<p>Mr. and Mrs. E. W. P. Foster have retruned
to Alexandria from Europe.</p>
<p>M. Saint Saena the emirent composer, in-
tends paying a visit to Egypt in December or
January next. In February he goes to Monte
Carlo to attend the rehearsals of his new
opera, L’Ancetre.</p>
<p>We regret to hear that Me. Molteni had
a paralytic stroke late on Monday night, and
that his condition, in spite of unremitting
medical watchfulness and care, gives rise to
very serious anxiety.</p>
<p>Mr.Reeves has arrived at the Carlton Hotel
Balkeley.</p></div>
<div><p>THE SUCBERIES CRASH.</p>
<head>M. Poutrel v. Hon. A.J Davey</head>
<p>On Monday the action brought by M.
Poutret against the Hon. A.J. Davey came
before tbe Cairo Mizel Tribunal the hearing
wu put back to the role special. M. Poutrel
claims one franc damages costs and the in-
sertion of the verdict in three Egyptian and
three French newspapers, on the ground that
tbe Hon. A. J. Davey dismissed him unjus-
tifiably from the service of the Suceries
Company on the charge of having kept him
in ignorance of tbe Say operations, and that
there is no foundation whatever for the
charge. Tbe plaintiff's assignation contains
an elaborate summary of the reasons
go to prove his own innocence in the matter.
We extract the* following passages from the
assignation:--
Attendu que par lettre du 29 septembre
1905, le sieur Davey a licencie le sieur Poutrol
du service de la Societe des Sucraries.
Attendu que les motifs mis en avant par
Davey consistent en des imputations de plu-
sieurs faite ayant tous eu pour but an dire de
Davey, de le tenir lui Davey dans l'ignorance
de operations Say (io)...
 Attendu que si ion comprend tres bien I'in-
teret que pent avoir. Davey dane les ciroons-
tances sotuelles a se faire considerdere comme
etant reste dans lignorance deadites opera-
tions, il est impossible pourtant qu'il cherche
a faire cela an detriment d’un employe dont la
eonduito a toojours e e absolument correcte,
et a se constituer ainsi les elemnts d’un “alibi
moral” preventif.
Or attendu que Poutrel ne pouvalt avoir
I’idee de tenir Davey dans l'gnorances de ces
operations (acceptions on antres) par la rai-
son toute simple qu’il ne pouvait venir a l'ide
de personne que Davey put les ignore.
 Attendu quo pour supposer que Davey les
ignonorait, il aurait tallu supposer ches ledit
Davey une dose d’ingenuite equivalant a l'in-
conscience.
Attendu en effet que ces operations out
toutes e e passeces regulierement en comptabi- .
lite et figurent en toutes lettres ettons chiffres
dans les livres de la societe. 
Attendu, en consequence qu'a moins de ne
pas saior lire ou de ne pas vouloir voir, toute
pereonne jetont les yeux sur les livres (et 
Davey avait ce pouvoir et ce devoir) etait ne-
cessairement mis au courant des dites opera-
tions. 
Attendu que dans ces conditions, suppose
Davey non au courant des acceptations Say,
ce serait admettre ohez lui ou bien la desertion
abeolue de son devoir et la meconnaissanbe
eotiere de son mandat, ou bien une attitude
speciale a la plus invetere et a la plus son-
pable des ignorances.
Attendu qne bien loin de vouloir cacher
a quiconque ces operations Say, que Davey
repudie maintenant, cest Pontrel lui-meme
qui, entre en fonetions, a donne personnel- 
lement des ordres pour que ces operations,
tenues jurqualora en dehors de la compta-
bilite se ent desormais passees reguliere-
ment et integralement dans la comptabilite
generale.
Attendu qu'ainsi passees integralament
ces operations ni rien de ce quis’y rap-
portait ne ponvait etre cache qu’il fant
done pour pretendre avoir ete tanu dans
l’ignorance et recourir a de si pauvres pre-
textes faire appal aux ressources fertiles d’une
imagination complaisante plutot quiaux saines
lumieires de la raison.
Attendu d’ailleurs que Davey est reste
siul administrateur present en Egypte en
l'ete 1903, (le requerant etant aussi absent
a cette epoque); que dans ces conditions
personne n’etant la pour lui maintenir de
force le bandeau sur les yeux, il eat impes-
sible que Davey u'ait pas ete mis par M,
Boinet, son securiaire particulier, choisi per
lui-meme et charge depouillement de la
correspindance sinon au courant da moine
aur la piste de ces operations qu'il ignorait
et core apres 5 ans passes par lui a la Di-
rection de la societe.
Attendu que dans le courrant de la presente.
annes, dans une instance engages contre la
Societe, il a ete depose par le sieur Talbot,
l'adversaire de la societe, un memoire dont
les echos meme affaibliset aisent encore assez
suggestifs. 
Que ce meme memoire a sans doute ete 
au moins parcouro par l’avocat de la Societe,
pui que ledit ayocayat a demande dans ses con-
clusions qu’il ful ecarle des debata comme
iejurieux (sic), a certainement ete communique
par cet avocat aux administrateura delegues
(dont M. Davey) a moins que de ce chef
encore ce dernier n'accuse l'honorable Me
Carton de l'avoir lui aussi maintenu dans son
etat d'ignorance chronique. 
Attendu done que Poutrol ne pouvant meme
pas soupenner que Davey put ignorer les ope-
rations Say, il a'envuit qu’il n’alien pa faire
pour eotretenir une ignorance qui, a ses yeux,
n’existant pas.
Attendu que dans ces conditions le licen-
ciement dont Poutrol a ete victime est aussi
arbitraire qu’injustice.
Attendu que ce licenciement,injuriex pour
Poutrel, est deriicA k raisra durir^buioea
' nn qootid ra do matin.
Qaa oette inisrtioa, eommandAe A Hem-
nut par oslai l* mfime qui svalt btfirfit k
; %Tgu„ do son ignorance dee folts, 0 encore
^gmtA, k raison do eon oarao’tro quasi-’
' dAtietoeux. b nsponsabilitA prop re et pmeoa*
nolle do Davey, rospoosabilitAdAjk emit pot
fosagisaeatnttntmen*lonta.</p></div>
                <div type="page" n="4"> </div>
                <div type="page" n="5"> </div>
                <div type="page" n="6"> </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Olivia Evanoff</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-19">2016-10-01</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1905-11-06">1905-11-06</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, Monday,November 6, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T.
                    1.
                </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> 
                </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, Thursday, NOVEMBER 9 190S.</head>
<div><head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 8 1005. </head>
<head>THE RUSSIAN HORRORS</head>
<head>“SURPASS IMAGINATION.”</head>
<head>VILLAGES BURNT.</head>
<p>St. Petebsburg, November 8.
An official communique says that it is not to
be denied that, in some places, the local anthori-
ties are hostile to the reforms and have
encouraged the recent excesses. A judicial
enquiry has been ordered in all the localities
where it is suspected that such has been the
case.	(Reuter)</p>
<p>Batoum, November 8.
120 Cossacks under the Governor of the
district were burning the villages in a turbulent
district in the interior when they were sur-
rounded by armed rioters. 105 were killed
after a desperate resistance of 17 hours, (R)</p>
<p>Odessa, November 8.
Yesterday 412 Jewish victims were buried in
the presence of vast crowds. They were buried,
without coffins, in trenches of seventy each. (R)</p>
<p>St. Petersburg, November 8.
Despite the general cessation of strikes, the
Railway Union has issued a significant circular
to the railway men saying that they must
store their arms, and when the decisive mo-
ment comes rise as one man, and never lay
them down until a complete victory be won.
The details of the horrors of the past ten
days are gradually leaking out. They surpass
imagination. In one instance, at Minsk, several
detachments of troops poured a cross-fire into
an unarmed crowd, killing and wounding 400
in a few moments. 
It appears that 50,000 troops with guns
were landed by the warships at Helsingfors on
the 3rd instaht.
The situation became most critical, when
the Imperial manifesto arrived and relieved
the tension.	(Reuter)</p>
<head>RELIEF ORGANISED BY JEWS.</head>
<p>New York, November 8.
A mass meeting of Jews has formed a relief
committee in aid of the Russian sufferers ir-
respective of religion. 56.800 dollars were
received from Jews in London, Paris, and
Berlin offering to participate in an international
relief organisation.	{Reuter)</p>
<head>GRAND DUKE VLADIMIR.</head>
<p>St. Petersburg, November 8.
The Grand Duke Vladimir has resigned his
command of the Guard. (Hovaa)</p>
<head>M. WITTE’S CABINET.</head>
<p>London, November 8.
The "Times" learns from St. Petersburg that
M. Witte has completed his Cabinet. Prince
Urosoff becomes Minister of the Interior, Prince
Eugene Trubetxski takes the portfolio of Public
Instruction, M. Shipoff that of Agriculture,
while M. Nimjechaieff becomes Minister of
Railways. All bare liberal views. M. J. Sbipoff
takes the portfolio of Finance; the others are
unchanged.	(Reuter)</p>
    <head>RAILWAY STRIKE IN AUSTRIA.</head>
<head>UNIVERSAL 8UPPRAGE MOVEMENT.</head>
<p>Vienna, November 8.
Ten thousand Austrian railway employees
have struck. Their demands inclnde universal
suffrage. The movement is spreading. {Reuter)</p>
<head>THE CRETAN INSURRECTION.</head>
<head>AMNESTY PROCLAIMED.</head>
<p>Canea, November 8.
A proclamation has been issued by Colonel
Benedetti, chief of the international troops,
calling upon the insurgents to lay down their
arms, and promising them an amnesty. (H)</p>
<head>BRITISH SQUADRON IN AMERICA.</head>
<p>Washington, November 8.
After a week of the most cordial amenities
from naval and official circles here and at
Annapolis, tbe British Squadron went to
Baltimore, where it was ovated by a crowd of
30,000, and thence to New York. {Reuter)</p>
<head>TYPHOON IN JAPAN.</head>
<p>Tokio, November 8.
A typhoon has ravaged the peninsula of
Oshima.	(Hovas)</p></div>
</div><head>POWERS AND TURKEY.</head>
<head>NAVAL DEMONSTRATION.</head>
<head>BLOCKADE OF DARDANELLES.</head>
<p>London, November 8.
It is expected that the oombined fleets of
tbe Powers, composed of 15 worships, will
appear in the Levant at the end of the week.
{Reuter)</p>
<p>Vienna, November 8.
It is stated here that if the demonstration
does not modify the opposition of the Porte
to the Macedonian reform scheme, the pacific
blockade of tbe Dardanelles will be proclaimed.
{Reuter)</p></div>
<head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
<p>The Sanitary Administration is, we under-
stand, in future to be known as the Public
Health Administration.</p>
<p>Cairo-Alesandria Navigation, except-by
way of the river, is at present impracticable
as the Bagonrieh Canal is closed for the time
being.</p>
<p>Survey Department -The Finance Minis-
try has opened a credit of L.E 4,0(0 for the
Survey Department, in order to facilitate the
land survey.</p>
<p>New Doctors—Abd-El-Arii Mohamed El-
Ghamry, Dadd Suleiman Bulus, and Shukri
Khalil Maluf, doctors, have been authorised
to follow their profession in Egypt.</p>
<p>The Pilgrimage. — The Ministry of the
Interior has selected the personnel for the
escort of the Mahmal. The Khedive will
shortly nominate the Emir el Hag.</p>
<p>The Late Grand Mufti. -- The late Sheikh
El Rafei left two works on the Hsnifi rite, to
which he put the finishing touches only a few
weeks before his death. His sons intend to
publish those works after Ramadan.</p>
<p>Suez Canal.—29 vessels passed through the
Canal on the 4th and 5th inst., 17 of which
were British, 5 German, 3 French, 1 Austrian,
1 Dutch, 1 Swedish, 1 Egyptian. The receipts
from the lst to the 5th inst were frs. 1,958,634.39.</p>
<p>Salt &amp; Soda Co., Ltd. —The sales of salt
during Ootober produced L.B. 21,163 828,
against L.E. 20,599 025 in October, 1901, the
total sales daring the ten months of each year
being:—1905, LB. 209,216.165 ; 1904, LE.
206,690.367.</p>
<p>Canal Cleaning.—All the canals in the
Menoufieh and Gharbieh provinces will have
lower levels or will be closed to navigation
by the 20th December and navigation will
be impossible, or at any rate very difficult,
from that date to the 20th Janaary, 1906.</p>
<p>Railway Fatality. - An express train was
passing by E'phent station, at 1 a.m. on the
7th inst., when a native woman fell on to the
line under the train. Her head and hands
were cat off. The next morning the doctor
said the moawen of Fashn marker examined
the body, but it was not identified.</p>
<p>Cairo ‘ Zoo.”—By kind permission of the
military authorities the Egyptian Army In-
fantry Band will play in tbe Ghizeh Zoolo-
gical Gardens every Sunday afternoon during
this season, commencing on Sunday, 19th
inst. The Ghizeh Boys Band will play as usual
in the Zoological Gardens every Friday after-
noon.</p>
<p>Affray with Robbers.—A party of night
robbers broke into an ezbeh near Da-
lamsha, Bilbeis markaz, on Tuesday night,
but were repelled by the gbaffirs, who
fired upon them, killing one. Tbe police com-
ing rapidly up, cut off the retreat of the
remaining members of the gang, who are now
in prison</p>
<p>The Recruiting Department. — The
Electorship of the Recruiting Department,
now vacant owing to the appointment of
Sarhank Pasha to succeed Lord Edward Cecil
Pasha as Under-Secretary of State for War,
will probably be conferred on Miralai Mahmoud
Bey Tewfik, head of the Military College, who
in his turn will be replaced by Hussein Bey
Jherif, chief of the Recruiting Department in
be Gharbieh province.</p></div>
<head>KING’S BIRTHDAY REVIEW.</head>
<head>KHEDIVE PRESENT.</head>
<p>The presence of H.H. the Khedive and of
Lord Cromer, the bright weather, and the
occasion of the 64th birthday of King Edward
VII. drew large numbers of sightseers to this
morning's review on Abdeen-sqaaro, Cairo,
and though, as a spectacle, the sight was
perhaps not as impressive as in 1904, owing
to the reduction of the Army of Occupation,
there was still any amount of oolour and life
in the scene, and the troops bore themselves
admirably.
Comparisons are of course odious, and we
have no intention of attempting them. We
need only say that the parade movements were
very good, the marching, dressing, wheeling,
etc., being excellently carried out, and that the
physique of the men was admirable. The
British soldier in Egypt is a far more satisfac-
tory sight than too many of the rank and file of
tbe line battalions that one sees at home, and
which often appear to be composed of weedy
boys.
The police were in readiness before 9 a.m.,
and the square, which had been cleared of
vehicles and loiterers, awaited the coming of
tbe troops. At the entrances of the streets
leading to the square, except those that had
been kept free for the troops to enter and to
leave by, large crowds gathered betimes, and
the enclosures filled up rapidly.
By a quarter-past nine all the troops had
moved into the square and taken up their posi-
tions, facing westward, the Rifles being on the
left nearest the Palace, the Inniakillings next,
and the Royal Engineers, Mounted Infantry,
and Royal Garrison Artillery on the right.
At 9.80 Lord Cromer drove up, the troops
saluting to the strains of "God save the King,”
while the Royal Standard was hoisted. The
British Consul-General, after a short oonversa
tion with Brig-General Bullock, then drove
along tbe rank, the troops presenting arms as
he passed.
H.H. the Khedive afterwards arrived, escort-
ed by his Body Gaard, and mounted on a
magnificent white Arab, tire bands playing
the Khedivial Anthem as his Highneea took
up his position close to the Royal Stan-
dard. A general salute followed, the national
anthem being played again, and the troops
gave three cheers for H.M. the King with
great heartiness, to the accompaniment of the
guns in the CitadeL
The troops then marched past, H.H. the
Khedive taking the salute, after which came
the interesting ceremony of trooping the
colour. The review closed with the Khedivial
salute, alter which officers and men returned
to barracks.
We understand that the Khedive expressed
his great satisfaction to General Bollock at
the fine appearance and admirable drill of the
troops.</p>
<head>CELEBRATION AT ALEXANDRIA.</head>
<p>At Alexandria, the usual parade took place
on Mustapha Pasha parade-gronnd at 10 a.m.
a feu dejoie being fired by the Royal Dublin
Fusiliers. At the same time a salute of 21
guns was fired from Fort Kom-el-Dik.
The Royal Standard Boats over all stations
occupied by British troops to-day.</p>
<head>THE KHEDIVE.</head>
<p>Immediately after the review this morning
the Khedive returned to Abdeen Palace, where
he received the Russian Agent and Consul-
General, who presented his credentials in
solemn audience.</p>
<head>LORD EDWARD CECIL</head>
<p>The following Order has been published by
H.R the Sirdar :—
H.B. the Sirdar wishes to express the great-
est regret at the retirement from the Egyptian
Army of El Lewa Lord Edward Cecil Pasha,
D.S.O., who is taking up a new appointment
under the Egyptian Government as Under-
secretary of State in the Ministry of Finance,
As Military Secretary, Director of Intelligence,
Agent-General, and Under-Secretary of State
for War, Lord Edward Cecil has shown most
marked ability and tact, and the excellenoe
and brilliance of his work has been very con-
spicuous. The Sirdar desires to place on record
his sincere appreciation of this officer's most
valuable services, and on behalf of the Army
wishes him every success in his future career.”</p>
<head>THE PILGRIMAGE.</head>
<p>The Ministry of Finance has agreed to a
credit of LB. 14,000 for the sanitary and
other measures to be taken on the return of
tbe pilgrims from Mecca and Medina.</p>
<head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS.</head>
<p>The Cunard S.S. Pavia arrived at Liverpool
yesterday afternoon.
The S.S. Royal Prince, with passengers and
general cargo, from London, left Malta yester
day, and is due to arrive at Alexandria on
Sanday.
The Westcott S.S. City of Dundee arrived
last night from Newcastle, London, snd Malts,
with passengers snd general cargo.
Tbe EIIeiman S.S. Andalusian arrived yes-
terday from Glasgow and Malta with general
cargo.
The Ellerman S.S. Avon tails to-day for
Liverpool direct.</p></div>
<div><head>BIRTHDAY HONORS.</head>
<head>LOCAL RECIPIENTS.</head>
<head>(Gazette's Special Service).</head>
<p>London, Thursday, Nov. 9.
Among the recipients of Birthday honors
are Dr. Buffer and Harari Pasha, who have
been made C.M.G.</p>
<head>EARL OF MINTO AT PORT SAID.</head>
<p>(From our Correspondent.)
Port Said, Wednesday.
The P. &amp; O. Victoria, by which Lord and
Lady Minto are travelling to India, has a
large number of prominent people on board,
among whom are Major F. L Adam (Lord
Minto’s A.D.C.), Sir G. Arbothnot, Surgeon
Lieut. Col. and Mrs. W. R. Crooke-Lawlesa,
Dr. K Dolman, Lord C. Dundas, Lady E
Elliott, Lady R. Elliott, Lady V. Elliott, Lady
Fawkes, Hon. and Mrs. R Lyttleton, Sir
Francis and Lady MaoLean, with two daughters,
Lord Francis Soott, Lieot-Co. J. R. Dunlop
Smith, Lady Sampson, and the Hon. Vansittart-
Lord Minto, with a large party of friends,
dined at the Eastern Exchange last night</p>
<head>EXPRESS SERVICE TO EGYPT.</head>
<p>The Ellerman, Hall and City Lines announced
a monthly express service from Liverpool to
Egypt Bombay, and Knrrachee. The service
will commence on December 14 with the Trafford
Hall, a new steamer launched last week. The
average passage to Port Said is to be ten and
a half days, and to Bombay twenty-one days'
sea passage, the Seer Canal excluded. The
steamers allocated to this service include the
new steamer City of Calcutta, which recently
made a passage to Calcutta under twenty-six
days.</p>
<head>SALVAGE OF DERELICT CRANE.</head>
<p>During the homeward voyage of the New
castle steamer Aureole, from the Black Sea to
Shields, the crew came across a self-propelling
floating crane, supported by means of a pontoon
about 100ft long, used for ship repairing in
rivers or harbors.
It was in the direct route of steamers bound
from Cape Matapan to Cape Pasoaro.
The Aoreole took the pontoon in tow with
three 7in. hawsers. For a time some of the
sailors remained aboard the deraliot to bale
out the water, but it labored so heavily in tbe
heavy seas that they were obliged to come on
board tbeir own vessel.
The pontoon crane which was worth £l 5,000,
was bound for Port Said, but nothing is known
as to wbat has beoome of its crew or the tag
which presumably bad charge of it. </p>
<head>CAIRO MIXED TRIBUNALS.</head>
<p>The Cairo Tribunal Correctional met yester-
day morning under the presidency of Judge
Nyholm. supported by Judge Hexligera and
Judge Yonuef Axis The assessors were Dr.
Voronoff, Dr. A. Schoober.and Messrs. J. Payn,
R. Bnriqoez, and Charles Batten berg, the
Parqnet being represented by Mahmond Bey
Rashdy.
Three appeals against sentences for contra-
ventions were heard, a British and Russian
and a French snbject having all got into
trouble for keeping an establishment for
hashish smokers. In two cases the hearing of
the appeal was pat off for a month ; in the
third the sentence was upheld by default. </p>
<head>LAND AND GENERAL TRUST.</head>
<p>Mr. Hooker, we learn, is only awaiting the
dispositions of the London board, before sever-
ing his connection with the Egypt Land and
General Trnst Limited.
Mr. A. P. Maok, a director of the Land and
General Trust left London on Tuesday last
for Egypt, in connection with the business of
the Trust.</p>
<head>ROBBERY OF ANTIQUITIES.</head>
<p>There have been a large and increasing
number of robberies at Karnak lately among
the workmen employed by M. Legrain in
excavating on behalf of the Department of
Antiquities. The most honest and hardest
workers have one after the other been caught
in the very act, and in every case the theft
was done to the temptations put in the way of
the workmen by the dealers in antiquities,
who offer the men very high prices. At Karnak
there are agents paid by these dealers, who
deliberately corrupt the workmen and the
night watchmen.</p>
<head>NOTES FROM MENA.</head>
<p>The following residents are staying at Mena
Honse: Mrs. Sidney Carver and Min Carver,
Mrs. Madden and fsmily, Mr. C. F. Armstrong,
Ugo La-ena Bey. Mr. J. M. Dodd, Mr. C. N.
Firth, Rev. and Mrs. Gordon Proctor.
Dr. and Mrs. BUiot Smith and Mr. P. 8.
Anderson and family will spend the winter at
Mena Honse.
Mr. James P. G. Hopkins and family are
»lao booked for a short stay there.
Among others staying at Mena are Dr. and
Mrs. Hayes, Mr. Wright Henderson, Mr. 0-
Crockett, Mrs. Charles Pease, Min Bewley,
and Herr Kart Wuttke.</p></div>
<div><head>CATTLE PLAGUE.</head>
<head>FRESH OUTBREAK IN SUDAN.</head>
<p>Cattle plague has again broken out in the
Sudan. 8,000 doses of serum have been dis-
patched from Cairo, and it is hoped that the
outbreak will be oonfined to the small area
at present infected.
We learn that several veterinary inspectors,
who have up to the present been employed
on cattle plague work in Egypt, are to be
transferred for duty in the Sudan.
The Serum Institute that was opened at
Abassieh has been given up altogether, the
remaining bulls having been bled to death
for serum. A quantity of this rinderpest
serum is now stored with the Nile Cold Storage,
Co., sufficient to keep within bounds any
serious outbreak.</p>
<head>IMPORTATION OF CATTLE.</head>
<p>The Quarantine Board has decided to with-
draw, as from the 29nd inst., the decision
to admit into the abattoirs is the interior
of Egypt bovidue coming from Syria, Asia
Minor as for as the Dardanelles, Turkey in
Barope (Macedonia, Bulgaria), Ronmania, and
Russia, and from any other country which
may not be recognised as healthy and free
from any suspicion of episooty. These bovidic,
however, will be admitted at Alexandria and
Port Said, with a view to their slaughter
in quarantine.
Bovide coming from the Somali coast and
from the Eastern Sudan will be landed at
Suez. there to be slaughtered in quarantine.
Tbe present dispositions concerning sheep
remain in force.</p>
<head>BUBONIC PLAGUE.</head>
<p>Another case of plague has been discovered
at Alexandria, the patient being a Greek pastry-
cook of the Midan quarter.
In consequence of this case the usual qua-
rantine measures on the departure of vessels
from Egyptian ports have been re-established.</p>
<head>FINANCE MINISTRY.</head>
<p>In all likelihood Lord R Cecil Pasha, as
co-Under Secretary of State for Finance with
Mr. Mitchell Innes, will be allotted the Free
State Land and the Direct Taxes Departments.
The remaining departments will be left for
Mr. Mitchell Innes.</p>
<head>EGYPTIAN ARMY.</head>
<p>Lieutenant G. Stewart, Coldstream Guards,
has been specially selected for service in the
Egyptian Army.
Leave of absence, on private affairs, has
been granted to El Lewa St. George C. Henry
Pasha, O.B., Adjutant General, B1 Kai" akam
Bray Bey, Medioal Corps, Bl Kaimakam Com-
u ins Bey, Medioal Corps, Bl Kaimakam Ismail
Bey Himmet, Beoraiting Department. Bl Bim-
ba«hi Clayton, Deputy Assistant Adjutant
General, and El Bimbashi Teacher, 19th
Sudanese.
The undermentioned offioers passed the
Intermediate Arabio Examination held on the
2nd Ootober: El Bimbashi Feilden, Inspector,
Bahr El Ghsztl Province, El Bimbashi Lewin,
Assistant Financial Secretary, El Bimbashi
Carey, 16th Battalion, El Bimbashi Nickerson,
Inspector, Sennar Province, and El Bimbashi
Jennings Bramly, Cavalry.</p>
<head>STATE DOMAINS.</head>
<p>Messrs. N. M. Rothschild and Sons an-
nouncee that a drawing amounting to £29,800
nominal capital of the Egyptian State Domain
Mortgage bonds will take place this month
in accordance with the terms of the general
bond of this loan. The numbers and descrip-
tions of tbe bonds drawn will be advertised,
and all bonds so drawn will cease to bear
interest from December 1.</p>
<head>COTTON EXPORTS FROM EGYPT.</head>
<p>During the week ending the 29th October
over 37,000 bales of cotton reached tbe port
of Manchester, of which 20,951 were from
America and the remainder from Egypt.
American shipments of cotton to Manchester
this season have now reached 35,596 bales, a
number behind the record of 1904. Tbe im-
portations from Egypt show an increase over
this corresponding period of last year of about
3,000 bales.</p>
<head>CAIRO STREET NUISANCE.</head>
<p>A correspondent writes:-
Some annoyance has recently been caused at
Cairo by the increases of that annoying class
of bicyclists which prefers the pavement to tbe
road. Out at Gherireh, or beyond Shocbra
and Abbasaieb, there is, no doubt, less to be
urged against tbe habit, but it is no joke to
walk on the pavements of, say, Suleiman
Pasha-street, or the streets leading toward tbe
Ministries, if one is constantly called upon to
get ont of the way by the bells of youthful
bicyclists, many of whom seem to steer so
badly that one easily understands why they
avoid the neighbourhood of the arabiyas. Of
course, if one refuses to move the cyclists must
avoid the pedestrian, bnt he often steers so
badly that it is better to run no risks.</p></div>
<div><head>NOTES FROM SUAKIN.</head>
<head>SERIOUS DAMAGE TO RAILWAY.</head>
<head>(From oub Correspondent.)</head>
<p>Suakin, November 1.
Washouts have taken place on the Suakin-
Athars line, and serious damage has resulted
in several places. Trains stopped running from
both ends between the 95th and 98th Ootober,
when tbe line was repaired and put in good
order.
Kaimakam Loogfield Bey, E.E., Asaristant
Director of Railways, left hereby special train
on the night of the 98th ult on inspection
duty and returned on the 80th, -after having
found everything in perfect working order.
Mr. Thomas Purvis, Suakin-Atbara Railway,
returned from leave of absence by the Khedi-
vial mari steamer Neghileh on 80th nit,
bringing with him Mrs. Purvis and child.
Dr. Crispin, S.M.O., Buskin Mondirieh, is
leaving for Port Sudan. He will organise the
Mondirieb medical staff and hospital then.
Dr. Pahmy win remain here as S.M.O. in
charge of the hospitals and the Suakin railway
employee. 
Among the signs of the development of the
Sudan, and the benefits resulting from the
opening of the new port, I may mention the
fact that Messrs. Loremato Bros., a large
firm of merchants, who have branches at
almost every port in the Red Sea, have
already established themselves af Port Sedan.
Both there and at Buskin, they are largely
patronised by English people. Their goods
come chiefly from England and are
in price. Mr. George Lorenxtato is the general
manager, and all orders pass through his
hands and receive his personal attention.</p>
<head>MYSORE CO. AND EGYPT.</head>
<p>In the report of tbe Mysore Reefs and
General Exploration Company for the year
ended September 30, the directors propose
another reconstruction. Tbe present company
was formed as recently as July, 1909, as a
reconstruction of tbe Mysore Reefs (Kangundy)
Mining Company, but the directors now explain
that a large proportion of the capital is repre-
sented in the balance sheet by the property
originally worked in India, upon which opera-
tions have been suspended, and they considsr
that the time has arrrived when this unproduc-
tive expenditure should be dealt with. They,
therefore, propose to form "The Mysore Reefs
and General Explorers, limited," to take over
the assets and liabilities of the present company.
The capital of the new company would be
£50,000, divided into 40,000 Preference and
160,000 Ordinary Shares of 6s each thus
providing for the allotment of one fully-paid
Ordinary Share for each old Ordinary Shan,
and one fully-paid Preference Share for each old
Preference Share. Tbe existing shares are £l
fully paid, and the proposal is thus to write
down the capital account by 76 per dent The
report shows a balance of profit for the year at
£1,673.</p>
<head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.</head>
<p>Princess Nazli Hanem arrived at Alexandria
from Tonis early this morning by the S.S. 
City of Dundee. On the vetsel being signalled
the Governor went ont to meet her in a Ports
and lights tender, and her Highness then
landed. She is proceeding to Cairo to-day.</p>
<p>Lady Cromer arrived at Cairo at 5 o’clock
yesterday afternoon from Port Said.</p>
<p>M. de Kerber, ex-President of the Council
in Austria, is expected in Egypt in a few days.
He will make a lengthy stay in Cairo.</p>
<p>Baron de Villebois, the Dutch Agent and
Consul-General at Cairo, is expected to return
on Saturday next</p>
<p>Connt G. de Zogheb has arrived in Cairo
from Europe.</p>
<p>Captain Gedge, R.N., Deputy Controller of
Ports and Lighthouses, returned to Alexandria
from leave yesterday.</p>
<p>Mr. Edmond Robertson, M.P., left London
last week for Gibraltar and Egypt</p>
<p>The latest bulletin indicates a alight improve-
ment in the condition of Maitre Molteni.</p>
<p>M. Mermont, chief inspector to the French
Eastern Railways and Mine Mermont have
arrived in Cairo, where they an making a
short stay preparatory to visiting Laxor and
Assouan.</p>
<p>Mr. Robert Williams, F.R.I.B.A., consulting
architect to the Central Buildings Co, Ltd.,
has returned to. Alexandria from London,
there he was called on important business.
among other matters being the mosque which
it is proposed to build in the Metropolis.
Mr. Williams, notwithstanding the immense
cost of the scheme feels asnguine that it will
be arried out sooner or later. The chief
difficulty appears to be finding a suitable
site in tbe City. Mr. Williams, who was at
one time a member of the London County
Council, is an authority on the boating ques-
tion, and has published a very interesting
work on the subject, which deserves the
persual of many who an interested those
in this oouatry, </p></div> 
